<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vintage Story Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Taon</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/</link><description>Recent content in Taon on Vintage Story Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Blackthorn</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/blackthorn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/blackthorn/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackthorn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Blackthorn, the bastion of the South was once known as Caer Balasir, seat of the Silverdawn Republic. Now it lies in the hands of dubious lords wishing to exploit the delicate balance of power in The Imperial Kindom of Silverdawn The city lies on the mountainside of the Plains of Amurru&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Plains of Amurru</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/plains-of-amurru/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/plains-of-amurru/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plains of Amurru&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Despite the constant rain and many dangers of the rolling plains of Amurru, Blackthorn has survived as a major trade hub for the proto humans. Known as a den of thieves, rogues and thugs - the local proto humans find their own order through strength and cunning over law and religion Blackthorn is constantly under threat from the Undead to the south which clammer out of the haunted forest every evening bringing death on all they approach. If it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for the assistance of the Shields of Enruel the Guard may have been overwhelmed several centuries ago and the whole land covered in the undead blight. The orc like creatures from Tean&amp;rsquo;Zu and Goblins also cause chaos for legendary Red Banner Trading Guild which ships its goods all over the continent from this location. Due to the guard being stretched thin with the undead, mercenaries are hired by merchants as they travel across the region. Temperate fields and forests with regular rain provides an endless harvest for the early humans&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Romnus Silverdawn</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/romnus-silverdawn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/romnus-silverdawn/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romnus Silverdawn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Romnus Silverdawn was a slave prisoner in the proto human kingdom who formed the Silverdawn Republic in 2385 MA after the slaves were freed. His daughter was Eryinth Silverdawn, wife of Athos Valeron&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Silverdawn Republic</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/silverdawn-republic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/silverdawn-republic/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silverdawn Republic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Silverdawn Republic was an early proto human kingdom that was formed after the slaves were released from their sentences after a Spellstorm it was founded in 2385 MA by Romnus Silverdawn and disbanded in 2450 MA by Athos Valeron It&amp;rsquo;s capital was Caer Balasir, now known as Blackthorn&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Tean&#39;Zu</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/teanzu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/teanzu/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tean&amp;rsquo;Zu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tean&amp;rsquo;Zu is the base of operations for the brutal orc like creatures that ravage the Plains of Amurru&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruled over by a tyrant the these creatures pillage and burn all they cross which is a blight for the Meroei who are already struggling with Goblins and Undead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say they are manipulated by others who do not wish to see the proto humans spread too far into other racial territories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was once forests have long since been burned and used to fuel the building of outposts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tean&amp;rsquo;Zu is in the western cliffs of the Plains of Amurru&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Eternal Sanctum</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/the-eternal-sanctum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/the-eternal-sanctum/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eternal Sanctum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Eternal Sanctum has stood since ancient time and housed the many noble houses of the Mysmaal long before their gift of vampirism Here House Vex finds it&amp;rsquo;s forefathers resting eternally. Recently the towering crypt has been repurposed as a city for King Tullan Vex who manages his Army of Crimson Shadow in his campaign to reclaim the Throne of Val`Elsir from his wife Queen Morgana Vex This ancient towering crypt looking over a vast blizard tundra built in ancient times to house the Mysmaal noble ancestors&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>