<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Events</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Funeral of Kaeden Shar</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/funeral-of-kaeden-shar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/funeral-of-kaeden-shar/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funeral of Kaeden Shar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QUEEN SHARS SPEECH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My appologies for my delay everyone, I was just paying my respects to the many family we have lost over the years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the the King and I have taken some time to say goodbye to our son, we thought it would be only fair to let you all come and say your goodbyes personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been all these years, that you loving citizens have taken care of my family as they have grown in this city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those he would call his best friends, those that spent a moment entertaining him, served him through his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of you paid a price in making my son a very happy prince.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot understand how torn my soul is from losing my son like this, but I know Banarui has guided him safely through the Maw and into the Spirit Realm and he is watching over us now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The King and I both understand that some of you only knew of Kaeden after he had already passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure, had he known you he would have liked you all very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know deep down, as his mother, he would want you here after what you have done for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will leave you all now to take a moment each with Kaeden and then the Highshaman will speak on behalf of the gods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIGHSHAMAN_VRSAS SPEECH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask Why? If the spirits exist for an eternity, and we pass to the spirit realm. Then why this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mortality is just a moment for us, a blink of an eye in our true life to come in the realms beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have ask then, why are we brought here, to experience this mortality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are we not always like our brothers in the spirit realm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good many of us will spend our time here and live, 250, maybe 300 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our time we will learn many things about this reality, the peoples we share our homes with and even the enemies we meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it this time the spirit begins to bloom? Lessons learned to take with it beyond?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so then Kaeden did not need any more lessons. He loved you all and you loved him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He learned how to fight from the Jagged claws, to sing like the greatest of Utran Bards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He knew the feelings he could have for another with his beloved Jaez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He crossed the blackfeather and saw the edges of the world And perhaps his final lesson at the hands of a world that can be brutal at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And perhaps his final lesson at the hands of a world that can be brutal at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaeden had no more to learn here, his soul is ready and the Banarui is waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of us that are blessed by the spirits learn what is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is we, the ones loved by the Spirits, are the only ones who can leave The Maw and enter the beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So take a moment, pray for Kaeden as he makes his journey. Maybe he will be there for you when your time comes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE DANCE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lights of the hall dim as you witness a younger anushi step forward from behind the tomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it is dark, you make out from reflections that he is covered in some sort of colourful powder and is wearing a type of ancient ritualistic garb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They appear to be engaged in some sort of spiritual dance, bellowing out noises and making strange shamanistic movements that seem to represents the Princes journey through The Maw. He carries a torch in one hand which he flays around wildly adding an intensity to his performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He unsheaths a glowstone blade which lightens up the corner of the room where two other dancers, dressed as wild spectres, emergy with a type of percussion drum in hand which they bash rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dancer and the spectres enter a strange confrontation, lights reflect across the corners of the room as the fire of the torch and red glow of the blade bounce off the surfaces of the chamber. With a fateful cry he leaps at the two spectres and they fall to the floor, raising his hands to the air he screams wildly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience, wipe their tears and applaud and cheer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dancers stand and bow, then face towards the tomb of Prince Kaeden and take a final bow before leaving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The queen stands and addresses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for coming, I will leave you now to take any more time you need with Kaeden, we will then retire to the tavern for drinks and celebrate my sons life - you are welcome to come&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chat Log Record: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discordapp.com/channels/359145879472701441/710022190694662154/711673297913380904&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://discordapp.com/channels/359145879472701441/710022190694662154/711673297913380904&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Jucos Missive</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/jucos-missive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/jucos-missive/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;Following the funeral of the Prince, the adventurers listen to the tales of a Bard who pleads with them to travel to Ezro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event saw players meet with the Bullywugs of Pollywog Hollow on behalf of Ezros Overseer Juco and get them to agree to aid Ezro in a battle against the undead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;chat-text&#34;&gt;Chat Text&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan rolls out a map and plots his finger across it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks into his book and mutters a prayer to Enruel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray looks around the tavern watching carefully at the people inside&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier sings a song in anushi about the heroic deeds of the late Prince. After a few minutes the other bard on stage starts arguing with Reggie about the lyrics not being respectful. The other anushi in the tavern start eyeing Reggie with mild hostility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier frowns at the other bard, realizing the general feeling has turned against him. He steps off the stage and orders a drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier eyes Belle lasciviously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Hello there, sweet face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Your hair is like the softest clouds in a morning breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: What sort of beverage does one as lovely as you drink?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: My name is Reggie, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier continues trying to flirt with Belle to no avail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray looks at the bard and chuckles then silently casts on him a spell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks over and tuts then gets up and heads to the bathroom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ray: The barkeeps and all the people seeing her or near her notice her casting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: is there no restroom in this tavern?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis takes a sip from the bottle of wine and looks at the wood of the bar not payining any attention to the people around her&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan leans on the counter and sighs, tapping his fingers at the barmaid who appears to be ignoring him&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier looks at the anushi bard with slight annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier mumbles something about his song being better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier finishes his wine then heads back to the bar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Another wine, if you please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Thank you, good sir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray looks at the barmaid and with a charming smile asks for a bottle of wine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan turns his head to the bard on stage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis takes another sip from her wine and starts looking at the people in the tavern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan closes his eyes in silent prayer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier mutters, &amp;ldquo;Hmmm, that was actually pretty good. Could use a drum rhythm to sound like war drums though.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier looks down to his decidedly non furry skin and chuckles once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis lets her eyes rest on the bard and decides to observe him for a bit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan turns to flip through the newspaper rag on the bar, oblivious of recent events&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray hears at the bard with attention&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks up, hearing a familiar place name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier looks around the place and the rather cool welcome he received here. He then thinks about his nearly empty coin pouch. He stands and goes back to the stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan nods towards the bard symbolising his interesting in travelling in that direction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Hey, friend. I&amp;rsquo;ll go. This place isn&amp;rsquo;t turning out to be that great for me anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray thinks to herself {Why not, I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything more important to do}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius gets up and slowly walks over to join the others. &amp;ldquo;As will I, I have been meaning to travel that way anyways&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis silently gets up from the chair and walks towards the bard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray gets up and goes towards the bard &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m interested in joining this quest&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis drinks the last bit of her wine and puts the bottle back on the bar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier chugs the last of his wine in one go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: i am looking for a place in the blackfeather, if i may travel with you, though im unarmoured, id appreciate to help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier eyes the cleric and shrugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: No problem, friend. I know that particular kitty. Met him a while back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius nods and looks at his new travelling companions. &amp;ldquo;Let us go, then.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan puts the newspaper rag down &amp;lsquo;So this prince&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; he points to the article &amp;lsquo;&amp;hellip; sounds like a horrible thing happened&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier heads toward the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis nods and waits for the other people to lead the way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan picks up his pack of supplies and places them on his back, leaving the newspaper on the bar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Oh yea, terrible. Really bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: i&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with this land, my first time so i am very sorry for your loss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius nods slowly &amp;ldquo;I was at his funeral, it was a sad day&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray shrugs hearing the stranger and follows him {Finally some adventure}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks downwards, awkwardly &amp;lsquo;i, am so very sorry&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius points at Sylvis &amp;ldquo;as were you, friend, if my memory serves me right&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks upwards at the bright sky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan squints, covering his face from the overwhelming light&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier begins strumming a song. The song is quite refreshing and invigorating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: I&amp;rsquo;m afraid my knowledge of these lands are still minimal, I travel mostly through alternative means and are not familiar with the roads. Does anyone else here know how to get there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Oh yea, I walk ALL the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan rolls out a map, &amp;lsquo;well i picked this up in Arrr, it looks to be somewhere south of here&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Just go south and follow the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius smiles &amp;ldquo;Perfect! Lead the way then, friend&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan nods &amp;lsquo;ah, looks like we have a guide&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: This way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius looks at the map. &amp;ldquo;excellent, let us go&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan &amp;rsquo;s face is invigatored by the overwhelming ease of the speed that he is travelling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan scowls towards the undead &amp;lsquo;Enruel, give me strength to stay on our quest and not slay these abominations right now&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: eugh thats quite heavy rain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier quickly puts away his lute now that it is raining. He pulls out a flute instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: we should use the forest as ocver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan lets loose a sigh of relief at the sight of the deep dark forest, &amp;lsquo;Enruel, we have made it, soon we will find that which you seek&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Oh hey there Chief!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks over at the polar bear so far from the tundra &amp;lsquo;Odd&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|One_Eye rumbles and says in orcish, &amp;ldquo;Greetings&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks shocked as it speaks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|One_Eye is holding a thick parchment in his hands and seems to be trying to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray frowns not understanding the language&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: a town!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks nervously at the guard &amp;lsquo;Can we just go in?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis looks at the town and nods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan notes the tavern &amp;lsquo;Ah great, remind me to go there in a moment&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: bind my soul please, kind soulbinder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray looks around the city&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan speaks to the guard, asking directions to Juco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan smiles at the overseer, warmly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Hello friend, it has been a long while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Reinforcements?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan starts eating a yoghurt as he leans on the banister&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Uh, that sounds &amp;hellip; sort of dangerous&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: I can help with morale. The rest though&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier nods in a way that says, &amp;ldquo;duh&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan raises an eyebrow at the idea of undead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: Did you say undead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: What you mean, undead? Didn&amp;rsquo;t that get taken care of when that Arch Lich fellow was killed. Errr, rekilled?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan puts his spoon down into his yoghurt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: If you can arrange free room and board, oh AND booze, at the local tavern? I&amp;rsquo;m in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: For, let&amp;rsquo;s say, three weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Syvis the Vanquisher: ((was silt killing the undead on the way ic or ooc ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: And I want some stage time there too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray thinks hearing the bard {yeah, we should choose a reward}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: If you seek to exorcise the dead, Enruel will gladly offer his aid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Yea, I don&amp;rsquo;t really think the undead would be appreciative of my spectacular singing voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: perhaps it has drawn them out of their grave&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: My vocal cords are worth more than the gross domestic product of some nations I could name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier sighs. &amp;ldquo;There is always another task.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: Of course I am not much of a fighter, but undead I can aid with - however I have been sent here for a purpose, I may need something in exchange&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks baffled &amp;lsquo;That sounds&amp;hellip; exotic&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~JfL_Wng: Hey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ray: they&amp;rsquo;re the builders xD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Oh yea, those green slimey fellows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ray: ))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Syvis the Vanquisher: ((again lol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks confused &amp;lsquo;What is a bullywug, if i may ask?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier smiles. &amp;ldquo;Oh yea, that sounds like a much better idea than going out and fighting undead.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray just hears them speaking and looks in silence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis smiles &amp;ldquo;They are adorable amphibious people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Duradae_Olath: secruity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks outside into the thick darkness &amp;lsquo;Yes i hear crows are quite common here&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Duradae_Olath: security?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Well, off we go, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Syvis the Vanquisher: ((i do have to go in like 45 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan asks for a moment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Duradae_Olath: aski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan enruel give us strength in our convictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier looks at the group with a mighty grin, strips off his clothes and jumps in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius ties his cloak around himself and follows suit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray uses her illusion to float over the lake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan squints &amp;lsquo;Is that a frog&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: So this is the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius looks around, &amp;ldquo;hmmm, I wonder who their leader is&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier puts his clothes back on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: I don&amp;rsquo;t know. Probably in the biggest hut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks confused as he sneaks past&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Hey friend. Where can we find your leader?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Oh, hello there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis walks straight to the leader knowing the way in this town&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray sighs &amp;ldquo;I should really learn more languages&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: He welcomes us and asks why we&amp;rsquo;re here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Glad you asked friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: The Anushi down there in Ezro? They are in a tight spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: They need your help. The undead, you know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: With the death of their prince they are worried they will lose the fight against the undead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan nods &amp;lsquo;The Gods favour those that rid the lands of that which should remain at rest&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray casts a spell to make the bullywug more friendly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Duradae_Olath: bank&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ray: is there a linguist here?))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis smiles at the Bullywug leader &amp;ldquo;Because then you could end all of these problems.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray frowns not understanding anything, turns towards the nearest person and says &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to look around&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan nods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier nods in agreement. &amp;ldquo;Yea, Undead don&amp;rsquo;t really go away unless you find the cause.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ray: wait a second))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ray: ugh))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks on, not understanding the response of the frog but understanding but tries anyway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan says &amp;lsquo;the undead are unlike any race, I have seen what they do to lands, look only at the deserts and the ruins of what once was there, now all there is is death and a glimer of hope in an oasis of otherwise deathly quiet sands&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: dont let this happen to your spawn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: That doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound good. Not at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan nods, not understanding a word of the frog but seeming to pull off that he does&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier grins. &amp;ldquo;You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it mister Froggy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius smiles &amp;ldquo;He agrees, he&amp;rsquo;ll send help&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray returns sighing {Why no bullywug here speaks meroei}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: So, time to head back to Juco?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray looks at the bard &amp;ldquo;so what happened?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan shrugs, i will look around town real quick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Oh, we asked him to send help to Ezro. It took a bit of doing, but he agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius nods and smiles &amp;ldquo;Thank you friend, we must all work together to ensure these lands remain free from darkness. I will see to it personally that this assistance is not squandered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius leaves the tent and joins the others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ray: silt, can I roll perception?))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ray: for the fake smile))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan shows his priestly book at the %t&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan nods and smiles, they seem to appreciate each other for a moment - he places his hand on the shoulder of the frog and thanks him, leaving the tent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Duradae_Olath: security&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Duradae_Olath: aski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: So, ready to head back to tell Juco the good news?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: I believe so&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: Alright friends, It&amp;rsquo;s been a long day, let&amp;rsquo;s return and give the good news to Juco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier suddenly stops in the shade of the trees as a string breaks on his lute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Hey friends, I just need a minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier starts replacing his string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan nods, he pulls out some bread from his pack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius sits on the side of the road to catch his breath&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier mumbles about how dark it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Thats better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: Wow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: it&amp;rsquo;s like a summers day in the vale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier continues repairing his string, but it is easier now that he can see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier winks at the cleric as he sings a quiet song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis smiles happy she could help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: Hmm who is that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius looks around at the figures advancing around them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Hello there friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: hello friends&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Nice &amp;hellip; robes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan mutters something to enruel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis turns around and lets out a high scream as someone in robes with a weapon suddenly appears behind her&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t sneak up on people like that, friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier shakes his head like he doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis looks at the person hidden beneath cloaks and slowely walks backwards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I don&amp;rsquo;t speak creepy cloaked figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: they appear to be sacrificing someone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ray: I&amp;rsquo;m invsibile))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier sings a strange new song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier stops his song with a disappointed expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: augh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Hey, stop that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan mutters &amp;lsquo;Enruel hold them still!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius stretches forth his hand and begins conjuring a torrent of flame from the ground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis runs away from the cultist trying not to trip over the roots&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: is everyone alright?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks around in the dark&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: You know it didn&amp;rsquo;t have to end this way, friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan feels about for his book&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier looks sadly at the bodies around them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: is everyone alright??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier sings a soothing song&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis runs into the shadow of a tree and curls up in a ball trying to hide herself as she gets flashbacks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan the darkness came back during the attack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: hey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray nods &amp;ldquo;so this is what happened&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: friend, it&amp;rsquo;s ok. They&amp;rsquo;re gone now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Usually I would just run from enemies like that, but not when they are attacking my traveling companions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan looks at the bodies &amp;lsquo;Why would they do this to us? What had we done?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: you can come join us, we need to head back to safety. it&amp;rsquo;s not safe in these woods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Yea, let&amp;rsquo;s head back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier shouts, Come on Syvis. Time to head back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis slowely looks up and says in a scared voice &amp;ldquo;Are they gone ?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Syvis the Vanquisher: Are you sure there aren&amp;rsquo;t any more hiding in the branches of the trees ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan nods &amp;lsquo;We are safe, The Gods will always protect those in need&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: the outlaws and vagabonds roaming these woods need not reason to attack. Perhaps they wanted our money, or they thought we were delivering good to ezro, it almost sounded like they were cultists trying to obtain a sacrifice for some evil purpose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Syvis the Vanquisher: Are you sure there aren&amp;rsquo;t any more hiding in the branches of the trees ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: they mentioned something about wanting our bodies as hosts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius shudders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: let&amp;rsquo;s continue on, no good will come of staying here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I&amp;rsquo;d have let them use my body for any number of fun things. But not like that. No siree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: a good idea, it is dark here and i am not familiar with this place&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: you seem to know this place quite well, are you a tracker?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: I dabble, yea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: we are lucky to have you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius looks at the priest and is grateful for his divine abilities, wondering which deity has such influence in these lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ray thinks back to the battle {my charm wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan smiles &amp;lsquo;Who can know how far the influence of the God of Secrets can go? Perhaps there is no limit&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Syvis the Vanquisher: ((i have to go in like 15 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan points &amp;lsquo;You appear to have dropped some jewelry&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius smiles in amazement. Enchanter&amp;rsquo;s mind trick? perhaps. More likely a divine connection. fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: Too right, we were. We did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Reggie_Luthier looks entirely too self-satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: this forest needs more lighting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: we were jumped by some strange people in the darkness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Reggie_Luthier the Companion: They froggies said they would hop right on over with some &amp;lsquo;o their best fighter types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Syvis walks to the corner of the room and puts her back against the wall constantly looking through the windows to make sure no more cultists are left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Silternius sees Syvis acting nervous by the window&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ray: nice))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Silternius the Vindicator: It&amp;rsquo;s ok, they&amp;rsquo;re gone now, you&amp;rsquo;re safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan does not feel hungry for once in his life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan places a map on the table of Juco, &amp;lsquo;as you promised, i am looking for a place of fungus&amp;rsquo; please mark it for me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Father_Branan: thank you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan smiles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Father_Branan smiles and nods to people &amp;lsquo;i hope we can meet again&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Raising an Egg</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/raising-an-egg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/raising-an-egg/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raising an Egg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;chat-text&#34;&gt;Chat Text&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Server&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BOT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today at 9:07 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath wonders why she needs that bag of corpses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:07 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Fran with her cloak coated in red looks at the cultist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:07 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth wipes her forehead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:08 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath wonders what ela is hiding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:08 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth bows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:09 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|One_Eye lumbers forward. &amp;ldquo;Me find five.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:09 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ela touches Fran&amp;rsquo;s cloak, and licks her finger, loudly smacking at the kenku blood &amp;ldquo;eww.. too tart&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:09 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Scinthia_NReth: i found one, but its rather nice compared to theirs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:09 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Hulking_Figure picks up the items&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:10 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth smiles &amp;lsquo;Quality over Quantity dear&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:10 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Fran frowns and look at ela &amp;ldquo;dont do that again&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:11 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth points at the person she gave it to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:11 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Fran the Butcher of Qylia: wait))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:11 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath gives up on trying to understand the cultist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:11 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Fran the Butcher of Qylia: i havve 5 ))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:12 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash watches the Cultist carefully&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:12 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Fran the Butcher of Qylia: yup))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:12 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Fran hands over her egg war.ers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:12 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Fran the Butcher of Qylia: warmers*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:13 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath wonders if he should give the cultist his egg warmers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:13 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth glares at the others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:13 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Scinthia_NReth: Im sure we have more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:13 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth laughs nervously&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:14 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|One_Eye rumbles in annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:14 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Fran looks at the cultist &amp;ldquo; I wouldnt do that&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:14 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~One_Eye the Chieftain: You no attack with you guard. We have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:14 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath wonder why ela was shooting at the hulking figure, then proceeds to attempt to dodge a barage of arrows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:14 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~One_Eye the Chieftain: All, give egg thingiez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:15 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath hands two egg warmers to the cultist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:16 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath makes a mental note to learn gialon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:16 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Scinthia_NReth: such a nice round number dont you think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:16 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ferox_Ragash the Weary: What you do with eggy warmers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:16 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Hulking_Figure lumbers forward and hands one warmer to Ferox with caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:16 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ela makes a mental note to learn Gialon, then changes her mind as it sounds hard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:17 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash takes the warmer carefully, placing the strange egg in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:17 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth looks at his pet wondering why it is doing things of its own accord, she glares at it then looks back&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:17 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath wonders if the scinthia&amp;rsquo;s skelleton would still move and fight if he pulled of its head&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:18 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash looks a bit skeptically at the Cultist, but watches in silence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:18 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ela tugs some life from a nearby stranger and winks at her as she runs away&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:18 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Fran the Butcher of Qylia: speedrunned dinner xD))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:18 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Scinthia_NReth: who is this duke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:19 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth ponders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:19 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath sits down, tired from the days work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:20 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Scinthia_NReth: Revolution over what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:20 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ela pulls out a dark red concoction and smiles mischeviously as she takes a sip&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:20 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Scinthia_NReth: Oh now there are four of them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:20 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ela perks up at the sound of a revolution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:21 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Scinthia_NReth: Well i do hope you will put in a good word for us dear&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:21 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth wafts away the flies gathering over her bag &amp;lsquo;Maybe one day, he might grant us an audience? Now we have shown how capable we are?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:22 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Duradae_Olath: hey scinthia, whats this about a revolution?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:22 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Hulking_Figure looks at Ferox and makes a horrible sound. It is the sound of someone breathing out through frayed vocal cords. There are no words. Just a tattered groaning sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:22 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ferox_Ragash the Weary: Do me know you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:22 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth whispers quitely towards duradae &amp;lsquo;Something he said&amp;rsquo; she points at the cultist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:22 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash stands and tucks the egg and warmer under her large arm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:22 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Hulking_Figure does not respond because the cultist holds out a hand to stop the figure from doing anything more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:23 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Fran the Butcher of Qylia: just say thanks that I&amp;rsquo;m mentored down e.e))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:23 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath whispers back &amp;ldquo;i dont understand him tho&amp;rdquo;, he quietly laughs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:23 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash looks to the Cultist. &amp;ldquo;You call me orctress..and big person want speak. Let speak&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:23 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Scinthia_NReth: Something about a duke dear, hes starting a revolution for the undead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:23 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash slowly walks forward to the pair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:23 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Duradae_Olath: ahhh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:24 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath gets intimitated by ferox&amp;rsquo;s glowing red eyes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:24 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Hulking_Figure turns his huge head toward the Orctress but makes no sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:25 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ferox_Ragash the Weary: You free to speak to me&amp;hellip;if can&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:25 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Hulking_Figure looks at the cultist then back. It lets out another horrible hissing, grating sound that is a terrible immitaion of speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:25 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ferox_Ragash the Weary: You sound in pain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:26 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Hulking_Figure shakes his head no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:26 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ferox_Ragash the Weary: So you no in pain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:26 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Hulking_Figure shakes its head no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:26 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth laughs nervously for her companions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:27 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ferox_Ragash the Weary: You happy? You free?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:27 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Hulking_Figure stares at Ferox unmoving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:27 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|One_Eye moves to Ferox and puts his hand on her shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:28 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|One_Eye whispers, &amp;ldquo;You no look with eyes. You look with spirit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:28 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath glances between the hulking figure and the orctress nervously&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:29 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|One_Eye walks calmly up to the hulking figure and stares it in the face for a time. Then nods and walks away into the forest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:29 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash shakes her head as her eyes tingle as One Eye allows her to look with the spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:29 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Fran the Butcher of Qylia: is everyone looking at ferox and hulking figure?))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:29 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash she grumbles, frustrated and confused&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:29 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Fran becomes invisible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:30 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath gets slightly bored, so he looks over his companions and tries to notice anything intreaging&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:30 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash looks to the Cultist. &amp;ldquo;Who say to call me Orctress..&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:31 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth wafts an ever growing amount of flies away from her bag of bodies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:31 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Fran moves while invisible and looks around to see if someone can see her and notes down the people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:31 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath notices a knife in solingkey&amp;rsquo;s hand, and backs away a little&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:32 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Scinthia_NReth smiles as she pulls the bag by &amp;lsquo;Well, this has been lovely, but i must get these back to my menagerie&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:32 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Scinthia_NReth: cheerio everyone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:32 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath wonders about the ratio of flies to bodyparts in scinthias bag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:34 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Ela the Nightwalker: I have no idea what any of you are saying&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:34 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath notices father branen off in the distance, and wonders why he now looks like a dark elf&amp;hellip;..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:34 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Fran the Butcher of Qylia: does the cultist have see inv?))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:34 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash growls, but backs away slowly, still concerned and frustrated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:35 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath decides to jump a zerzura scout that is loitering nearby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:38 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath wonders if he should tell anyone what he heard in the good event earlier when he snuck by it, but then remembers that he heard nothing of importance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:39 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ela laughs out loud for no apparent reason&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:39 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Duradae_Olath looks at ela, wonders what she laughed about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:39 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Fran from the shadows looks at the cultist and waits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:40 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ela shuffles her cards again and looks for someone to ask the dead about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:40 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:|Ferox_Ragash allows her eyes to wander over the group, her eyes only pausing on Fran for a second&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9:40 PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019:~Fran the Butcher of Qylia: good, I&amp;rsquo;m following them))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Message #roleplay-history&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Spellstorm</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/spellstorm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/spellstorm/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id=&#34;event-date&#34;&gt;Event Date&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 OE (171966 UT) - The Old Meropian Age&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the emergence of the taktevolken hoards on Nuchalnuth and the discovery of races existing on the continent a great battle occured. The Jin did their best to fend off the scourge of undead machines but the unique anti-magic of the Taketevolkiens and their horrendously evil Queen known only as &amp;ldquo;The Darkness&amp;rdquo; was the perfect match for the here-to-fore unsurpassed Meta-magic of the Jin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jin and the unholyness that was the Taketevolkiens became embroiled in an inter-dimentional, cross time battle for the life of Solinia itself. Swirling itself into a massive Spellstorm it connected the time waves throughout all past and future ripples allowing the travel of bodies, minds, souls and species. Intermixing them and creating a fusion of conformity and complacency that was to be the undoing of all in the great aura of apathy it engendered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the destruction, the spell storm ravages many other continents of Solinia including Halcron and Acacia&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Caerthian Invasion</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/the-caerthian-invasion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/the-caerthian-invasion/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Caerthian Invasion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Caerthian Invasion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;event-date&#34;&gt;Event Date&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1234 P-OE (196982 UT) - Time of Crisis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning 196982 UT (1234 P-OE), the Caethian Invasion was one of the fastest and largest land and sea based military campaigns ever witnessed in the lands of Amaria. The final battle saw the death of many important figures, including Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir, ruler of the Caerthian Empire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-war&#34;&gt;The War&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the death of Methabeht and the shattering of the Time Line, races found the future and the past merged into some unknown land known as Amaria. Seeing the Aerindal alive once more the Emperor began a grand campaign to crush not only the Keladun and recently escaped Anushi slaves, but the Aerindal for the final time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was during this campaign that Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir took the advice of a mysterious sage known as Shai&amp;rsquo;Din who gave him the where abouts of a tomb containing a powerful weapon known as Hiran Asura. Using this weapon he launched a final attack on Eindel but was ultimately killed in the process as Shai&amp;rsquo;Din turned sides with the defenders and led the evacuation of Amaria from the Caerthains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;major-figures&#34;&gt;Major Figures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/emperor-valelsir/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Caerthian Emperor&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grand Marshal Karth,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Savril the Golden Blade,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belara of the Resistance,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emperor Khodhe,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Queen Echo of Praecentia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King Johnathon Fox,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Lanchester,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fran,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greyson,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polemistlis,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zyther,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silternius,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thallion,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violet,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zytari,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xander&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;major-battles&#34;&gt;Major Battles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Morheim,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Andyr,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Krosis,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Iremia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Bhava,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of the Ecclesia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second Battle of the Ecclesia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Undergate,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Shasun,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Praecentia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Arnar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;specific-event-lore-text&#34;&gt;Specific Event Lore Text&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forces that rule the shores of one of the continent&amp;rsquo;s great lakes have at last clashed over territory and expansion. Undergate has declared war upon New Genesis, and the city of Rarahat&amp;rsquo;s devout have accepted. Should you wish to get involved in this event, your character will have to be engaged in the ongoing roleplay between these two cities. You may speak to Johnathon Fox or Arafel if you wish to join either side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;losses&#34;&gt;Losses&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir was murdered by the lich Shai&amp;rsquo;Din in the final moments of the Eindel siege during The Caerthian Invasion of Amaria in 1234 P-OE (196982 UT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;final-outcome&#34;&gt;Final Outcome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Militarily, the war was a total success with all objectives completed&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>