<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Events</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Spellstorm</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/spellstorm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/spellstorm/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id=&#34;event-date&#34;&gt;Event Date&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 OE (171966 UT) - The Old Meropian Age&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the emergence of the taktevolken hoards on Nuchalnuth and the discovery of races existing on the continent a great battle occured. The Jin did their best to fend off the scourge of undead machines but the unique anti-magic of the Taketevolkiens and their horrendously evil Queen known only as &amp;ldquo;The Darkness&amp;rdquo; was the perfect match for the here-to-fore unsurpassed Meta-magic of the Jin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jin and the unholyness that was the Taketevolkiens became embroiled in an inter-dimentional, cross time battle for the life of Solinia itself. Swirling itself into a massive Spellstorm it connected the time waves throughout all past and future ripples allowing the travel of bodies, minds, souls and species. Intermixing them and creating a fusion of conformity and complacency that was to be the undoing of all in the great aura of apathy it engendered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the destruction, the spell storm ravages many other continents of Solinia including Halcron and Acacia&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Caerthian Invasion</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/the-caerthian-invasion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/the-caerthian-invasion/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Caerthian Invasion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Caerthian Invasion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning 196982 UT (1234 P-OE), the Caethian Invasion was one of the fastest and largest land and sea based military campaigns ever witnessed in the lands of Amaria. The final battle saw the death of many important figures, including Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir, ruler of the Caerthian Empire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-war&#34;&gt;The War&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the death of Methabeht and the shattering of the Time Line, races found the future and the past merged in some unkown land known as Amaria. Seeing the Aerindal alive once more the Emperor began a grand campaign once more to crush not only the Keladun and recently escaped Anushi slaves, but the Aerindal once more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was during this campaign that Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir took the advice of a mysterious sage known as Shai&amp;rsquo;Din who gave him the where abouts of a tomb containing a powerful weapon known as Hiran Asura. Using this weapon he launched a final attack on Eindel but was ultimately killed in the process as Shai&amp;rsquo;Din turned sides with the defenders and led the evacuation of Amaria from the Caerthains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;major-figures&#34;&gt;Major Figures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Caerthian Emperor,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grand Marshal Karth,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Savril the Golden Blade,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belara of the Resistance,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emperor Khodhe,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Queen Echo of Praecentia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King Johnathon Fox,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Lanchester,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fran,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greyson,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polemistlis,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zyther,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silternius,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thallion,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violet,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zytari,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xander&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;major-battles&#34;&gt;Major Battles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Morheim,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Andyr,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Krosis,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Iremia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Bhava,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of the Ecclesia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second Battle of the Ecclesia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Undergate,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Shasun,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Praecentia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Arnar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;losses&#34;&gt;Losses&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir was murdered by the lich Shai&amp;rsquo;Din in the final moments of the Eindel siege during The Caerthian Invasion of Amaria in 1234 P-OE (196982 UT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;final-outcome&#34;&gt;Final Outcome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Militarily, the war was a total success with all objectives completed&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>