<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Events</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Funeral of Kaeden Shar</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/funeral-of-kaeden-shar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/funeral-of-kaeden-shar/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funeral of Kaeden Shar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QUEEN SHARS SPEECH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My appologies for my delay everyone, I was just paying my respects to the many family we have lost over the years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the the King and I have taken some time to say goodbye to our son, we thought it would be only fair to let you all come and say your goodbyes personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been all these years, that you loving citizens have taken care of my family as they have grown in this city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those he would call his best friends, those that spent a moment entertaining him, served him through his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of you paid a price in making my son a very happy prince.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot understand how torn my soul is from losing my son like this, but I know Banarui has guided him safely through the Maw and into the Spirit Realm and he is watching over us now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The King and I both understand that some of you only knew of Kaeden after he had already passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure, had he known you he would have liked you all very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know deep down, as his mother, he would want you here after what you have done for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will leave you all now to take a moment each with Kaeden and then the Highshaman will speak on behalf of the gods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIGHSHAMAN_VRSAS SPEECH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask Why? If the spirits exist for an eternity, and we pass to the spirit realm. Then why this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mortality is just a moment for us, a blink of an eye in our true life to come in the realms beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have ask then, why are we brought here, to experience this mortality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are we not always like our brothers in the spirit realm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good many of us will spend our time here and live, 250, maybe 300 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our time we will learn many things about this reality, the peoples we share our homes with and even the enemies we meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it this time the spirit begins to bloom? Lessons learned to take with it beyond?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so then Kaeden did not need any more lessons. He loved you all and you loved him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He learned how to fight from the Jagged claws, to sing like the greatest of Utran Bards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He knew the feelings he could have for another with his beloved Jaez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He crossed the blackfeather and saw the edges of the world And perhaps his final lesson at the hands of a world that can be brutal at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And perhaps his final lesson at the hands of a world that can be brutal at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaeden had no more to learn here, his soul is ready and the Banarui is waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of us that are blessed by the spirits learn what is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is we, the ones loved by the Spirits, are the only ones who can leave The Maw and enter the beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So take a moment, pray for Kaeden as he makes his journey. Maybe he will be there for you when your time comes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE DANCE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lights of the hall dim as you witness a younger anushi step forward from behind the tomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it is dark, you make out from reflections that he is covered in some sort of colourful powder and is wearing a type of ancient ritualistic garb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They appear to be engaged in some sort of spiritual dance, bellowing out noises and making strange shamanistic movements that seem to represents the Princes journey through The Maw. He carries a torch in one hand which he flays around wildly adding an intensity to his performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He unsheaths a glowstone blade which lightens up the corner of the room where two other dancers, dressed as wild spectres, emergy with a type of percussion drum in hand which they bash rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dancer and the spectres enter a strange confrontation, lights reflect across the corners of the room as the fire of the torch and red glow of the blade bounce off the surfaces of the chamber. With a fateful cry he leaps at the two spectres and they fall to the floor, raising his hands to the air he screams wildly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience, wipe their tears and applaud and cheer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dancers stand and bow, then face towards the tomb of Prince Kaeden and take a final bow before leaving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The queen stands and addresses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for coming, I will leave you now to take any more time you need with Kaeden, we will then retire to the tavern for drinks and celebrate my sons life - you are welcome to come&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chat Log Record: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discordapp.com/channels/359145879472701441/710022190694662154/711673297913380904&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://discordapp.com/channels/359145879472701441/710022190694662154/711673297913380904&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Spellstorm</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/spellstorm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/spellstorm/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id=&#34;event-date&#34;&gt;Event Date&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 OE (171966 UT) - The Old Meropian Age&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the emergence of the taktevolken hoards on Nuchalnuth and the discovery of races existing on the continent a great battle occured. The Jin did their best to fend off the scourge of undead machines but the unique anti-magic of the Taketevolkiens and their horrendously evil Queen known only as &amp;ldquo;The Darkness&amp;rdquo; was the perfect match for the here-to-fore unsurpassed Meta-magic of the Jin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jin and the unholyness that was the Taketevolkiens became embroiled in an inter-dimentional, cross time battle for the life of Solinia itself. Swirling itself into a massive Spellstorm it connected the time waves throughout all past and future ripples allowing the travel of bodies, minds, souls and species. Intermixing them and creating a fusion of conformity and complacency that was to be the undoing of all in the great aura of apathy it engendered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the destruction, the spell storm ravages many other continents of Solinia including Halcron and Acacia&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Caerthian Invasion</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/the-caerthian-invasion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/the-caerthian-invasion/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Caerthian Invasion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Caerthian Invasion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;event-date&#34;&gt;Event Date&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1234 P-OE (196982 UT) - Time of Crisis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning 196982 UT (1234 P-OE), the Caethian Invasion was one of the fastest and largest land and sea based military campaigns ever witnessed in the lands of Amaria. The final battle saw the death of many important figures, including Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir, ruler of the Caerthian Empire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-war&#34;&gt;The War&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the death of Methabeht and the shattering of the Time Line, races found the future and the past merged into some unknown land known as Amaria. Seeing the Aerindal alive once more the Emperor began a grand campaign to crush not only the Keladun and recently escaped Anushi slaves, but the Aerindal for the final time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was during this campaign that Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir took the advice of a mysterious sage known as Shai&amp;rsquo;Din who gave him the where abouts of a tomb containing a powerful weapon known as Hiran Asura. Using this weapon he launched a final attack on Eindel but was ultimately killed in the process as Shai&amp;rsquo;Din turned sides with the defenders and led the evacuation of Amaria from the Caerthains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;major-figures&#34;&gt;Major Figures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/emperor-valelsir/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Caerthian Emperor&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grand Marshal Karth,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Savril the Golden Blade,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belara of the Resistance,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emperor Khodhe,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Queen Echo of Praecentia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King Johnathon Fox,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun Lanchester,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fran,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greyson,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polemistlis,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zyther,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silternius,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thallion,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violet,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zytari,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xander&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;major-battles&#34;&gt;Major Battles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Morheim,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Andyr,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Krosis,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Iremia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Bhava,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of the Ecclesia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second Battle of the Ecclesia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Undergate,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Shasun,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Praecentia,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Arnar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;specific-event-lore-text&#34;&gt;Specific Event Lore Text&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forces that rule the shores of one of the continent&amp;rsquo;s great lakes have at last clashed over territory and expansion. Undergate has declared war upon New Genesis, and the city of Rarahat&amp;rsquo;s devout have accepted. Should you wish to get involved in this event, your character will have to be engaged in the ongoing roleplay between these two cities. You may speak to Johnathon Fox or Arafel if you wish to join either side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;losses&#34;&gt;Losses&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir was murdered by the lich Shai&amp;rsquo;Din in the final moments of the Eindel siege during The Caerthian Invasion of Amaria in 1234 P-OE (196982 UT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;final-outcome&#34;&gt;Final Outcome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Militarily, the war was a total success with all objectives completed&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>