<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – The Planes of the Gods</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/</link><description>Recent content in The Planes of the Gods on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Plane of Shadow</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/plane-of-shadow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/plane-of-shadow/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plane of Shadow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A realm of the Gods ruled by Somnus&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Plane of Time</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/plane-of-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/plane-of-time/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plane of Time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Plane of Trade</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/plane-of-trade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/plane-of-trade/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plane of Trade&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A realm of the Gods ruled by Alorn the Artisan - also known as The Forge City of Amirith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;inhabitants&#34;&gt;Inhabitants&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city of Amirith sits at the boundaries between many other realities and welcomes nearly every known type of entity in the mortal planets and planes. Trade rules the city, and due to the infinite destractions brought with vast wealth and endless material choices, there is little need for racial tensions. Instead the city finds itself more at war among the great organisations and factions that slide upwards and downwards on the economic ladder that powers the cities commercial engines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;alorn-the-artisan&#34;&gt;Alorn the Artisan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alorn rules over the The Forge City of Amirith and is found working endless goods and weapons in the planar forges deep below the city. Order is maintained through the products he creates and their effect on those that use them. The items he creates can, and have, changed the course of many lives on Solinia and the Planes of the Gods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;organisations&#34;&gt;Organisations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many organisations that are present within the city including&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Great Ocean Trading Company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xunshi Trading Company&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Maw</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/the-maw/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/the-maw/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Maw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Whenever a Solinian dies, their soul enters the afterlife. Unfortunately, this afterlife is known as the Maw, a city of the dead, where the atmosphere is continually humid and the buildings are made out of bones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, the buildings continually need to rebuilt, as frequent earthquakes always knock them down, sometimes trapping souls in the rubble. What is the worst feature of the Maw, however, is how most of the streets are made up of crushed, dead souls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are very intertwined so it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to untangle them, but observers who came back from the afterlife speculate that the crushed souls are only the first layer of many, with no telling how far down the morbid pile reaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add to its eerieness, some of the souls contained look nothing like any species found like Solinia. For whatever reason, the Maw is located near the edge of Solinia&amp;rsquo;s solar system, as all souls are drawn there. Only an excorcism, or stagnant rifts found in the Maw allow passage back to the living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rift portals are unusual in that they never dissapate, and that they seem to get smaller, as though something was sapping them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>