<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Gods</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/</link><description>Recent content in Gods on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Aerin</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/aerin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/aerin/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aerin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Aerin the Valorous, Prime Elemental God of the Sky and ruler of the Plane of Valor. He is credited with vanquishing The Ancients during The Great Cleansing His mortal creations include the Valerin Ruler of Valisi - The Realm of Valor (Plane of Valor)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Amurru</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/amurru/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/amurru/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amurru&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Amurru the Deep One was a member of the Prime Elemental Pantheon and would rule the earthern realms and construct a mighty race of stone golems called Gialon during the wars of The Great Cleansing. Ruler of Delgar - The Endless Depths (The Plane of the Deep) Responsible for the Gialon though they do not always believe this&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Ashoka</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/ashoka/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/ashoka/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashoka&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Ashoka was a lover of Zephyr and the son of Valhas and Tisroeh and is the former God of Peace. However, due to the brutal murder of Zephyr at the hand of Deuzulus he has become the god of suffering.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Auroris</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/auroris/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/auroris/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auroris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Vishim God of the Sun&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Belshazar</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/belshazar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/belshazar/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belshazar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Belshazar is the entity (deity) created by The Primordials to guard over the planet of Solinia once it was seeded with the four elemental powers He is responsible for the creation of the Plane of Balance and his only son Sethris and is one of the oldest Gods, predating The Pantheon Very few sentients are aware of Belshazar See: Origins&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Boralis</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/boralis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/boralis/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boralis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The God of Knowledge and Wisdom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;divine-domains&#34;&gt;Divine Domains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge and Wisdom&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Deuzulus</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/deuzulus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/deuzulus/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuzulus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuzulus is the God of Hate and Jealousy and is the son of Ingorir and Lunarine. He is most known for his lust and eventual murder of Zephyr in cold blood said to spite Ashoka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuzulus gave access to the Plane of Wind to the Oshira which allowed the destruction of Zephyr and his elevation to God of Wind after her destruction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;caerthian-origins&#34;&gt;Caerthian Origins&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is believed Lunarine saw something terrible unfolding on Solinia during the Age of Defiance. Deciding to intervene she
approached a priest of the sun known as Ingorir. Believing it to be a messenger of Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul, Ingorir fell to his knees in awe. Lunarine caressed his cheek and smiled..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;You have a temper that others cannot see, I will see that fire stoked. Do for me just one task and I will offer you a place in permanent servitude to the blazing fires of the sun&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glaring in pure admiration at the bright glow of the Goddess he quivered &amp;lsquo;Yes&amp;hellip; anything&amp;hellip;!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She kissed his forehead and beckoned him forward, &amp;lsquo;Come - show your love to the Goddess. Our embrace shall bring forth a new order, one that will last for a hundred thousand years&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The confused priest held her hand and walked onwards into the light. &amp;lsquo;When you awake, you shall be with a gift of our union. You must ensure the Queen takes one bite. With this action you will change everything. In 20 years a journey will open towards the North, you must take it and then everything will be clear&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Goddess wrapped her arms around the priest as light shone throughout the Temple of Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;Then shall we be together once more&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bright light subsided and the priest looked upwards, lifting himself up from the floor of the temple he noticed the dragon fruit in his hand. Clasping it shut he headed straight for the palace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not long after that the queen gave birth to Deuzulus Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir, Prince and heir to the Caerthians Throne. In his youth he became fascinated with the forbidden Aerindal. How different and beautiful he thought they were, he became enamored by Princess Zephyr Vaelan, finding any way he could to get a glimpse of her beyond the northern walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was when he reached the age of 20 that a delegation of the Valderain, Keladun and Aerindal came before the Caerthians. They hoped to travel on a pilgrimage north, to the last refuge of the Dal, and ask why the earth seemed to be tearing itself apart. Seeing Zephyr was a member of the pilgrimage, Deuzulus demanded his inclusion, the Emperor was reluctant however, understanding his tutor Ingorir would be in the party, evenutally agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a long journey, frought with dangers, but the delegation finally arrived. The last remaining Dal spoke before the pilgrims and explained all she could about place they stood. The Anchor, was a place that held the past, present and future together. She spoke of an event that was happening, far in the future, that stood to tear everything apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elemental pantheon was waning, they no longer had the worshippers or energy to maintain order in the universe. It was time for a new elemental pantheon to emerge, one that could bring a new order to the world. She spoke of how the Kelderan and Dal had replaced the Prime Elemental Pantheon in the centuries earlier, and now it was time for the new races to take the mantle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With agreement, they stepped forward into the anchor, and a new Pantheon emerged&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gias of the Keladun - The Goddess of Earth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingorir of the Caerthians - The God of Fire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manandu of the Valderain - The Goddess of Water&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zephyr of the Aerindal - The Goddess of Wind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching as Zephyr vanished into the blackness of the anchor, Deuzulus screamed out &amp;lsquo;Zephyr, no! Don&amp;rsquo;t leave me!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old Dal held her hands out to the sun elf, &amp;lsquo;I am sorry child, she is no longer the one you once loved&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;She has transcended to something far greater, she will never know life as the mortals do. She has a great duty now and so have you&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elf looked, confusingly at the Dal, &amp;lsquo;What about me?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Everything must be balanced&amp;rsquo;, she smiled &amp;lsquo;And the partner of Order is Chaos&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Enruel</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/enruel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/enruel/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enruel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enruel the Ascendant - Rules over the Plane of Secrets (Principal God of Knowledge to the Meroei race)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Eriadar</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/eriadar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/eriadar/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eriadar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Eriadar the Prismatic Dragon is a child of the Plane of Balance and first to pierce the veil from the Plane into the realm of Solinia. He is responsible for the creation of the Dragons on Solinia, one of the first races to have existed. Eriadar is worshipped by 99% of dragons that remain alive on Solinia to this day&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Gias</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/gias/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/gias/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gias&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Gias is the Goddess of Earth and ruler of the Plane of Earth. It is said that Gias gifted The Aegis to Sigurd, a powerful artifact which allowed him to defeat incredible creatures.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Goryan</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/goryan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/goryan/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goryan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Goryan the Dream Maker rules over the Plane of Dreams and is mostly depicted in the apperance of a Garuda He is often seen or associated with Zurvan when he delivers prophecies in the form of visions to ones deemed fit to see the nature of all things Goryan is the counter opposite to Xetizel, the God of Nightmares, a dark crow like figure which prays upon those not strong enough to walk through the dream plane It is believed by those who worship Goryan that Solinia was destroyed during the catastrophic events of Kumari and we have long since been severed from true reality, living only in the final dream played out by the Dreammaker&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Ingorir</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/ingorir/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/ingorir/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingorir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingorir is the God of Fire, lover of Lunarine and father of Deuzulus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;caerthain-origins&#34;&gt;Caerthain Origins&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingorir began life as a humble priest to Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul and spent much of his life providing religious rites for the royal and high ranking members of the Caerthain Empire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason or another, Lunarine looked upon him favouribly and chose to position him so that he could be elevated to the new Elemental Pantheon as the God of Fire, taking the place of Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The union of of Ingorir and Lunarine resulted in the birth of Deuzulus, the eventual God of Hate&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Kylia</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/kylia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/kylia/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kylia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Kylia the Tempest was a member of the Prime Elemental Pantheon and creator of elemental titans and seafolk that would cleanse the lands with tsunamis and endless tempests during The Great Cleansing Ruler of Raelion - The Field of Storms (Plane of Storms). The lands of Qylia takes it name from this Goddess&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Lunarine</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/lunarine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/lunarine/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunarine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Lunarine is the Goddess of Strategy and Conquest and lover of Ingorir the God of Fire. They bore a son named Deuzulus who became the God of Hatred and Jealousy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is credited with the elevation of Ingorir from a mortal Caerthian to the Elemental God of Fire&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Methabeht</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/methabeht/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/methabeht/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methabeht&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Methabeht is certainly not a name from the true tongue of the Tinai but it some other race that potentially existed a long time ago. The tales of bards that have been passed down for generations speak of him as The Life Bearer and he is often associated with healing and birth. However, due to the age of the stories most people do not believe him to exist accept a few prophets often branded as madmen. Including the Cult of Methabeht. In the tales The Tinai, a race of angel like creatures, were known to worship him and him alone&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Salus</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/salus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/salus/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
God of Health and Salvation worshipped by Eusebians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;divine-domains&#34;&gt;Divine Domains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health and Salvation&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Savira</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/savira/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/savira/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Savira&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Savira the Enflamed was a member of the Prime Elemental Pantheon and responsible for creating the unstoppable weapon know as Xephrit Syfyr a Purefire dragon who would lead an army of flaming elementals during The Great Cleansing Ruler of Sindiril - The Palace of Flames (Plane of Flames) Her child Xephrit Syfyr due to its incredible power is worshipped as a god in its own right&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Sethris</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/sethris/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/sethris/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sethris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Sethris the Stalker is the God of Balance and Master of the Hunt. Worshipped by most tribal and feral races he is popular particularly among the Chunel Sethris rules over the Plane of Balance and represents the balance of nature Sethris can take many forms and is often worshipped by those who inhabit the dangerous jungles of Solinia, he is usually depicted as a jet black jaguar or a amazonian stylised male hunter He is the only son of Belshazar and draws power from his fathers plane and as such represents an aspect of his fathers power. He is opposed to the influence of the material and any attempts to redirect the course of the natural order of things&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Sl&#39;Vastra</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/slvastra/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/slvastra/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sl&amp;rsquo;Vastra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Sl&amp;rsquo;Vastra was once a mortal Oshira that is said to have been the first being to master the arts of Translocation. Using this she led the Oshira all over Solinia conquering and enslaving all races in her path. Not content with the people of the earth she led her campaign into the Planes of the Gods and killed Zephyr the Blazen Goddess of Wind taking the plane as her own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This act infuriated the pantheon but allowed Sl&amp;rsquo;Vastra to be elevated to Demi Goddess of Rage for which she is now known as The Ravager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Itis unknown how Sl&amp;rsquo;Vastra mastered the arts of Translocation, but some believe Deuzulus had some involvment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After centuries of enslavement of other races Sl&amp;rsquo;Vastra entered the Plane of Wind in the Lost Age and executed the Goddess Zephyr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elevation to Demi Goddess of Rage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oshira&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Sol&#39;Azul</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/solazul/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/solazul/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul is the Caerthian God of the Sun&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Somnus</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/somnus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/somnus/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somnus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Somnus the Shaderider is the God of Shade and Darkness and rules over the Plane of Shade. It is believed Somnus was the lover of Zephyr and her death plunged him into an enormous depression. Some say that Somnus gifted the Mysmaal Vampirism because of the death of Zephyr but none know of the true reason This god is often attributed as the main deity of the Mysmaal Somnus fell into deep depression after the death of Zephyr - he despises the Oshira to this death for their involvement Somnus gifted the Mysmaal with Vampirism in the Lost Age&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Syfyr</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/syfyr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/syfyr/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syfyr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Syfyr is a diety worshiped by the Gialon of Nasudana and believed to represent the element of purefire&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Weaver</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/the-weaver/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/the-weaver/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Weaver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A deity mentioned in Genesis and sometimes named Kali or Hallistra&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Zephyr</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/zephyr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/zephyr/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zephyr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Zephyr the Blazen was the Goddess of Air before her destruction at the hands of Empress Sl&amp;rsquo;Vastra, leader of the Oshira which was orchestrated by Deuzulus, the God of Hatred and Jealousy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zephyr was the lover of Somnus and Ashoka, her death was responsible for Somnus&amp;rsquo;s plunge into deep depression&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zephyr was an Elemental level deity and it is believed one of the earliest members of the modern day Pantheon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;death&#34;&gt;Death&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zephyr met her end in the Lost Age at the hands of Sl&amp;rsquo;Vastra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her realm, the Plane of Wind is now ruled over by Sl&amp;rsquo;Vastra the Ravager who has twisted it to her own image&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;origins-as-a-caerthain&#34;&gt;Origins as a Caerthain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zephyr was born Zephyr Vaelan, Aerindal and Princess of the Vaelen Dynasty of Eindel. Having lived her youth on Qylia she was a member of a party which made a pilgrimage to The Anchor in the era known as The Age of Defiance. On her arrival, she met with the last of the Dal and was elevated to the Elemental Diety of Wind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rescue-of-zephyr&#34;&gt;Rescue of Zephyr&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the events of the Time Crisis, an adventurer known as Natalie found a way to travel back in time to the Age of Defiance and rescue Zephyr before her murder at the hands of the Oshira, she was then transported to Amaria where she prevented the destruction of the Aerindal at the hands of Hiran Asura and the Caerthian armies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battle took a great amount of energy from Zephyr, and her wearabouts are currently unknown, it is believed she travelled north to the Severed Isles with the escapees of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/the-caerthian-invasion&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Caerthian Invasion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Zhuvirae</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/zhuvirae/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/zhuvirae/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhuvirae&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Zhuvirae is the Goddess of the Moon and Matron of Shadow It is believed her influence lays over the celestial moon known as Shima She is a patron goddess of Taxicost and is believed to be from a different Pantheon than those of standard deities of Solinia. Due to this, Zhuvirae is considered one of the &amp;lsquo;Outsiders&amp;rsquo; Zhuvirae shares many similar influence powers to the Somnus, God of Shadow and it is believed that she occupies his position in a different pantheon from either a different area of the universe or perhaps the multiverse Zhuvirae appears to have an influence over the Spirit Realm and is often spoken of in Shaman texts. The majority of her worshippers are beings that occupy the moon of Shima but there are other creatures on Solinia who she has contacted Her primary concern is the infiltration of the Solinian Plane of Shadow, a war which she has been engaging with against Somnus since her arrival She is directly opposed to all beings of Light and Sun, such as Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul and Auroris Some vampires worship her, but Mysmaal oppose all belief in her and follow Somnus exclusively due to the gift he gave them&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Zurvan</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/zurvan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/gods/zurvan/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zurvan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mortals have been gifted the power of free will which often directly contradicts the divine will of the Gods. Due to this the Gods actions often only steer the direction of men. All of the Gods hold sway over areas of power and influence and all power flows downwards from the upper pantheon. The non discordant Gods primary desire is to maintain balance and offer stability to a reality which can only extend so far when coming into contact with beings who hold the power of free will&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to this it was necessary for a being which could foresee all potential realities laid bare by the manifested power of mortals so that each potential outcome of an event could be influenced in a direction to maintain a stable reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing how such a power could benefit him the Dark God Etsi did take on the form of a beautiful female mortal named Eloria who&amp;rsquo;s glowing skin and figure was said to rival even the Goddess of Beauty, enamoured by this maidens form Bolaris the God of Knowledge did lay with her and she give birth to a child named Zurvan, blessed with the power of knowledge and wisdom and tutored by Etsi, Dark Lord of Bargains. As the divine child grew in age and power he began to foresee future events before they happened, whispering in the ears of his mother the outcomes of deals she would make. Etsi, in his ruse when bargaining with other Gods consolidated great power during this time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not until the boy grew into a man that Etsis power over the child begin to falter. As his power grew he began to see not only events that would come but events that had or could have already happened. Seeing through his mother&amp;rsquo;s questions and their true purpose he would no longer aid her in acts of trickery, in a fit of rage Etsi cast the young man down from her plane onto Solinia never to return to the realms of the pantheon until he agreed to help her once more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alone and wondering the lands of men Zurvan came into contact with many mortals many who began to follow and worship him as a great prophet of fortune and foresight. Each contact with beings of free will took its toll on Zurvan as his powers of divination grew more complex and chaotic with each encounter. With so many potential realities and destinies of these mortal beings, Zurvans mind began to shatter, his language becoming ever more unintelligible and his writings become odd patterns and symbols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Zurvans ideas and stories became increasingly abstract and confusing (even his body appearing weakened as the burden of his gift appeared to take a toll on him physically) one of his most devout apostles began to write down the divine words into The Great Book of Destiny a task which drove each new scribe into an ever increasing madness. The task passed down from person to person as each apostle was slowly lost to the chaos in Zurvans teachings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing the great suffering of his child Boralis cursed Etsi. Beseaching Boryan, The God of Dreams to place Zurvan in a peaceful sleep so that his physical body may rest as his mind grappled with the nature of time. It was there on the edges of the Plane of Dreams that the Plane of Time would sprout, it&amp;rsquo;s many paths spreading out into a complex maze of walkways along the sound of ticking clocks did Zurvan wander, occasionally passing great messages to his apostles on Solinia through the dreams of Goryan so the Great Book may continue to be written&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said the Great Book is still maintained by a secret order of paladins and shall one day find its way into the hands of a worthy mortal so it&amp;rsquo;s teachings can lead them through a time of great calamity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;divine-domains&#34;&gt;Divine Domains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Destiny&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>