<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Locations</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/</link><description>Recent content in Locations on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Acacia</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/acacia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/acacia/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acacia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Acacia is home to various casts of Lidkim, a lizard like race that have existed on this continent for centuries. Originally hailing from their capital of Chelthix they have since been ravaged by an everlasting war between themselves and a subsect of cannibals known as the Zunak. Acacia is also home to once Vishim explorers who have made a home here and seek to aid the Lidkim with their troubles.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt; Something happened on this island many thousands of years ago that raised the entire western portion of the island and scorched the once wild forests that covered the land. During this time, the Lidkim speak of a curse that tainted their kin and transformed them into cannibals which resulted in the the total annihilation of their capital Chelthix. Fortunately for the remaining sane Lidkim the Vishim, who had recently begun a seafaring race, arrived and formed a partial alliance with them in agreement for land on the eastern shore to study the architecture and gather resources. The Vishim soon established the city of Braemar and eventually the fort of Fiongate that some Lidkim use as temporary housing although most prefer to stay in the lost capital of Chelthix which they hope to one day rebuild if they can finally rid the land of the Zunak.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Transport Links&lt;/strong&gt; The Vishim port of Braemar is established on the north eastern shores of the continent which is the main hub to other locations on the world.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; Azura Beza Tean&amp;rsquo;Zu The White Mount Lost Chelthix Braemar Feryn&amp;rsquo;s Scar Fiongate Llys Don Stormhold&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; Dangerous wildlife, monsters, weather and so forth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The continent itself is split into two very distinct plateus that are accessible by the giant waterfall next to the Lost Chelthix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also to the north west can be found a long stretch of mountains where the pyramids Azura and Beza can be found as well as a sacred mountain known to the Lidkim as the White Mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flora-fauna&#34;&gt;Flora &amp;amp; Fauna&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the unusual geography this land contains all manners of unusual stones and plantlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lower section of the island is home to many snakes and cats that appear to have made their way from the western plateau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upper plateua is home to all manners of poisonous and wild creatures. Mostly desert cougars and scorpians from Feryn&amp;rsquo;s Scar as well as a large amount of sand and dust elementals. Not to mention the many undead Lidkim.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Alaris</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alaris/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alaris/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alaris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alaris was a city founded by the descendents of the deserted crew ofElement 5 in the Western Continents of Solinia far to the south ofKumari on the many island chains. It’s people eventually migrated to the Northlands where they discovered relics of the past which had become known as the site of the Exerak Incursion, a giant temple filled with ancient racial history far underground. With this invaluable information the people sailed far east to their homelands with information that could change everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to records, during the expedition home to Tsiyon , the fleet stopped at an island to resupply food and materials for the journey home. This island was fondly named by it’s people as Aquion for it’s many clear water lakes and the vast ocean that surrounded it. After the fleet had resupplied, some of the expedition stayed behind. It is known that due to the boom in prospecting these settlers eventually discovered the lost continent of Kumari far to the north where the Kingdoms of New Meropis were founded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Alarans of Northreach were dedicated to the old ways of Element 5 and many have considered them to be worshippers of the water elements due to their many relics depicting trident idols and other ocean dieities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city of Alaris itself had a mixture of cultures and people due to the many races that made up the old crew of Element 5 but the city was eventually abandoned, along with Northreach following an invasion of undead triggered by the discovery of the Exerak Incursion site.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Alcor</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alcor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Over the centuries the continent of Alcor has been home to many cultures. In modern day, the continent can most assurably be noted as under the control of the Kandam Empire except for a few pockets of cities that are under constant attack by the Kandamese aggressors. The oldest civilisation to exist on the island would be the Mysmaal, an eternal vampiric race which rule from the northern city of Mysma which stays out of the conflicts that have always trouble the continent but over the recent years, seclusion and hiding has become more and more difficult. The Kandamese empire hold the majority of control over the continent and attack any that attempt to land by outsiders. The meropii would be more welcoming but they are so tucked into the forests that they rarely get to meet any outsiders. This does not stop others from sneaking onto the island to aquire its many forms of poison.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt; Originally the continent was home to the grand white city of Eusebes a center of art and culture to many in the southern hemisphere. Alas, as with all good things it eventually collapsed, segmenting it&amp;rsquo;s people into five tribes. The new tribes that grew out of this event include the Kandamese, Meropii and Kitezhan. During this time the tribes experienced relative peace amongst each other, respecting each others differences as they always had during the time of Eusebes. However, on the crowning of Kandamese Holy Emperor Dravidian, Kitezhan was eventually invaded by the Kandamese people and, despite the efforts of the Meropii tribe to protect the Kitezhan&amp;rsquo;s, it eventually fell, remaining to this day as under ground ruins inhabited by the remnents of the Kandamese forces. To this day, the Meropii remain under assault from the Kandamese forces at their city of Meropis on the western corners of the continent and have so far experienced success in their defensive strategy thanks to an alliance of sorts with the creatures that inhabit the forests to the south of their borders.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; The Ruins of Kitezh Old Eusebes The Holy City of Meropis Dark City of Kandam Mysma, Tower of Undeath&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; Most wildlife and even civilisations on this continent are naturally aggressive towards any outsiders. Except the meropii, who even though good aligned, are still cautious of any outsiders due to the many attempts of sabotage on their people by the Kandamese. The most dangerous of threats on the island would certainly be the Mysmans, an ancient vampiric race which fortunately remains secluded most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alcor, despite existing so close to the southern colder regions, is mostly tropical and covered in dense Jungles inhabitted by all manner of wild creatures. Disease and poison are a common issue for the inhabitants of this island to which has contributed towards them become skilled herbalists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flora-fauna&#34;&gt;Flora &amp;amp; Fauna&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All manner of creatures inhabit the continent, mostly a extensive variety of birds and reptiles which find a home in Alcor including the swamplands of Schera, the jungles of Virumaa and the holy sanctuary of the Himapan Forest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-resources&#34;&gt;Natural Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alcor is renound for it&amp;rsquo;s poisons which brings assassins from all over the world of Solinia. It is also known for it&amp;rsquo;s abundant supply of timber and white rock.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Amaria</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/amaria/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/amaria/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amaria&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Amaria is an archipaelo that snakes across the far south east of the planet Solinia. The island chain itself is currently undiscovered by most races of Solinia. Due to the sizes of the islands and the peculiarity of its position on the planet there lays a variety of topical features from wind swept deserts to frigid icy plains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recent-history&#34;&gt;Recent History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the events of Time Crisis the survivors found themselves in the newly formed land of Amaria&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appeared to be a place locked between many periods of time with people and cities of the modern era as well as the old&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old long lost empires such as the Caerthian Empire subjugated most of the lands and this led to an escape of the lands via the way of the Sea surrounding the Qylian Western Isles and landed on the The Severed Isles&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Angel Isles</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/angel-isles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/angel-isles/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angel Isles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Angel Isles are a set of lands in the south of Solinia inhabited by Mysmaal and Orc It was in the recent era that the Mysmaal assisted the escaped Meroei, Corrupt Vishim and Nijin from the Dead lands of The Jungle The odd weather patterns and location of the islands allow the varying climates but most of the area is covered in unihabited frozen tundra where the ruins of Balrud lay It is believed the Angel Isles got their name from the Tinai as there lays an ancient lost Tinai Temple at the junction point between several of the islands&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Asgarad</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/asgarad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/asgarad/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asgarad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Home to the Vishim a human like race that once hailed from Caer Bedion. Also a cast of Subhumans which the Vishim consider barbaric make their home in Faen&amp;rsquo;Dan. This village has existed for as long as the Vishim can remember and they have held a friendly alliance against the forces of Balor that seep from from the northern and eastern areas of the continent. Both races have become exceedingly efficient at hunting undead, one through highly tuned skill of weaponry and magic and the other through brute force. Other races are known to inhabit the lands of Asgarad including the Yotes and a cast of Eiao to the far north. Both of these races have little dealing with the barbaric subhumans and Vishim and these days prefer to keep themselves to themselves. Whether this is due to events in the past not many are sure.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Transport Links&lt;/strong&gt; Ravenholme acts a port to connect Asgarad to Avalon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; Ravenholme Faen&amp;rsquo;Dan Lunacia Barrik&amp;rsquo;s Fall Caer Bedion Balor&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; Aside from the many aggressive animals on this continent Undead are without doubt a major problem to the localised races. Mostly spawning out of the many graves of the ruined human city of Myrgard they also smother the entire northern continent as they spew forth from the ancient tower of Balor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asgarad is mostly covered in tundra, mountains and forests and is situated in the very far south of the southern hemisphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flora-fauna&#34;&gt;Flora &amp;amp; Fauna&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the snow covered peaks many polar bears, mammoths and wolves can be found. This is a common source of protein for the villages of Lunacia and Faen&amp;rsquo;Dan. In the outer areas beyond the snowy peaks one may find a variety of wolves, rabbits and many birds which the Vishim appear to avoid hunting in favour of wild fruits and nuts except in the occasional need for population control which they normally leave to the Caer Bedion Rangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-resources&#34;&gt;Natural Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stone, metals and timber are in high quantity in this land. Also of note is a unique type of ice that appears to be an excellent for building if kept at the correct temperatures. This has been attributed to the natural beauty of Caer Bedion which is completely built of this material.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Avalon</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/avalon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/avalon/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avalon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Originally located on their first maiden voyage from Asgarad, the Vishim have made the majority of this continent their home and use the lands for food and resource supplies for Ravenholme. Over the years the port of Westhaven has grown and many have settled here permanently. Many Vishim rangers travel to Shadowmoor to begin their training. Avalon is also home to The Garuda a race of birdmen that inhabit the Monastary of Amonsul.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Transport Links&lt;/strong&gt; Westhaven acts a port to connect Asgarad and Acacia to Avalon.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; Shadowmoor Monastary of Amonsul Mt Athos Westhaven Xzarkot&amp;rsquo;s Tower&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; Higher into the mountains can be found stone elementals that have been known to be aggressive to outsiders. Also to the almost impassible north can be found the tower of the mad Geomancer Xzarkot. The Vishim suffered many casualties scouting Xzarkot&amp;rsquo;s Tower when they originally came to Avalon but have found that he has no interest in the outsiders so long as they stay far away from the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the western area of this land is covered in dense forests which provide a bounty of fruits and berries. To the center of the island can be found Mt Athos believed to be a holy location to the native stone elementals.
Resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many varieties of rocks can be found on this location as well as an abundant supply of timber, fruit and some freshwater fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flora-fauna&#34;&gt;Flora &amp;amp; Fauna&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most wildlife here are forest dwellers including wolves, bears and other animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mountains themselves are home to a number of stone elementals.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Esoron</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/esoron/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/esoron/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;Esoron is the landmass that represented all of the Tinai territory prior to the destruction of the cataclysm&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Garden of the Gods</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/garden-of-the-gods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/garden-of-the-gods/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garden of the Gods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A place said to lay at the northern most part of the World&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Halcron</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/halcron/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/halcron/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halcron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Meroei hold dominion over many of the lands of Halcron and have built the grandest capital on Solinia full of many of the races of the world. Also to the far west the Ogres hold their capital in Osogok . To the far north are the Gobel a menace to the Meroei and deadly in combat due to their ever increasing numbers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Transport Links&lt;/strong&gt; Tsiyon acts as a hub and a central port for nearly every city on Solinia.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; Tsiyon Moracre Forest Greenbarrow Wheton Aldgate Ruins of Ephesus Osogok Upper Plains of Karnon Lower Plains of Karnon Blacklight Forest Silvershade Lake River Erilyn Glacies Cavern Cryswind Peak&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; The largest threat to the civilised inhabitants of Halcron are the Gobel , grotesque evil creatures of which there are many in and beyond the northern mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rolling plains and mountains cover most of Halcron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flora-fauna&#34;&gt;Flora &amp;amp; Fauna&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wolves, snakes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-resources&#34;&gt;Natural Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halcron contains many types of wild animals that roams the forests and plains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halcron is also unique in that the Cryswind Peak and the mountains surrounding it contain nearly all types of metals used by the Meroei.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Kumari (Kandam)</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kumari (Kandam)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Kumari has seen many ancient races rise and fall and was once the seat of power for the Dragons far atop Mount Enlil . It was the birthplace of the Orc races at Id Kura, the location of the creation of the Half Dragons and more recently the bastion of the Western Alliance in the Kingdoms of New Meropis . Sitting valiantly at it&amp;rsquo;s center is Solinia&amp;rsquo;s largest mountain range and many varieties of terrains cover the rest of the massive continent. Kumari finally fell as a continent when the storm dragon Python opened the Tomb of Hiran Asura deep under the kingdoms of new meropis. The people that did survive this cataclysm fled east across the ocean. They still bear the name Kumarian for their time here. Travel to and from Kumari extends southwards through the many isles access to the rest of the world is blocked due to the raging sea Occupied by Dragon, Half Dragon, ProtoHuman, Orc, Goblin and more&lt;br /&gt;
**Locations of Interest ** The Ruins of Valum Vaton The Gate of Id-Kura Xenophon&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; Undead, Elementals, Dragons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several flat planes a gigantic mountain surrounded by many smaller islands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-resources&#34;&gt;Natural Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puresnow, lava, ash, metals, minerals, charcoal&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Nasudana</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/nasudana/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/nasudana/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nasudana&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Nasudana is home to the Gialon an elemental race hailing from The Temple of Syfyr. The Vishim have also recently made their home here and have settled the town of Aldwynne to the East of Silverwyn lake. Many Vishim diviners travel here for the strange visions that are given to them in the waters as well as the unsual healing properties that the island holds.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt; This continent has clearly been home to another race that appears to have abandoned it some centuries ago as proven by the presence of Agartha as well as the giant Exarak Monument. The Gialon have little interest in the structure (or are withholding information from others) and the Vishim are still attempting to uncover more information since most of it is fallen and buried deep underground. Leaving just the architecture for investigation and the real treasures out of reach. It will take some time to uncover all of it&amp;rsquo;s secrets and the Vishim have sent considerable archaelogists to uncover more. However, some artifacts of note depicting what appear to be events in history have been recovered and are on display in Ravenholme. Some believe that the Hoakan&amp;rsquo;s once originated from this location, leaving due to some invading race. Evidence has been found by the Vishim of a lost civilisation but no invading army.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Transport Links&lt;/strong&gt; A small dock has been setup just south of Aldwynne which is used to export some resources and for visitors.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; Mt. Syfyr Aldwynne Agartha The Temple of Syfyr The Exarak Monument&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; This island is mostly a spiritual sanctuary and even the Gialon, who are known to have quite a temper, are accepting of outsiders (so long as they stay out of their business).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nasudana is entirely covered in forest, except for the north eastern mountains surrounding The Temple of Syfyr. This place is also home to an inactive Volcano which the Gialon seem to have a natural affinity to and worship it as a god.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flora-fauna&#34;&gt;Flora &amp;amp; Fauna&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many rare flowers can be found in the forests which are often used as perfumes and for some herbal remedies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large proportion of birds, woodland creatures and earth elementals. Some fire elementals can also be found near the volcano but they do not seem to venture much further. However, this has not always been the case the Vishim have discovered many burned sections of the forest that appear to have regrown at a rapid rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-resources&#34;&gt;Natural Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This continent is home to many unusual forms of metal and stone which are mostly exported to Westhaven by the Vishim.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Nuchalnuth</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/nuchalnuth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/nuchalnuth/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nuchalnuth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A number of cultures are native to Nuchalnuth, including the Takafi, the Morannon, the Navajo and the Chunel. The western region of Nuchalnuth, the Plains of Jingara, are a very dry and inhospitable climate. Mostly flat, water is at a premium in many areas. To the north, the Skaranach Highlands become hillier and, to the Northwest, more lush. The Jungles of Metnalba, located to the west, are dense with verdant growth. Hills are common, with streams and rivers darting under the canopy like quicksilver. Green Hell, the thin bridge of land connecting southern Metnalba with Jingara, is a unique area. It has no true ground, only the monolithic trees in which all manner of life can be found Verlore lays in the western regions of Jingara. It is from Nuchalnuth that Rhukadlor commands the invasion of the Southern continents. In the heyday of the Human Empire, Nuchalnuth was heavily populated. Some of the leading scientists of the time conducted their work in what is now the Jungles of Metnalba, and Jingara was home to a unique tradition of spiritualists. This all came crashing down when the empire fell, and now all that&amp;rsquo;s left is crumbling ruins. Nachulnuth is believed to be the location of the south of the Spellstorm&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Taon</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/taon/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Taon is a continent in the planet of Solinia. It is cut off from the rest of the world following a Spellstorm some time around the Lost Age It is the ancestral home of the Mysmaal prior to their arrival on Alcor&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Severed Isles</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Severed Isles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Severed Isles are a selection of small islands to the north east of Qylia and south of the Garden of the Gods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main four islands are Candus, Elyan, Karnak and Utra consisting of a wide variety of topical climates and fauna&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Dessai</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/dessai/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/dessai/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dessai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Dessai&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Other</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/other/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/other/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Other&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Qylia</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/qylia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/qylia/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qylia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Qylia&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Planes of the Gods</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-planes-of-the-gods/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Planes of the Gods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Planes of the Gods&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>