<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Southern Wastes</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/southern-wastes/</link><description>Recent content in Southern Wastes on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/southern-wastes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Ranthans Ridge</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/southern-wastes/ranthans-ridge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/southern-wastes/ranthans-ridge/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranthans Ridge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Ranthans Ridge&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Summit of the Fallen</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/southern-wastes/summit-of-the-fallen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/southern-wastes/summit-of-the-fallen/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summit of the Fallen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recenty arrivals of the Wastes are the illusive Shattered Wing arm of the Asurans. They have constructed an impenetrable
fort in the wastes not far south from the Fading Wilds. It currently unclear what the purpose of the Asurans are. Some believe the
summit is holy place, dedicated to their God, Hiran Asura. Others are not so certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The House of the Shattered Wing is currently led by Lord Alastor Az&amp;rsquo;zealeif who makes his home in the summit. It appears he has been particularly
interesting in monitoring the progress of the recent survivors that crash landed on the southern coasts of the Blackfeather Plains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Summit is surrounded by a Faded village, who have come to pay homage to the the temple in the summit and await the arrival of the demi god Hiran Asura&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only time will tell what the purpose of the Asurans are on the Island and why they are so interested in those that have arrived but
few believe that it will be benevolent&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>