<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Misc</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/</link><description>Recent content in Misc on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Music</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/music/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/music/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazing Music by artists including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Buckley - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scottbuckley.com.au/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.scottbuckley.com.au/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tristan Lohengrin - &lt;a href=&#34;https://tristanlohengrin.bandcamp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://tristanlohengrin.bandcamp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peritune - &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/sei_peridot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://soundcloud.com/sei_peridot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bensound - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bensound.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.bensound.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Wei Script</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/wei-script/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/wei-script/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wei Script&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very rare script found on ancient structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These symbols also appear on the Exarak Monument on Nasudana&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Old Item Lore</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/old-item-lore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/old-item-lore/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old Item Lore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Old Item Lore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tend to your dead when the battle is done if you tend to the wounded til the battle is won&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conjuring fire was one of the first abilities taught to the magicians of Tsiyon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear to you, Lord Methabeht, smite my enemy and I shall forever give myself in service. - Darakua&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old elemental school page detailing the art of summoning perfect circles of frost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dusty parchment documents the history of the Mysmaal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hunting a winged beast is easier done when they are young - Elarok Lightbringer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Modern Humans seem to be just as obsessed with knowledge as their predecessors - Salvador Kondrat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A warrior&amp;rsquo;s stamina reserves are invaluable in the heat of battle Captain Bynde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forward my brothers! We shall win the day! General Mato&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through a cloud of blood, the warrior seeks h&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that bow, call from the sky for arrows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observe my brothers, the gift of the gods!- Ioni Miriad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no haste when traveling this land, move quickly to your destination. Sepa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who needs air when Methabeht will provide? Ioni Miriad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to my children, I leave this cloth. As shelter and safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good look hitting me! Bleed of the Cell Squad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battle was fierce and lasted weeks, the O&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They shot through the dark pines hungry for their next meal, in a pack as one. Scholar Aquilar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arcane Shield is passed down since the time of the Vishim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lizardmen have always had the ability to take a few more hits when the going gets tough General Mato&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ancient curse of Deuzulus, passed down for generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beings of the element can survive in places others could never Scholar Aquilar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power of &amp;lsquo;Blinking&amp;rsquo; is taught to High Human children at an early age. Scholar Aquilar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Halfling race has always been a hard one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ogre&amp;rsquo;s can use their sheer mass to great effect in combat Captain Bynde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trolls have an innate ability to summon bursts of furious strength Captain Bynde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple piece of technology developed by the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The various diseases carried by the undead&amp;rsquo;s rotten flesh are often turned on their enemies. Scholar Aquilar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The charge of a Barbarian is a sight to behold Captain Bynde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are coming for us brothers! We shall make them rue the day! General Mato&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ancient mechanical weapon of the clockworks is legend Scholar Aquilar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bleeding foe will fall with ease Captain Bynde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To block an attack is the first step, it only becomes useful if you can retaliate Captain Bynde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This spell seems to have storm runes on it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draw upon the power of the under dark to swee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There lay in front of them their beloved rule&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like minded elves find comfort in their share&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You draw upon the legacy of your people to ai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Foresworn&amp;rsquo;s blessing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forsaken turn their ancient curse against&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Clockworks have springed heels, allowing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The races of the combine agreed upon a sacred&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes not aiming for one target is exactly what you need Captain Bynde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To shoot a foe is easy, to hit them in such a way that you remain hidden, now that is a skill! Rauchlehre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backlash is the staple of many Tsiyonian Magician&amp;rsquo;s arsenals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A well timed dash can confuse and disorient your opponent, leaving them open to an attack Rauchlehre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those goblins can disappear at a moment&amp;rsquo;s notice, be on your guard men! Rauchlehre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although not the most powerful spell, Magic Missile is a standard spell that every aspiring young mage must know. -Scholar Aquilar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel the breath of Methabeht upon you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Magicians of Tsiyon are renown for their ability to create storms of flames&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look upwards my son, see what methabeht can bring for us - Druid Kenria Selri&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through worship we can call upon aid in our times of need - Ioni Miriad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold! The gods look favourably upon you! - Ioni Miriad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dead dare not speak of what lays within that ancient ring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ilandria clammered up the ancient steps of that forgotten temple - the Tinai were real!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shamans of old could bring the spirits to bear witness against the living&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goblin shamans were the foremost in curse-mongering spirits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once used by the Machelite Wizards for aid with thier footings on the passes of thier mountain home&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that halflings tend to hide their armour under their clothes, leaving their opponent unsure how well armoured they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Half Elves seem to have taken the most beneficial traits of the Elves and Humans to make them into skilled runners&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked deep into his eyes and he looked deep into me, into my very essence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With wings outstretched they took to the sky!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pah, you call that magic! - Last words of Kliri Xeria&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch your step about fairy rings. Lest you find that somethings queer. Once you were there and now your here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh Manandu! Spare my people from this wretched disease!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methabeht, I beseech thee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll have to get that looked at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ha! Ashtor stands with me this day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we can do better than that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The God of the Hunt blessed this arrow herself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT DID YOU SAY!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eat my friends! Eat, everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastering the art of sorcery against one target is all well and good, but what about when you are surrounded?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had lost his mind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come forth to me brethren!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off we go then!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only those that could withstand the flames could converse with the lord of fire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A guardian must be unwavering when facing an enemy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-silence-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will never forget&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instant death with only one shot - of course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send your dogs, do your worst! We have a cause to fight for and we will never give in to the likes of you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rangers of Asgarad were known for their prayers to Methabeht&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how it is possible to take the power of Ice Comet and turn it into many?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your blades will do nothing against that mad mage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the creatures of the wild fear them, for they stand at the very top of the food chain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 years he&amp;rsquo;s conquered that arena - i don&amp;rsquo;t see him giving it up any time soon - Joaira Ragepaw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah you! Come on then! - Liak Ragebourne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s that over there in the trees? - The last words of James Hammerthorn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the arrival of the new gods, everything will change - Prophet Envarik&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conflagration, my dear boy - Arcanist Deliar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes I&amp;rsquo;m ready! - Ebonclaw Direrage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yer gonna get it! - Dwarven Battle Cleric Halrak Irontoe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spells are all good, but what happens when you get into a real fight, mage? - Warrior Guildmaster Tempra Stormhand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few have spoken of the Burning Circle of Unseen hands, their dark bargains and treacherous deeds are rarely heard of twice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relax your mind - Enchanter Jyani&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand your ground!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give you about, hmm, 3 seconds - Spellweaver Wellan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steady! Steady! FIRE!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must carry on - Nightstalker Rin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder, hmm, yes perhaps this should work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something a matter with your sword, friend? - Arcanist Losian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let them run, the poison will run it&amp;rsquo;s course&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TO THE DEATH!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your end shall be my beginning - Xul&amp;rsquo;Varien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Duneguard worship tranquility above all&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though your journey shall be long and full of hardship, i will watch over you - Methabeht&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Om nom nom nom nom!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time for a beating boys! - Arngank Terra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annihalate them all - Captain Bosac&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot be moved! - Wraithclaw Savagecry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your life shall be mine! - Necromancer Teria&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the power of nature be your wrath - Josiak Rosethorn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to find your souls true home and return to it at will through translocation - Tresta Reinan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through manipulation of the soul, we may now advance our research to return others to their souls bound location - Tresta Reinan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love you Selorian, I always will - King Lerian II&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He just stood there like he didn&amp;rsquo;t feel a thing - Sage Santia Derman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to flee Kumari, Now!! - Xiea Veredeth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shielding provided can be repaired but only with the favour of the divine - Exarch Oliak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was there that Shenyi faced Hiran Asura&amp;rsquo;s mightiest generals and slayed them all with his mighty bow - Scholar Aquinas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the cold has set in, the pain will eat at you like any other poison - Mial Sirik&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marianas secret is not widely known&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magic can be a force for order or chaos, pupil. which will you choose? - Evoker Xamir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The God of the Hunt directly influences the Ranger as they run faster for a short period of time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Ranger becomes more adept, they can use their own stamina pools to rush in or out of danger for a time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ranger learns to master their own body, and can force themselves to run at abnormal speeds to better hunt their prey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give into the primal instinct of your prey and use their own speed to hunt them in the wild&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intense testing of potion ingredients has allowed the Ranger to blend in with their environment for a short time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do not need shields when you have knowledge - Markkar Rae&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your arrow surrounds the prey with a glowing aura, allowing you to track them for a short while&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early Rangers discovered a way to coat their daggers with a minor poison. This poison does not last very long, but it was a step in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worshippers of Auroris have been known to summon his wrath&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some wizards have mastered the power of striking his enemies with thunder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wizards of races that live in cold places have the power of casting a ice bolt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Thunder Strike, like the thunder bolt, strikes Thunder upon their opponent but with increased ferocity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ignorir, the god of fire has drowned his victims in a cloud of pure fire - The Trials of Liona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The powers he held were unfathomable, the skies would fall at his beckoning - Excerpts of The Proteans&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashtor has blessed us this day, so raise your bows high rangers! We will shall never fall! - Tyric Stormborn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have learned to manifest pure cataclysm in your hands student. Use this power wisely. - Archmage Carrack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magic is but a tool to an end, today you shall learn how to meet your goals - Elder Aandal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somnus the Shaderider is the God of Shade and Darkness and rules over the Plane of Shade. It is believed Somnus was the lover of Zephyr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was three times - In the prison of Zuriel. I was in the citadel - With Shana and Alpha. I witnessed the destruction Of all of Esoron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whats better than heat? More heat! - Arion Firelance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the chaos Hiran Asura caused, deep within he suffers most of all from regret. This is what fuels his fury&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our extended use of alteration, a theory i call Translocation, we will soon enter the planes of the gods themselves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more shall you be after my knife is drawn&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shall not fall when my heart becomes lame! My foes shall not pike me when my own body sags in the trenches of the Under! - Captain Le&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes my ol&amp;rsquo; eyes tear to do this, but it needs teh be done. -Banly Mixxerit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give &amp;lsquo;em a good sluggin&amp;rsquo;. They deserve it for challenging you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rings of Solinia were built by a now forgotten people, we believe them to be a place of worship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auroris, look down upon us from the Plane of Sun and save us from this calamity!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Careful! Don&amp;rsquo;t play with fire!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hot in here? Or is it just me..?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you smoke? Not anymore!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smoking is bad for your Elf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the mountanous terrain most of the birdmen of Hoa&amp;rsquo;Kar live on high&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ArchWizard Aerin Starfire mastered the art of translocation and travel most of Solinia. Famous for rediscovering to Alaris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep in the south the Underking did wander, coercing all in his path to spite his brother&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stolen the power of coersion he did and with that power he enslaved all in his path - Gobel Sage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick! Run to your sobering foe across the woods. Catch up to their measly selves!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A soul is bound always to a location, forever to return even in death&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bai Hu! Mighty spirit god! Aid us this day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xuan Wu! Mighty Turtle! Clear me of my wounds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold the trap now lays waiting for the game to fall into - Mysmaal Hunter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look! The forest is consuming him! - Ranger Misgar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chestplate was worn by a famous shadow knight&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Created in the forges of the Plane of Hate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assembled by Methabeht himself in the Plane of Nature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A helm blessed by Asthor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tunic blessed by Asthor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pair of leggings blessed by Asthor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pair of boots blessed by Asthor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This orcish armour seems imbued by magic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This armour is covered in runic prayers to Somnus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An exquisitely designed mysmaalian helmet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An exquisitely designed mysmaalian chestplate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exquisitely designed mysmaalian greaves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exquisitely designed mysmaalian sabatons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This armour seems to resonate incredible energy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This armour seems to have been corrupted beyond its original use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This armour shimmers softly in the dark&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You feel a sense of dread when looking at this corrupted armour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kura repurposed that ancient arena into a place of death and blood - Gerla NVar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mysmaal demand blood to sustain themselves, but all they had were Orcs&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mysmaal are cursed by Somnus himself, a pact from ancient days - few remember before then&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Reavers are the elite guard of the mysmaalian royalty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This armour was blessed by Methabeht for Saenheras devotion and kidness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This armour was forged in the fires of the Plane of Truth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiran Asura has brought a calamity on Solinia, we must escape - Gabriel Methon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiran Asura seeks to bring down the pantheon and so far he has been successful - Evoker Myrfire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it is settled, the Tinai shall evacuate as many as we can and await our return from Shima&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a blessing to be invited to join the Storm Callers, few have the ability - High Caller Yuta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asura! Wretched betrayer! When we return from the Under we shall see to your destruction! - Lord Erebus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save your words Taliesin, your witchcraft will never be tolerated, how many times must you end up in the cells? - King Zuriel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This armour is so unbelievably fabulous you can barely contain your squeels&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoken only in legend, the Mythical Cap of Circitor was thought to possess special powers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was later that night I heared the screams of the soldiers who had ventured into the forest - Ashoal Veredeth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the rangers watching over this camp we would be overwhelmed at nightfall - Ashoal Veredeth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the whispers from the woods, late at night that drove them completely insane - Ashoal Veredeth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the druids who had ventured into the woods was found polluting our water supply - Ashoal Veredeth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would the Mysmaal even help us? We need to get away from this place, its nothing but trouble - Rigsy the Bandit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the bandits are building a settlement to the south, we should join them - Arcanist Nlia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So dem humans and darkies wanna join us eh!? - Smasher Urg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property of Highguard Division 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ignorir, God of Fire sits atop the Burning Throne of the Plane of Fire - Archmage Xenir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A necromancer can use its powers to inflict pain on others and sustain itself - Scribe Jira&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our eyes play tricks! Who is there?! - Last words of Melaron Dutra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will escape? No, already you are feeling weak, tired and helpless - Shadowcaster Xeneran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your life is mine Harris Shakar! - Renal the Lich&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He hovered about his hounds and looked down on his victim, this was their last night and his first meal - Tales of Roan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admins need to test things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this spell it is possible to bind a lesser Gialon to ones will - Conjuror Quidish&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What use is a living army that must be fed? - Shadowmancer Faydan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power of the mind is yours to bend now, Enchanter - Coercer Milo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elements are under our control Bardil, we are Magicians now - Foragal Flamestar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His mastery over conjuration allowed him to summon weapons controlled entirely by magic - The Tales of Sir Graydan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fire! Burn! Kill them all! - Gobli Firebender&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was quite the pain to travel with, but always useful at mealtime - Bard Wealo Manthir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objects scattered along the crypt raised around the Archmage as they flung towards the ogre one by one - The Glorin Tales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the blaze, Sairin Raeborn was never the same, his face scarred and barely recognisable. Hero of the people and none could gaze at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said that non could strike him, the blades were his guardians and also him prisoner - Of the Outcast Weron Pyrmancer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They edged closer, the magician raising his hands and the magma of the volcanic crate rose and cooled, making a path for them to cross&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helmet was adorned with an essence of a God in reward to Urstin, the First of the Kings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tarchari has given us passage with the Orc bandits, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be many nights now - Roa Dusai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the men failed to find the answer in medicine, they turned to the Gods - High Priest Gunrim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spirits walk among us in another veil, in the darkest hour may they guide you - Spiritual Horan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sometimes stare into that blizard at night Manwe, and I see shapes moving in the night - Eranal Olagar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He walked, no more than a stones throw and dropped, absolutely, dead - The Seven Curses of Caleb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coldest of winters is to come and with it many horrors - Oracle Joli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked down, chanting as he would as he mixed that fatal liquid in his bowl - Tales of Winter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ranger smiled at his competitor and gave wink before dissapearing into the forest - The Rangers of Halcron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A unit by itself is strong but when led by a Paladin they are far more capable - Stratregist Jiral&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were doomed, I know it. But then he nealt and mutters some ancient words. I dont know how we made it out of there - Tsiyon Newspaper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None could stand in their way, they were on a crusade that no king nor hero could stop - The Crusades of Yamin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got passage on the Eye of the Storm to some Orc village in the Thundering Sea - Heia Mil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eye of the Storm is the ship the bandits have anchored in the south coast, we make our way tommorow - Roai Turin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cell had been unlocked in the night, by who we do not know my lord - Jailmaster Potis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Balrud is lost, we are now at the mercy of the Mysmal - Guard Hunon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must secure the north before those THINGS break through our defenses! - Guard Amruel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stand forever, united against that which brings our end - Last Days of the Silent City Watch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city shall fall and with it I shall finally rid this land of the medelling Eusebians - Corruptor Gyle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blackthorn Archers marched into the valley of Somnerog unto thier final doom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pale shadow crawls at the Silent City, soon they shall breathe no more - Arch Lich Kyrix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the 4th day since I discovered the ruins here, it seems a civilisation existed some time ago - Scholar Erian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold him down! What is he blathering about, what ruins?! Speak man! - Captain Reian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is here in the blistful towers of the Silent City that we study lost Proto Human texts - Sage Viria&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great was the honour of the Palguehealers. They tried so hard but even they fell to the Putrid death..in the worst way. ~Dorn Meardric&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mausnu came to exorcise the evil in the dredd valley but was taken by them, never to return&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Somnerog fell that night to the hordes of the cruel knight - Tales of the Silent City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halira! Wretched Banshee of the Sands! No druid are you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They cowered in the basement as the Ooze seeped in above them&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickly, to the basement! Come children!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doom! We are cursed and fallen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come, we must go, now! I have summoned a fury to avenge us! Now flee! - Arch Wizard Holira Starfire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source of his power, the visions given by non other than Yeadra the Betrayer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do you think we can change? Is there no other path, my beloved sister? The Legend of the Banshee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was enthralled, it was a love that would see her doom - Myths and Legends of The Thundering Sea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gift, from my sister for our wedding my love, x - Yeadra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ssshh, sleep now, its over - Coercer Drial&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sends your pet after a target&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actions can be forgiven, over time - Judge Moa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must concentrate if you wish to study with the Council of Four - Master Kiran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body is crippled by a mind that cannot keep itself in balance - Coercer Asdaroth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is just a wolf, what will it do? Report us to the authorities? Hiria the Thief&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Coercer can convince the mind of a mortal that they are something they are not - Coercer Harathon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This armour seems to be missing the trainee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxicost and lycan! A plague on us all! We must burn them! Notes of the Mysmaal Inquisition of 1511LD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Redscar are a legendary band of thieves scattered all over Solinia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not just poisons, but the darkness itself that will devour our enemies - Archlich Merliklar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is no natural death, it was poison! The Trial of Raezn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somnus, I beseach thee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This armour seems to resonate dark magic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many locked in our cells Taliesin, do you wish to spend the rest of your life with the likes of them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dead are risen and approaching our walls all under the command of that fallen knight and his obimination of a lover - Last Days of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted for exceptional service&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The head of a Witch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bag seems to contain pieces of a blade&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malaron, i trust you know what to do when my courier delivers this. Everyone is ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This item was awarded for exceptional service&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the seal of the Bluelight Paladins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until such time as the Book is read, we shall forever protect your secrets - Page 2, Oath of the Blue Light&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until such time as the Book is read, we shall forever protect your secrets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food Supplies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head of Joseph Mirleaf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unusually, this locket has a loose moon shaped object inside it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This backpack contains rations, a note and some warm childrens clothes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chest contains meroei food supplies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sword is adorned by the symbol of Hammerfield&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Oshira travelled most of Solinia on their campaign to conquer the Gods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The egg is warm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holding this sword fills you with overwhelming rage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undergate Specialty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Common Bar Stool&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Ilria G&amp;rsquo;Ril&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said the blood of a taxicost can be used to imbue weaponry which would damage vampires and werewolfs alike&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This coin is stamped with the seal of Undergate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meroei spread like a cancer, if we are to conquer the surface we must irradicate their nest, enslave Hammerfield&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see your name scrawled in the paperwork&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weapon seems very old and has some damage. Red glowing glyphs adorn the blade and appear to be decipherable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bow of testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mythical item was believed to have been forged during the time of the Proto Human Empire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strength, unbridled can match any magic - Xio Shun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mythical spell used by the legendary druid Circitor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a unique artifact to Solinia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a rare item from the XunShi Trading Company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special reward from an unknown person&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weapon seems very old, glowing glyphs adorn the blade and appear to be decipherable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His experimentations finally reaped a reward, making Rennegon the first Shadow Knight to reap a soul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dead walk again! I have seen it with my eyes! He is no priest, he is a terror! - Tales of the Templars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inquisition!! Run you idiots! - Last words of a Heretic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your actions are an affront to all that is holy! In the name of your god I command you to cease! - Last days of the Inquisition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is an army against us 4? We have the gods on our side! - Calif Blacktide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bandits are in collusion with the Orcs of The Thundering Sea. We are investigating the matter further - Mysmaal Informer Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taliesin came to us, speaking words of a prophecy. We naturally played along but we thought you would need to know - Vicar Garafen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mausnu has been lost, there is little we can do now, the valley is gone - Priest Urian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gate sits in the center, i am certain it will open an entry way to the Plane of Rage - Misira Valen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chestplate illuminates with the power of the Plane of Fire!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a crafting component&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forged in the Plane of Nature this Blade was once granted to Raen Flamewalker the legendary Druid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This item is made the razer of a fallen oshira&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A legendary blade used in the last days of the City of Esoron, wielded by General Drixdr of the armies of Hiran Asura&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For exceptional service&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This spell book is filled with drawnings of unusual items&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This item has been magically fused by a specialist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this infusion incantation, simply holding the ore in my hand I can infuse it into a phantasmal ingot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One part mold, four parts ingot has resulted in a success, phantasmal armour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work lifes work is a success! One part armour, one part essence, one part pure mana!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again a breakthrough - 1 part mold, 1 part wood, 2 part ingot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems swords can also be enhanced with essence, 1 part sword, 1 part essence, 1 part pure mana!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Old Links</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/old-links/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/old-links/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;2011-thread&#34;&gt;2011 Thread&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.minecraftforum.net/forums/archive/alpha/minecraft-survival-servers/1031961-1-7-3-strict-rp-noglobalchat-townssmp-nopvp?page=2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.minecraftforum.net/forums/archive/alpha/minecraft-survival-servers/1031961-1-7-3-strict-rp-noglobalchat-townssmp-nopvp?page=2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-the-website-was-minecraft-roleplay-server&#34;&gt;When the website was Minecraft Roleplay Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20120820000719/http://www.minecraftroleplayserver.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://web.archive.org/web/20120820000719/http://www.minecraftroleplayserver.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-the-website-was-solinia-online-mc&#34;&gt;When the website was Solinia Online MC&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soliniaonlinemc.wordpress.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://soliniaonlinemc.wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the website was www.soliniaonline.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20110828232655/http://www.soliniaonline.com/lore/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://web.archive.org/web/20110828232655/http://www.soliniaonline.com/lore/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;old-forum&#34;&gt;Old Forum&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://solinia.freeforums.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://solinia.freeforums.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Old NPC Lore</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/old-npc-lore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/old-npc-lore/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old NPC Lore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Old NPC Lore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MasterShu Bentui, Barashan. Do you hear the whispering of the wind? A new symphony begins in the great Kojiki and you are its rhythm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MasterShu The Kojiki is the rhythym of destiny. It guides us all. A new harmony has begun and you are but one layer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MasterShu XunShi priests study the Kojiki to determine actions that will occur in the future. When you are ready, we will begin its tale about you barashan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MasterShu A jelous god brings blood upon the forgotten temple of war, your journey begins there, Barashan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ragnot Dis crime! I make orc mad! No more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ragnot Dem stupid orc! Lose our life to wrong God! Dis must stop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ragnot Break de magics! Is only way, bring me head of dis witch! I give gud reward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erion_McBride You&amp;rsquo;re with the BlackHoods yes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erion_McBride Good, we&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for you. I have a small favour to ask, relay to Kirik we are ready to move&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erion_McBride Thanks, hurry along now, we don&amp;rsquo;t have much time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erion_McBride Then get the hell out of here - i have no need for you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirik_Blackfist What do you want? Did he send you? Are they ready?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirik_Blackfist So they&amp;rsquo;re ready to move huh? I guess its time then, take this to Berigan, he&amp;rsquo;ll know what to do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirik_Blackfist Where is berigan? Where do you think? Are you the courier or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ServantOfRarahat Death and destruction, it is the way of all things. Embrace it and our lord for your own salvation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PriestBerigan Praise Rarahat! Lord of Death and Destruction!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PriestBerigan The Book! We can begin! Rarahat your time is now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CrusaderDurendal Welcome to the Shrine of Zurvan. I am Crusader Durandel, it is my charge to guard our holiest of relics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CrusaderDurendal The Book of Destiny lays within the chamber behind me and was gifted to our order in ancient times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CrusaderDurendal The Book of Destiny contains forbidden texts that none may read until the chosen time as dictated to us by Zurvan. Here we stand, ever guarding it until the time comes that it must be used&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CrusaderDurendal Zurvan is the God of Destiny. Each BlueLight Paladin follows his teachings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CrusaderDurendal Praise Zurvan! Another Squire makes his pilgrimage to the Shrine of Destiny. You may rest your feet friend, your pilgrimage is now at an end and we welcome you to the Order as a Paladin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CrusaderDurendal Paladin Moss is on a very important mission. We have been made aware of a dangerous group known as the Black Hoods of Rarahat who are attempting to summon his dark magic. Should their plans come to fruition a new era of death shall be brought upon Solini&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur_Trian Another day another hoe! I swear to Zurvan they work me to the bone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur_Trian Oh! Another wants to listen to my tales? I have many, I was a paladin you see! Long ago, saw many things in Solinia but alas those days are gone since I lost my oath&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur_Trian Oaths all a paladin has! Without it, we mean nothing, we have to uphold the oath, its our charge you see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur_Trian An Oath? For me! You have brought me back into the fold! Please, take this! Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shiela_Appletoe Welcome to the Hammer and Nail, need a drink darlin? Or just hear for gossip?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shiela_Appletoe If i have to listen to Arthur going on and on about his time in the BlueLight I may just lose my mind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arcas_Fireblade Fine smithing, fair prices. How can i help?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayor_Erilon Another stranger in Hammerfield. Just what we need with all the trouble we&amp;rsquo;ve had recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayor_Erilon We&amp;rsquo;ve had no end of food supplies lost and now Jack&amp;rsquo;s livestock have gone missing. With no food to supply the town I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how long hammerfield can hold up. Sorry, I didn&amp;rsquo;t mean to burden you with our problems but as a mayor it&amp;rsquo;s very stressful for &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayor_Erilon Fren is looking into it, but it doesnt sound like hes having much luck. How we will make it through the winter I will never know&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayor_Erilon Are you seriously accusing me? Where is your evidence? Are you going to get this job done or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayor_Erilon Are you seriously accusing me? Where is your evidence? Are you going to get this job done or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack_Ryder Suppose you&amp;rsquo;re here to trade, good luck when we have nothing to trade but dirt and grass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fren_Brightstar Please dont bother me, I&amp;rsquo;m very busy right now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fren_Brightstar The missing supplies! So the mirfields had them huh? I shoulda known! Turned up out of the blue and always kept themselves to themselves. Well not to worry, at least you found em! Take this, it was a gift from the Mayor but what use is a sword to people &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fren_Brightstar Yes food, i&amp;rsquo;m trying to find it now please leave me alone unless you have found it yourself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fren_Brightstar You can&amp;rsquo;t surely be accusing me? I am the one looking into this investigation! What would be my motive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fren_Brightstar Are you seriously accusing me? Where is your evidence? Are you going to get this job done or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph_Mirleaf Have you seen papa?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph_Mirleaf No i mean well kind of! My sister was hungry! Papa has been missing for days and I needed to do something! I am sorry I didnt mean to make the mayor lady angry. If you help me find my papa I will give you back the food&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph_Mirleaf Last thing papa said was he had found something in the mountain, he said we&amp;rsquo;d be rich beyond our dreams but then he never came back - I hope you can find him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph_Mirleaf Oh hey! Did you find papa? Whats this a note? Oh aunty! Thank you! We will head there now, here help yourself to the food, tell the mister i&amp;rsquo;m sorry ok!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph_Mirleaf No i mean well kind of! My sister was hungry! Papa has been missing for days and I needed to do something! I am sorry I didnt mean to make the mayor lady angry. If you help me find my papa I will give you back the food&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Milly_Mirleaf Where is papa?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jango_Mirleaf I don&amp;rsquo;t know who sent you to this cursed place but you better leave before its too late&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jango_Mirleaf Damn my eyes for finding this place, I am cursed and can never return to my beloved children! What horrors I have endured in my transformation, one that I can never see befall on them. Please, you must leave this place and find their aunt and give her th&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahora_Mirleaf Hey hon! Welcome to the Bridge Inn! You after a drink or just want some place to stay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahora_Mirleaf Whats this? This looks just like&amp;hellip;. what is this inside? Oh&amp;hellip; oh no! Its happening again! The children! Quickly give them this and tell them to come to me immediately! Do not panic them, god bless them they are lucky they are still alive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahora_Mirleaf Back before we came here there was a forest, it was a peaceful place in the day, but then people started dissapearing in the night. We&amp;rsquo;d hear horrible howls and occasionally the screams of our neighbours. One by one our villagers dissapeared and when it &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GregoirAlexander Your stench infuriates my senses. Remove yourself from my presence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melaron_the_Lich The serpent hisses with the purest of rage. Harnessing its power it rips apart the realm of the Gods. You stand before a relic of history which has been claimed by lesser beings but its power sits, ever dormant, waiting for the return of she which ravages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melaron_the_Lich The appropriated realm of the Ravager has been claimed by one of Hate. The Goddess howls atop her tower of frenzy, restless she eyes further conquest to satisfy her endless lust of power. Bring me one of her children and I will bestow you with her glory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melaron_the_Lich You please the Goddess with your offerings. Bring me a weapon of compassion so we may taint it with her fury&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melaron_the_Lich Your devotion to the Ravager has not gone unnoticed. Her influence over this realm shall serve you well. Pray to her for fury, pray to her for frenzy and walk this realm with the purest of rage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farin_N&amp;rsquo;Rix Welcome to the Underfall Tavern, home to the finest music, food and blood wine this close to the surface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farin_N&amp;rsquo;Rix Sure I can get you some wine, but you&amp;rsquo;ll need to show me your coin first, 1 piece of to be exact&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farin_N&amp;rsquo;Rix Well if you don&amp;rsquo;t have any coin I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I can&amp;rsquo;t help you. We have enough people here trying to scrounge drinks from me, why don&amp;rsquo;t you go get yourself a job and then come spend that hard earned money here ok?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farin_N&amp;rsquo;Rix So you finally got around to making some money here huh? Well that&amp;rsquo;s great! Here&amp;rsquo;s your drink, hope it was worth the labour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ariala_D&amp;rsquo;Raal Oh hey handsome! You here for a song? My throat is a little dry but I&amp;rsquo;ll be starting the next song soon, hope you can be around for it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ariala_D&amp;rsquo;Raal For me? How kind, I must admit I&amp;rsquo;m rather nervous on my first night here. Father didn&amp;rsquo;t appreciate me turning my back on my studies at V&amp;rsquo;lorn for a career as a bard but I fear I could not spend one more day scouring through those boring dusty tomes. He a&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ariala_D&amp;rsquo;Raal You have a way of getting revenge? Do go on? His battle plans? I suppose I could retreave them for you, he does so hate it when his plans fall apart. It will take some sneaking around, i shall use one of my stage characters, Licil_R&amp;rsquo;Sath, meet me outside&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan_N&amp;rsquo;Var The tomes of the underdark have been studiously kept by our keepers for centuries. Here we propel our people forward by the wisdom and teachings of our forebearers. It is no doubt that the knowledge that sits within these walls is what positioned the dar&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan_N&amp;rsquo;Var There is always work to be completed. Currently I am sequested to a job that could be fulfilled by one of my servants, and seeing as you are here perhaps you could run this errand for me. Scurry along with this tome for High Priest Xeran will you and I s&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan_N&amp;rsquo;Var As much as I appreciate the efforts of the priesthood, I care little for that aged priests gratitude. My role here is to provide knowledge and for that I need no thanks. You have proven yourself a useful little rat, I will now offload some more of my bur&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HighPriestXeran Another lost misguided soul steps into the bosom of hatred. Deuzulus has brought you today, he sets you on a path to emblazon you with eternal scorn. Hatred for others protects us and empowers us. It is with this strife we have conquered The Under and sh&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HighPriestXeran Can it be? Such an archaic tome I thought had been lost! Raans service will be noted to the Priesthood, please send our gratitude. We shall implement its teaching into the doctrine immediately&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HighPriestXeran The endless work of spreading the message of Deuzulus is a task for each one of us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord_D&amp;rsquo;Raal The S&amp;rsquo;Kor fool pushes his religious agenda upon the citizens of Undergate damning the security and future of the city. His efforts must be put to an end if we do not want to fall into absolute chaos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord_D&amp;rsquo;Raal Lord S&amp;rsquo;Kor has a continuous stream of resources from the fanatical devotees that believe in his madness of discovering the birthplace of Deuzulus. If we can sow doubt into the populous about this foolhardy venture of his we can reduce his finances and tu&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord_D&amp;rsquo;Raal The artifact which mentions the origins of Deuzulus is currently locked up in his vault and guarded heavily. If the artifact were to say, disappear, he would have nothing to present to the believers at the announcement this evening. Obviously stealing fr&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord_S&amp;rsquo;Kor It is the divine will of Deuzulus that has guided us since our inception in that fetid nest of mysmaal and it is his will that will lead us forth. Abandoning the search for the birthplace of Deuzulus for some idiotic campaign to the surface will only det&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melin_R&amp;rsquo;Len The Indigo Daggers are masters of stealth, forgery and deception. Any job can be satisfied if your pockets are deep&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melin_R&amp;rsquo;Len If you are looking for a forgery please be prepared to pay a hefty cost, of course there are alternatives to payment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melin_R&amp;rsquo;Len Services for services. It so happens we have a task that may suit you, if you are discreet and can put aside your moral obligations for a moment. Does that sound like something that could interest you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melin_R&amp;rsquo;Len Good, then what is it you want to be forged specifically? Deeds, official documents, or the change of duty pages for House S&amp;rsquo;Kor? Don&amp;rsquo;t look shocked, we have people in many places. Understand this, we know that you are working for House D&amp;rsquo;Raal and it wou&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melin_R&amp;rsquo;Len Lord D&amp;rsquo;Raal is currently financing the army of Undergate and is planning an attack on one of the local surface settlements. Normally we dark elves don&amp;rsquo;t concern ourselves with the lives of lesser beings but in this case we have a specific interest the co&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melin_R&amp;rsquo;Len I shall provide you with what you need on receipt of a simple slip of paper. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;re quite capable of that yes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melin_R&amp;rsquo;Len Good, I see you are capable of manipulation and able to follow orders. I may have more work for you in the future. For now, we shall conclude our deal. This document should get you what you need&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Licil_R&amp;rsquo;Sath Oh look, a walking lump of refuse, how novel!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Licil_R&amp;rsquo;Sath Move quickly, I fear he is suspicious&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guard_N&amp;rsquo;Rot As members of the personal guard of Lord S&amp;rsquo;Kor it is our duty to protect the S&amp;rsquo;Kor dynasty and its property&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guard_N&amp;rsquo;Rot Oh? I was expecting G&amp;rsquo;Tir to relieve me and you are not him. If there has been a change of duty, then where are your change of duty pages?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guard_N&amp;rsquo;Rot So I am to personally escort Lord S&amp;rsquo;Kor on his announcement, very well. Take the relic and protect it like your own. Should anything happen to it Lord S&amp;rsquo;Kor will have you quartered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tamrin_N&amp;rsquo;Rot Welcome to the Blue Flame, we specialise in dark elven armour, weaponry and tools. Do you have something specific in mind or are you just browsing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tamrin_N&amp;rsquo;Rot It just so happens there is something I need. I have an order to fulfill that requires a particular type of reagent for imbueing a dagger. It may not be an easy task, but if you can provide me with the blood of a night creature, I can reward you with an &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tamrin_N&amp;rsquo;Rot Wonderful, and from the looks, completely uncontaminated. This should satisfy the order perfectly. Thank you for your aid, here&amp;rsquo;s your coin as promised&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Old Passives</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/old-passives/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/misc/old-passives/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old Passives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Old Passives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mysmaal (Vampire) :
- Active: Drain Life - Deals 1 damage each second over 5 seconds to the target and heals self the same amount each time damage is dealt; Range: 3 blocks to start ; Cooldown: 5 seconds ; Power: 30
- Active: Corruption - Cover the target in a blanket of darkness and confuse them (Blindness 2 + Confusion 100) for 7 seconds ; Cooldown: 25 ; Power: 15 ; Range: 7
- Passive: Unholy Flesh - Recieves a Weakness 2 status effect while in any light level above 11
- Passive: Night Prowler - Recieves a Strength 2, Speed 1 status effect when time is between 11000 - 23000 ticks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elemental (Fae / Fairy):
- Active: Elemental Calling - Immediately regain 100 power by sacrificing 4 hunger points; Cooldown: 120
- Active: Fae Wings - Player flies for up to 10 seconds (loses flight when hit) ; Cooldown: 30 ; Power: 10
- Passive: Windwalk - Permanent Speed 1 boost (20% increase speed)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinai (Light Tinai / Angel):
- Active: Winged Angel - Take flight for up to 15 seconds (does not lose flight when hit) ; Cooldown: 30 ; Power: 10
- Active: Pray - Heals the target (or self if no target) 3 hearts (6 points) ; Cooldown: 10 ; Mana: 35 ; Range: 8
- Passive: Divine Blessing - Passively regains power (10/s while in light level 12 or above)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fallen Angel (Dark Tinai / Evil Tinai)
- Active: Winged Angel - Take flight for up to 15 seconds (does not lose flight when hit) ; Cooldown: 30 ; Power: 10
- Active: Smite - Deals 5 points of damage to the target and sets them on fire for 5 seconds ; Cooldown: 15 ; Mana: 35 ; Range: 8
- Passive: Unholy Aura - Speed 1 &amp;amp; Strength 1 boost when in light level below 12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tailless (Dragon)
- Active: Dragon Breath - Deals 3 AOE damage to targets within a 60 degree arc in front ; Cooldown: 10 ; Power: 25 ; Range: 5
- Passive: Draconic Scales - Has a permanent Resistance 1 buff (20% less damage recieved)
- Passive: Draconic Strength - Has a permanent Strength 1 buff (20% more damage)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vishim (Light Elf / High Elf)
- Active: Bandage - Heals the target (or self if no target) for 3 hearts (6 pts) ; Cooldown: 15 ; Costs: 1 paper ; Range: 3
- Active: Spirit Charge - Buffs the target (or self if no target) +35 (RPchat) shield points ; Cooldown: 15 ; Mana: 25 ; Range: 8
- Passive: Compassion - Passively regains power (5/s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrupt Vishim (Dark Elf)
- Active: Scorn - Gives the target the status effects Confusion 2 and Weakness 1 for 10 seconds ; Cooldown: 30 ; Mana: 25 ; Range: 15
- Active: Drain Soul - Active casting (Requires standing still and not being hit) that steals 5 mana / second from the target (Works on Mobs and Players) for up to 5 seconds; Cooldown: 15 ; Range: 10
- Passive: Sleight of Hand - Gain a Speed 1 boost for 10 seconds each time you hit an enemy (does not stack)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undead:
- Active: Cannibalize - Bites the target dealing 8 damage to it, and healing self for 5 ; Cooldown: 30 ; Power: 50 ; Range: 3
- Passive: Rotten Flesh - Receives Slowness 2 while in water, and Weakness 1 while in light above 11. (boat does not count)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clockwork/Automata
- Active: Oil - Provides a Speed 1 boost for 10 seconds ; Cooldown: 30
- Active: Automata Vision - Toggles Night Vision on/off ; Cooldown: 5 ; Power: 15
- Passive: Metal-man - Receives Slowness 2 while in water (boat does not count)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxicost (Beastmen)
- Active: Call of the wild - Summons 2 wolves and automatically tames them for the player that summoned them ; Cooldown: 300 ; Power: 30
- Active: Bloodlust - Strength 1 + Speed 1 for 10 seconds ; Cooldown: 40 ; Power: 40
- Active: Bite - Bites the target dealing 5 damage ; Cooldown: 10 ; Power: 35 ; Range: 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wispen (Plantfolk)
- Active: Nature&amp;rsquo;s Devotion - Borrows energy from the world to gain Regeneration 2 for 10 seconds and give Regeneration 1 to all group members within a radius of 8 for 5 seconds ; Cooldown: 60 ; Power: 15
- Active: Root - Roots the target in place, rendering them unable to turn or move for 5 seconds; Cooldown: 25; Power: 25; Range: 8
- Passive: Nature&amp;rsquo;s Heritage - Passively gains power (5/s) while in light level above 7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eusbian (Halfling)
- Active: Swift Feet - Gains Speed 2 for 10 seconds ; Cooldown: 30 ; Power: 50
- Passive: Stout Roll - Takes &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; all fall damage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capripeds (Faun)
- Active: Pacify - Removes aggro from all monsters around you and gives Weakness 2 to all enemies in a 5 block radius ; Cooldown: 60 ; Power: 15
- Active: Dash - Speed 1 boost for 10 seconds ; Cooldown: 25; Power: 25
- Passive: Vegetarian - Recieve a Saturation 1 buff for 1 second every time you eat bread, apples, or mushroom stew&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gobel (Goblin)
- Active: Poisoned Touch - Poisons the target for 10 seconds ; Cooldown: 60 ; Power: 45
- Passive: Cunning Deceit - Has a 5% chance to poison a target on each hit (including arrows)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sept (Insect folk)
- Active: Sting - Charges forward 3 blocks where you aim (including if looking up) and deals 3 immediate damage to a target if the target comes within a radius of 3 blocks after casting. The target is then poisoned for 5 seconds ; Cooldown: 15 ; Power: 15
- Passive: Exoskeleton - Has a Resistance 1 buff until after being attacked three times, then it is disabled for 45 seconds;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lidkim (Lizardman)
- Active: Tailwhip - Slows (Slowness 1) the target for 5 seconds and deals 3 damage ; Cooldown: 5 seconds ; Power: 15 ; Range: 5
- Passive: Water Dash - Has 3x speed while in water
- Passive: Gills - Permanent Water Breathing spell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morannon (Dwarf)
- Active: Drinking Arm - Deals 3 damage and Confuses (Nausea/Confusion) the target for 5 seconds ; Cooldown: 5 ; Power: 35 ; Range: 3
- Active: Personal Heating - Turns 3 Gold &amp;amp; Iron ore into ingots ; Cooldown: 60 ; Power: 25
- Passive: Miner by Heart - Has a permanent haste (mining speed 2) boost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human
- Active: Bleed - Injures the target dealing 3 damage and causing them to bleed for 1 dmg per second over 3 seconds
- Active: Leap - Jumps ~1 block into the air and up to 3 blocks forward (Up/Down direction not counted) ; Cooldown: 25 ; Power: 15
- Passive: Humanity - Passively regains power (1/s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High Human
- Active: Calm - Restores 50 power over 10 seconds (5/s - cancels if hit) ; Cooldown: 45 ; Power: 15
- Active: Fireball - Manifest and throw a fireball in the direction you&amp;rsquo;re facing (does not deal block damage) ; Cooldown: 3 ; Power: 35
- Active: Leap - Jumps ~1 block into the air and up to 3 blocks forward (Up/Down direction not counted) ; Cooldown: 25 ; Power: 15
- Passive: Higher Consciousness - Passively regains power (5/s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barbarian
- Active: Slam - Lunge forward 3 blocks, dealing 5 damage, slowing (slow 1) the target for 10 seconds, and pushing them with you. ; Cooldown: 25 ; Power: 45
- Active: Warcry - Provides the user and all group members withing a radius of 10 blocks with a Strength I &amp;amp; Speed I buff for 10 seconds. ; Cooldown: 25 ; Power: 15
- Passive: Heavy Hand - Have a 10% chance to deal 2x damage with a normal weapon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half Elf
- Active: Dodge - Charge 3 blocks in the direction you&amp;rsquo;re facing (including up/down) ; Cooldown: 5 ; Power: 25
- Active: Backstep - Leaps back 3 blocks ; Cooldown: 5 ; Power: 25
- Passive: Feather-lift - Has a permanent speed 1 &amp;amp; jump 1 boost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobbit (See Eusbian)
- Active: Swift Feet - Gains Speed 2 for 10 seconds ; Cooldown: 30 ; Power: 50
- Passive: Stout Roll - Takes &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; all fall damage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gnome
- Active: Clusterrocket - shoots 3 small fireballs that have a non-block damaging 3xTNT explosion that manifest and spread out upon colliding with an object or entity ; Cooldown: 30 ; Power: 45
- Active: Creation - Create an automaton to fight for you (Summons an iron golem) ; Cooldown: 60 ; Power: 50
- Passive: Engineering - Permanent Speed 1 boost; Permanent Haste 1 boost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half Dragon
- Active: Dragon Breath - Deals 3 AOE damage to targets within a 60 degree arc in front ; Cooldown: 10 ; Power: 25 ; Range: 4
- Active: Power-Jump - Gain a Jump 2 boost for 3 seconds ; Cooldown: 18 ; Power: 25
- Passive: Draconic Strength - Has a permanent Strength 1 buff (20% more damage)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troll
- Active: Throwing Knives - Throw an arrow with the strength of a medium-charged bow ; Cooldown: 0.25 ; Costs: 1 arrow ; Power: 5
- Active: Berserk - Gain Strength 1 for 10 seconds ; Cooldown: 25 ; Power: 50 ; Costs: 4 Hunger Points
- Passive: Del&amp;rsquo;Fuego - Has a 5% chance to light targets on fire when using arrows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ogre
- Active: Stomp - Stomps the ground, dealing 5 damage and slowing (slow 2) all hostiles on ground within a radius of 5 ; Cooldown: 30 ; Power: 50
- Active: Swing - Requires charging for 2 seconds (cannot attack, but may be hit while charging. Attacking will cancel the ability), then deals 10 damage, Stuns the target (Slow 5), and knocks them 5+ blocks high and 2+ away from you ; Cooldown: 35 ; Power: 75 ; Range: 4
- Passive: Monstrous Strength - Permanent Strength 1 boost, 10% chance to knock the target 3 blocks into the air and 1 back
- Passive: Heavy - Permanent additional 10 health points; Permanent Slowness 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wood Elf
- Active: Hide - Toggles Invisibility 1 while standing still when the time is between 11000 - 23000 ticks
- Active: Ancestral Spirits: Calls on ancestral spirits, summoning friendly beasts to assist (Summons 2 permanent wolves automatically tamed to player) and gives the player Regeneration 1 for 10 seconds ; Cooldown: 300 ; Mana: 50
- Active: Healing Salve: Use your herbalist skills to make a salve that helps the target heal (Regeneration 1 on target for 10 seconds, or self if no target) ; Cooldown: 5 ; Power: 15 ; Costs: 2 leaves / saplings / flowers ; Range: 3
- Passive: Nature&amp;rsquo;s Calling - Speed 2 boost whenever near Logs, Saplings, or Plants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ratman
- Active: Escape Artist - Removes all negative buffs from self and gains speed 1 for 5 seconds ; Cooldown: 60 ; Power: 50
- Active: Leap - Jumps ~1 block into the air and up to 3 blocks forward ; Cooldown: 25 ; Power: 15
- Passive: Plague-ridden - Has a 10% chance to poison the target for 5 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orc
- Active: Rage - Strength 2 buff for 10 seconds; Cooldown: 35; Power: 35
- Active: Slash - Deals 3 damage to target plus an additional 3 damage to all targets within a 60 degree arc; Cooldown: 15 ; Power: 25 ; Range: 3
- Passive: Critical Strike - Has a 5% chance to deal 2x damage when attacking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kobold (Wolfman)
- Active: Four-legged run - [Toggle] Take on the appearance of a wolf and run on four legs with a Speed (1) boost (Players disguises as Wolf) ; Cooldown: 5
- Active: Bite - Bites the target dealing 5 damage ; Cooldown: 10 ; Power: 35 ; Range: 3
- Passive: Craving - When a weak animal or enemy is nearby, your hunger drives you faster (Mob/Monster/Player with half HP = Speed 1 boost; &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; HP = Speed 2 Boost; Boosts Increase by 1 if in Four-Legged run) ; Range: 25&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>