<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Kumari (Kandam)</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/</link><description>Recent content in Kumari (Kandam) on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Ashengate</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/ashengate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/ashengate/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashengate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A lost city&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Id-Kura</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/id-kura/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/id-kura/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Id-Kura&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Id-Kura is a legendary gate placed on the side of Mount Enlil which leads into The Under. It is told of in many creation tales that a race did pass through here to escape a coming cataclsym at the cost of the life of their ruler. It is guarded by a behemoth that demands a sacrifice for all who enter and challenge for all who leave.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Mount Enlil</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/mount-enlil/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/mount-enlil/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mount Enlil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Mentioned in many ancient tales, Mount Enlil is the largest mountain range on Solinia It is referred to in the Poem of Taliesin as the &amp;lsquo;White Mount&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Valum Vaton</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/valum-vaton/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/valum-vaton/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valum Vaton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Located in the North Western continent of Kumari, It is speculated by modern human archaologists that this site was at one time the homeland of the ancient dragons as spoken of in recovered half dragon texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High mountainous lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-resources&#34;&gt;Natural Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abundancy of minerals and metals&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Xenophon</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/xenophon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/kumari-kandam/xenophon/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenophon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Xenophon is believed to have been founded by a pre-cataclysm civilisation who&amp;rsquo;s name is since lost to the sands of time&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; The Pyramid of Xenophon&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; Wolves, the occasional undead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demographics&#34;&gt;Demographics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies at the ruins of Xenophon have left scholars certain this society was highly skilled in magic and settled in the area sometime during the Mythological age&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infrastructure&#34;&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is believed at one time that this area once housed a large shipping port but recently scholars have discovered the remains of what may be the first translocation spire on Solinia (disputed)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;assets&#34;&gt;Assets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except for the localised resources that can be found in the area this location is overwhelmed with ancient pottery, the occasional undecipherable stone tablet and many remains of a now dead society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenophon is believed to have been founded by a pre-cataclysm civilisation who&amp;rsquo;s name is since lost to the sands of time. What is certain, from tablets that have bene located at the dig site is that it was named after a Master Wizard who (possibly) conducted experiments with translocation magic. From what has been written on the subject Xenophon created a grand pyramid to channel energy found in the area and attempt to rip a portal open to another side of the planet. Modern day wizards agree this site does indeed assist in conjuring the forces necessary to leap and often bring students with them to demonstrate and train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenophon is an archeological gold mine and many scholars have demanded universal protection from all races at the location so it can be further studied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located in the north western continent of Kumari, Xenophon was originally a fertile land but these days the ruins are mostly covered in tundra following the recent departure of the most modern glacial age&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-resources&#34;&gt;Natural Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wolves often make their home in this area as do various animals&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>