<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vintage Story Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Alcor</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/</link><description>Recent content in Alcor on Vintage Story Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Eusean</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/eusean/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/eusean/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eusean&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Eusean is a mythological city mentioned in the Poem of Taliesin it is thought to predate most Eusebian cities on Alcor and may even be the original city of their namesake&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Meropis</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/meropis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/meropis/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meropis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Meropis is an ancient holy city on the land of Alcor, which is populated exclusively by Eusebian. It is opposed to the Kandam empire and is mainly concerned with maintaining nature and worship of Methabeht. This city is a place of legend and its name was used in homage to create The New Meropian Empire on Kumari&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Mysma</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/mysma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/mysma/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mysma&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Mysma is a common name used to identify capital cities of mysmaal dynasties Mysma - The Dynasty of Taon (House Vex) Mysma - The Dynasty of Alcor (House V&amp;rsquo;Mar) Mysma - The Dynasty of Angel Isles (?) Scholars have discussed the possibility of the origins of the name Mysmaal and have come to the conclusion that although the Mysmaal base their origins in Taon, it was not until the Tower of Mysma was discovered on Alcor that the race began to identify themselves as Mysmaal&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Scheria</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/scheria/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/scheria/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scheria&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Once a home to the ancient people of Eusebes and the now ruined city of Kitezh this land is mostly covered in swamps. However to the south there are relatively fertile lands among the ruins of the once great Eusebean capital. Scheria itself is now home to bandits and other swamp life as well as the various warring factions of Alcor. Also to note should be the tower of Mysma, home to the ancient vampires of this forest and the many undead that surround the tower rising high above the pit where they make their home. Strangely, far north of the Mysma can be found an area covered in complete ice where some believe is home to a white ice dragon. Most believe this is myth as many dare not tread near the tower of the vampires let alone further north.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt; Once home to the great city of Eusebes the people here eventually segmented into five tribes due to some forgotten event. Kitezh eventually rose to replace Euesebes but eventually was destroyed by the Kandam Empire. The Tower of Mysma is said to have existed here since any can remember and has always been an area of danger to any race travelling through the northern swamplands.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Transport Links&lt;/strong&gt; The northern regions are directly next to the ocean but due to the hostile undead and vampires none have managed to enter. The only real way to enter into Scheria is through the ruins of Kitezh far on the east of the continent.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; The Tower of Mysma The Undead Pit The Ruins of Eusebes The Ruins of Kitezh The Kitezhen Pyramid&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; Most creatures here are extremely dangerous and poisonous. However the greatest risk is most definately from the vampires, undead and giants to the north.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of Scheria is covered in swamp lands apart from the fertile lands to the south where lie the ruins of Eusebes. The area itself is home to two mountains, one east and one west. Each mountain provides a underground network of caves that lead to The Himapan Forest (west) and Virumaa (east).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the south lies a large lake where Eusebes and it&amp;rsquo;s farmlands once lay. All this is now ruins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flora-fauna&#34;&gt;Flora &amp;amp; Fauna&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reptiles, bog slogs, snakes, undead, vampires and some giants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-resources&#34;&gt;Natural Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many poisons and unusual plant life can be found in this area. Also a large number of reptiles and undead. Bone armour, Leather armor and the likes are common here. Some tried to recreate the once ancient farmlands far to the south but eventually failed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Himapan Forest</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/the-himapan-forest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/the-himapan-forest/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Himapan Forest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Home to a number of mythological creatures such as centaurs and rare birds. It is a place of nature and growth and some believe blessed by forgotten gods. However there are no civilisations here as such except the city of Meropis which lies to the far north.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Transport Links&lt;/strong&gt; The only means of entering and leaving this area is through a tunnel that leads directly to the swampland of Scheria. This is heavily guarded by the centaurs who take great pride in their holy land.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; The Everliving Flower The entrance to Meropis&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; All life here is relatively peaceful unless you are found to be tainting or desecrating their holy land.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt; This land and it&amp;rsquo;s inhabitants are believed to outdate even the ancient city of Euesebes. The Meropii who live here left eusebes to find a home among the positive life forces of the continent. Over time the village of Meropis grew into the gigantic white stoned citadel it is today and it dedicates itself to peace and growth and has held off many invasions from the Kandam Empire thanks to a shaky alliance with the local centaurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forest is situated deep into the mountains of Scheria and is split into 3 main areas all containing a wild variety giantatic mushrooms, trees and ancient tree roots that twist around the terrain. The land itself is smothered in lush growth and flowers aided by the many streams and waterfalls that run through the area as well as the dedicated care of the land by the local centaurs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flora-fauna&#34;&gt;Flora &amp;amp; Fauna&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many plants and flowers can be found here to make all manner of cures and perfumes although any resources taken should always have permission blessed by the local inhabitants less you anger them and their gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many wildlife including a variety of rare birds, some peaceful apes and many white horses&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Tower of Mysma</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/the-tower-of-mysma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/the-tower-of-mysma/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tower of Mysma&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Home to the vampiric Mysmaal None travel here except fool-hardy treasure hunters hoping to recover ancient artifacts. However all they will find here is undeath or something worse&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt; Not much is known about the tower or it&amp;rsquo;s people. The tower itself is certainly from before the cataclsym however it&amp;rsquo;s people may not be. Mysma acts as a breeding ground for vampires and a house for other loyal undead that act as servents to the residents which have mastered the dark arts. Mysma has been documented as being present during and long before the city of Eusebes was ruined. It is believed to have been once a religious structure that served some purpose to a long lost race but little can be confirmed without venturing deep into the infested citadel&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; The tower itself The pit of the dead&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; Significant undead and vampire presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;defences&#34;&gt;Defences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base of the tower is surrounded by undead inside a giant bone filled pit, there are no other life forms to be found here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located to the far north of the swamps of Scheria this age old tower looms over the land and is a landmark for any to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;natural-resources&#34;&gt;Natural Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Significant amount of magically unfused bone can be found in the pit that surrounds the tower.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Virumaa</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/virumaa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/alcor/virumaa/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virumaa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Apart from the small outposts of the Kandamese and the entrance to the city of Kandam itself there are no civilisations that exist in this jungle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Local Wildlife&lt;/strong&gt; Bog slugs, snakes and many dangerous reptiles.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Transport Links&lt;/strong&gt; The only methods of entrance to the jungle itself is through a cave entrance in the swamp of Scheria. Giving the Kandam empire a relatively defensive position against outsiders.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Locations of Interest&lt;/strong&gt; The Lost Temple of Araz&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Threats&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the wildlife here is extremely deadly, if you do survive the brutal attacks from one of these creatures the poisons they hold will surely get you in the long run.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt; After the fall of the city of Eusebes the Kandam tribe settled here. Being people of war and battle they found the inhospitable lands a place to focus their strength in honour of their god of war and a perfect place to train their young. In time the village of Kandam became a city and recently the fortress of the entire empire that rules the majority of Alcor with an iron fist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tropical jungle sits on the southern borders of the continent of Alcor. It rests to the south of the swamps of Scheria and is commonly associated with the Kandam Empire who&amp;rsquo;s capital is located here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flora-fauna&#34;&gt;Flora &amp;amp; Fauna&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many poisons are found within the bogs of this swamp as well as reptiles and slugs which can be used to make all manners of clothing and unusual dishes. It is also a major source of timber to the Kandam Empire.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>