<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Stories</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/</link><description>Recent content in Stories on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Another Time</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/another-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/another-time/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High Preistess Lena looked down upon her winged brothers and sisters of the faith from atop the shimmering citadel of Esoron. For centuries they had followed the teachings and ways of the God of Growth, Methabeht, and aided the world form into the wonder of nature and life that it had today. Now their entire existence was held in the hands of a rogue brother who had turned against their lord for the teachings of another. Tonight in every one of their cities of peace and growth, they would barricade their gates and prepare for their true enemy, destruction. Everything opposite to their way of life. The Tinai were powerful, indeed more powerful than any other race on the planet. But they were not for war. They had defended the elder humans in their early days but never anything like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;I fear we will not escape this one Shana&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;We must keep our faith Lena, less we follow the same path as him. Did he not promise us a place at the end of time?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;I fear that his will has been tampered by that of another. Something has changed and our destiny with it.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Then what should we do?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;That is what concerns me most sister. We must leave this planet and fast.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;We cannot abandon Solinia. It is our duty to aid her and see that the great growth continues.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;We will be of no use to anyone if we are all dead. We shall return in time my friend, when the world needs us the most.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;But Lena.&amp;rsquo;, emotion could almost be seen in Shana&amp;rsquo;s eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;When the time comes, you must take the citadel with you and leave. We shall hold him off till you are all in safety.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;And you?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;I will leave that to destiny. Growth guide you, my sister&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within moments of those words a great flash exploded over the horizon and the priestess shielded her eyes as the land began to tear itself apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Go, go now!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Death of Samuel</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/death-of-samuel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/death-of-samuel/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death of Samuel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death of Samuel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being framed numerous times, betrayed by those he trusted, those that he showed mercy to, and abandoned by those once loyal to him, Samuel died a lonely death, being deprived from those he loved and depended on him. Nothing else seems to be left of Samuel Fletcher except his tarnished honor and abridged reputation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or so he thought&amp;hellip; as the life gently faded from Samuel, the Gods convened around his corpse mourning the loss of yet another hero. As his soul faded into the maw they beckoned him to make a single wish to change solinia forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johnathon stares into the eyes of his once friend. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; He says as he drives his sword through Samuels heart. He sighs as he closes Samuels dead glazed eyes and looks around at those with him, thinking on all that lead to this point; Lies, deceit, plots, betrayal. &amp;ldquo;Elise will pay for turning you against us again old friend.&amp;rdquo; He says to himself. No longer is the royal court in danger. Samuel will not go through with destroying the royal court and waging war so that all of Solinia will be under his flag. &amp;ldquo;His greatest crime was siding with the enemy we once had together&amp;hellip; The one he wanted to kill. You will be buried surrounded by those you betrayed who still love you. You are not the man i once called friend&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m sorry things led to this point.&amp;rdquo; Johnathon gets up and picks the body of Samuel up with tears in his eyes as he nods to those around him that it is finished&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argo the Angel of Vengence points his scythe towards Jonathon - That body is sacred; I command you to release it to the Gods or suffer the wrath of the fallen pantheon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elise sits in the rafters with shadows embrace holding her close as she watches her lord be slaughtered for false information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johnathon looks down at the body of his once friend and sheds a tear. If the Gods demand it then so be it. He lifted the body over his head and beckoned towards the Gods.. &amp;lsquo;Take it&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m sorry it came to this Samuel&amp;hellip; maybe they have more righteous plans for you&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seraphim lowers his scythe and stands as a silent guardian in front of the body which begins to breathe again. The cloaked figure of Zurvan approaches from the darkness &amp;lsquo;we have taken great risks leaving our temporary sanctuary Samuel. We await your final wish before we may deliver you to the maw&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a faded sigh and last breath, &amp;lsquo;&amp;hellip;Truth&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The angel unsheaths his blade and places it over the body of Samuel &amp;lsquo;Rest now; champion&amp;rsquo; The body disintegrates into ash as a golden glow in the shape of a man is absorbed into the blade. The angel picks up the sword and resheaths it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zurvan speaks &amp;lsquo;It is done then. I trust you will see the blade is delivered&amp;rsquo;. The angel nods as Zurvan returns to the shadows.
May Echo, daughter of Samuel Fletcher and Natalie Blades know the truth&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Genesis</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/genesis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/genesis/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tale passed around regarding the creation of the world among some races of the world. Some say it is so old that no one is even sure if it is true anymore.
Part I: Echoes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halistro considers ‘It seems so easy to get lost in this universe. Step through a portal and who knows where you end up. This one took me to a begining place. A place where the ideas are spinning around you waiting to grasped and held together to form&amp;hellip;.something. But take the next step and pass the sign that says ‘Where to go from here’ and enter a world that is empty at the moment. Is it always like that? Who knows. And what is meant to happen in that place?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aataltal considers ‘Why am I even here? What is this place? Is it anything at all? I see nothing, hear nothing, smell nothing. But I feel that thers are around me, close to me – I know that I am not alone. So is this the purpose of the place? Somewhere for beings like us to exist?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aataltal Considers ‘Give us light and we will see. Give us ground and we will shape. Give us stars and we will dream.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aataltal considers ‘As I stared at the stars and dreamed of a place to call home, a brightness shone more great than anything I had seen before. With it came wind and rain which covered the earth and filled it’s body with the oceans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halistro says ‘Ah, but I am already a creature of another realm, already made and deeply intrenched in what I am.’ She giggles as she crouches atop a mountain newly formed, head tilted up to the sky, letting the rain drench her face for a moment then stares forward. ‘So it is the desire to have meaning that drives the will to create for the purpose of having meaning. I breath, I bleed, I think.. therefor I am?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And high into the sky a serpent, great and wonderous, wrapped itself around the world and began to consume itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aataltal approached the peak of the mountain, ‘This place is bound to it’s own eternity now. Our footsteps will be gone in moments but our thoughts here, in this tiny moment, will guide this universe for years to come.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–
Part II: The Weaver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darkness so sweet, soothing, wrapping itself around me like? Hmm. I don’t know&amp;hellip;soft, warm, safe..yes! safe! This means something! Another sensation stirred, drawn from the first like a gentle breeze prodding at me&amp;hellip;yearning..hunger..need&amp;hellip; And from this came other thoughts and feelings&amp;hellip; Quickly they multiplied, swirling and dancing, congealing into what quickly became a storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A raging storm that screamed and fought desperately to break free as form took shape, held it, tightening it’s grip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear grew. It pushed and pressed, a weight that was sure to crush and then falling faster and faster, the fear growing ominous and threatening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do&amp;hellip; something!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An explosion of brilliant blinding light consumed the darkness and with a heart rending cry, drew breath&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-woven&#34;&gt;The Woven&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She screamed in pain as her heart and lungs sought life. The air burned, her blood boiled in her limbs and pounded in her head, her body convulsed. Then slowly The Woven | She calmed. The storm broken, the rain falling gently around her. She stands on trembling legs. Her arms wrapped around her as her body shivers. The Woven | She gazes at the Ouroboros. “And so it begins. What has been thought can not be extinguished..only changed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intense electrical storms of the night began to settle and a bright star in the distance watched over frozen peaks as daylight broke. The storm had charged the ice and snow with a strange energy and for the first time it began to melt and trickle down to the basins below. As it met with the lake the cold charged water clashed with the tranquil and from them rose tiny wisps that floated softly among the morning air. On the edges of the lakes, where the two waters collided, tiny black spheres appeared, small at first and they moved in all directions, growing as they merged with one another. The wisps floated softly amongst the lakes of the water and from the lakes rose the blackened spheres which consumed them and created new entities of many varieties of colours. This strange dance continued on for hours as the the lakes were soon full of hundreds of shades of wonderous blue creatures. And on the edges of the shores forms of green spread over the terrain forming tall trees and flowers of all shapes and sizzes. Life, it seemed, was growing all over the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She made her way down the slope to where the land was growing lush and green. She could sense the presence of others but had seen none yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land was thriving and she laughed and danced, drinking in the life around her. She was content to let the world evolve and she soon perfected her form to fit in. Small and lithe, skin milky white, flowing flame red hair and eyes as green and lush as the land. In time she learned to make use of what the world had to offer. She wore a robe woven from soft fiberous plants. Her red hair plaited with flowers. A small knife from the ore in the ground, a staff she carved from the strong wood of a tree. She drank from the water flowing down the hill streams. Her belly was full juicy berries. She was alone, but she was happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heat of the sun woke Aataltal from his long sleep. He sat up abruptly and looked to the side of the camp to wake Halistro | Halisstra, but she and her provisions were gone. He stood up, stretched and let out a deep yawn. Rubbing his eyes he took a look around at the landscape with amazement. Where had been miles and miles of snow could now be seen bright green fauna and wild trees for miles around the feet of the mountains. He gazed in astonishment and wondered what combination of powers could have created such beauty. He paused for a moment and gathered his thoughts and searched for tracks as to where his old friend had gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Always running off without me!’ he said to himself jokingly and began to follow tracks down the mountain towards a deep lake in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he approached the edges of the forest he could hear the clattering of pots and pans in the, he pushed back the overgrowth and made it to the edge of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old druid never really slept. While Aataltal had only begun to stir, she walked down to the lake. Halisstra was curious about whoever was making all that clatter with the pots and pans and so she planted herself at the edge of the lake. Her roots sunk deeply into the soil soaking up the water seeping into the ground. Her branches spread wide, her green leaves taking in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much can be learned of others if you just watch and listen, carefully paying attention to the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small wood elf sat, munching a mouthful of dried nuts and berries. The pilfered bag discarded, the pots pans and empty containers scatered about. She perked up as she heard rustling in the brush. Sitting ever so silently, listening..and listening&amp;hellip;and listening. Finally she shrugged and swallowed what was in her mouth. She wondered if the half elf would ever reappear. It was all well and good to prance around in a newly created world but she wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to stay here forever waiting for something to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She lay in the tall grass, arms pillowing her head, her gaze towards the heavens. Slipping a hand out she raised it up and with a flick of her finger a star plummeted downward and in an instant was snuffed out. She giggled. &amp;ldquo;See how easy it is? How many years had she tried? This world will do no better. Doomed before it barely began. Why? They are unyielding that is why. Their world has become so dreary it has dulled their minds. They are trapped in that world. No visable chains or cage bars hold them. They are held captive by their own minds.&amp;rdquo; She giggled some more, turning on her side watching the leaves falling from a tree. &amp;ldquo;I can do the same to you. With just a click of my fingers&amp;rdquo; She snapped her fingers for emphasis. &amp;ldquo;Poof! You are gone.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She rolled with laughter, then rising to her feet she lifted her arms swirling about. The sky grew dark, the air arid, the grass withered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her laughing filled the world that was slowly retreating back to dust.
Part III: Responsibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whispers of a being fluttered past the ears of the weaver. &amp;lsquo;Why do you destroy?&amp;rsquo; She turned, to locate the being but was unable to see any source. &amp;lsquo;Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t every new life be given a chance to grow before meeting the the eventual hand of obliteration?&amp;rsquo;. The leaves and roots of the nearby trees gathered together and grew into a form representing a man leaning towards her with no mouth or eyes but a certain curious expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mischievious elf frowned at the being a slight hint of guilt on her face. &amp;ldquo;I was left alone. Well, alone except for the druid there.&amp;rdquo; She nodded at a tree that was withered but still standing. She frowned again. &amp;ldquo;And she&amp;rsquo;s no fun. I was bored.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then her eyes sparkled and her lips curled into a smile. &amp;ldquo;I can fix it. You&amp;rsquo;ll see.&amp;rdquo; She turned. Studying the landscape. Corpses of sea creatures had piled up on top of each other in the receeding pools of water. She waved her arms and cyclones swirled around the dead things raising them into pillars of decaying flesh and dust. Flames errupted consuming the pillars and then died. What was left was miles and miles of obsidian pillars, oddly beautiful skeletal sculptures of black glass rising out of the empty basin thousands of feet high their tops disappearing into an atmosphere thick with heavy dark clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atop the pillars particles of dust soaked in the moist air and fell. Green life spread over the surface, vines reaching out from one pillar to the next. Soon a lush jungle had spread out like a canopy over the arid basin below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She shrugged giving a mischievious grin. &amp;ldquo;There. Now what can you do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The being looked on at what she had created and it&amp;rsquo;s form returned into the forests around her. The jungle ahead of the weaver opened up and the trees shifted beckoning her towards a path that had been made deep into her new lands. The older forests around her whispered &amp;lsquo;Your children await you at your temple and they need your help.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weaver stepped through the forest as it grew and expanded around her. The time here was running at a different pace to her. The forests grew and rivers swelled and then contracted.People and creatures sped around her as a civilisations rose and fell. As she peared deeper she saw a great zigurrat being constructed, plated in a magnificent gold that reflected the light of the midday sun. Adorned atop was a great statue representing her image. The people moved in a hurry around at the basin where the temple stood and new statues, streets and structures were constructed at a rapid pace. She began the walk up the stairs of the temple and with each step time slowed down until she reached the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;How can we help the Tinai? They were the ones that released this monster in the first place!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Just because he is one of them does not make it the responsibility of the Tinai to save the world! Was it not our god that brought the very&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;idea of destruction into the world to begin with?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;How dare you assume the will of the gods!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;If we try to fight this alone we will surely fail. We must ally with the Tinai and aid them in their battle. He has torn the southern lands apart and is gaining speed every day. It will not be long before he arrives here and we follow the same fate as Izarak&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;No one has held the power of the Tinai, our abilities in combat and with the schools of magic are far inferior. How can we even begin to assist them?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;We can give them time. Time to prepare.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Our only hope is to prepare a defense and to find a place to ensure the safety of our people!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;No defense would save you against his anger - he rips the very ground from beneath civilisations and sends it to oblivion in moments!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;He is right we cannot hope to run and escape his will. Our only choice is to stand and fight, at least we would die in honour&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;I refuse to listen to your madness! My family will never walk into battle to be surely ripped apart, that is suicide! We will make for the caves, I hope for your sake our Lady will return your senses before it is too late for all of us.&amp;rsquo; The noble storms out of the temple beckoning his guards to prepare his people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Those that wish to stand and fight remain. Those that cannot stomach destiny should leave for The Under at once. &amp;lsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining nobles looked amongst each other but neither budged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Then it is settled. We will send word to the Tinai that they will have our aid. We will defend our world together and see this blight removed from existence. His power is incomparable to the will of our Lady. She will see us through this day.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Origins</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/origins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/origins/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Origins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said in the beginning there was nothing but a vast endless sea of unbroken darkness in which a god as ageless as time swam, lighting its way with vast jewel like suns. On its journey the god did stumble upon the barren landscape of a now dead star lying upon its center it did see a bright blue lake of incredible beauty glistening with astral magic of the wisps that flickered above it. Curious to the nature of this outside influence of his domain the god broke a part of itself and elevated the wisps to a pantheon of primordial entities that would watch over the world in his stead as he continued his journey through the stars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time the primordials transformed the energies of the long dead star into vast blue oceans, ever growing lush vegetation and towering mountain peaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pleased with the near perfect order and testimony to the will of their creator the gods now planned their much needed rest. To ensure the world could be watched over in their slumber they fused their being into one and formed a god of great power to watch over the world and ensure balance would always be maintained until the great day their god would return from his journey through the heavens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the watchful eye of Belshazar, God of Balance the planet waned and grew over the seasons it was during this period of tranquility the god found the need to release his own creativity that had been granted to him by his forebears and so he set about to build a planar reality along side the world where he could rest and unleash his need for his own designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this Plane of Balance he built a reality of untold creations, living thinking creatures blessed with the powers of creativity and freedom to go amongst his plane and forge unfathomable lands of aesthetic beauty. He sat often with his creations and discussed the meaning and histories of the places of his children and in return told them of a place beyond this world built by his ancestors, The Primordials&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curious as to the place beyond the veil the children did peer, the first being Eriadar the Prismatic Dragon. Setting aloft among the skies of the Plane he pierced the veil and deposited a brood of dragons deep into the largest mountains of the world of their creator. As Eriadar traveled, observing the natural beauty of the world he noticed two beings he recognised as the Outsiders from the tales of his god had once shared. Fearful he returned to the God of Balance who scorned Eriadar for his trespass beyond the veil sealing it from further interaction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observing The Outsiders the god of balance saw the Outsiders basking in the spread of greenery across the planet and they did seed it with their own. A mighty storm did surround one of the creatures and a torrent of chaos ripped its way among the land. Black orb like spheres arose from the sacred lake of the Primordials and for the first time evil had been born on the world of the gods. The second outsider gazed on in horror at his counter part and formed creatures white glowing orbs that danced among the black merging and turning them into a blurry pearlescent balls of light from each grew wild and colourful plants, fish and other seaforms fell into the lake hopping to the shores in another instant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The god of balance stared in disbelief as time ran at an incredible pace. The first outsider smiled at her power among the world, with the flick of her finger she brought a distant star from the far reaches of the cosmos and it came crashing down into the earth - the shattering rumbled across the planet devastating all that the Primordials had achieved. The dying remnants of the star swam in the space above the earth encircling the planet forming itself into two great moons that circled the world. The lands cooled and the land grew once more, the creatures formed simple wildlife and evolved into a variant of hundreds of creatures, the two outsiders seemed to be at war with one another for a time and then, in a whisper they were gone, the world changed forever more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The God of Balance returned once more to the sacred world of the Primordials and wept, the inhabitants warred among each other and vast stretches of land still bore the scars of the outsiders. In his anger he brought forth four of his greatest creations and charged them with absolute authority to purge the land of chaos and return balance once more to the lands. Taking one last look at his folly in turning his eye away from the world he returned to his plane sealing the veil forever&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Poem of Taliesin</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/poem-of-taliesin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/poem-of-taliesin/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poem of Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This poem was located in the Temple of Tranquility and is yet to be deciphered by the people of Hoakar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Poem of Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was nine full months&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the womb of Shai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before that I was Methabeht,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I am Taliesin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was with my king&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the heavens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Ferrelux fell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Into the deepest hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I carried the banner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the Rokr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know the names of the stars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the North to the South.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in Caer Bedion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenophon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I accompanied the Weaver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the soul of Ghufran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was the flaming arrow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Akakios was slain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in Llys Don&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the birth of Adelita.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was patriarch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Leonidas and Enoch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was there at the destruction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the peaceful Eusean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was the foreman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the construction of the Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was three times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the prison of Zuriel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in the citadel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Shana and Alpha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I witnessed the destruction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all of Esoron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a unswerving shield&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Oboron of Azura.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have gone hungry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the only One.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was at the White Mount&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in the court of Tarakan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In stocks and in fetters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a year and a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was instructor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the whole universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shall be until the judgement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the face of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have sat in the perilous seat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above Caer Sidi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shall continue to revolve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the three elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a marvel in the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which I cannot reveal.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Cataclysm</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-cataclysm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-cataclysm/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cataclysm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-reign-of-hiran-asura&#34;&gt;The Reign of Hiran Asura&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an old tale that has been passed on from generation to generation. Who know&amp;rsquo;s if the cataclysm ever did happen. If it did it certainly was a long time ago. Longer than any of the current races of the Solinia have been around&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an old tale that has been passed on from generation to generation. Who know&amp;rsquo;s if the cataclysm ever did happen. If it did it certainly was a long time ago. Longer than any of the current races of the Solinia have been around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;brief-overview&#34;&gt;Brief Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some races speak of a race known as the Tinai A winged biped race not unsimilar to angels. They existed before the time of the current world and were known to worship the God Methabeht, a God which no race on Solinia currently worships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legend has it that the Tinai were forced to evacuate the planet due to a cataclymsic event that resulted in the complete destruction of all life on the planet. For what reason, nobody can remember. But some speak of tales of a particular Tinai named Hiran Asura who turned against his people after he gained considerable power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tinai are believed to have existed in a magestic capital city in a continent that nobody has been able to locate. Perhaps it has long sunk or been washed away by the sands of time. Some believe that this city left the planet and entered the heavens where the Tinai still live. But maybe this is just rumour&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;read-lore&#34;&gt;Read Lore:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Genesis Storyline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-cataclysms&#34;&gt;Other Cataclysms&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some races refer to other events as catacysms such as the Destruction of Kumari and the annihalation of the Proto-Humans.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Dead Age</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-dead-age/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-dead-age/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dead Age&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Post Cataclysmic era known as the Dead Age is a period of our history that many scholars have toiled over deciphering tomes of lost civilisations, excavating ancient ruins and even communing with those that have passed beyond this world and far into the stretching Maw. Now, after a recent discovery and a chance meeting with the natives (that our people have come to name The Observers) I am finally able to share with you, my fellow scholars, some rather interesting information that may take your time away from the hard work on rebuilding our lost libraries. I hope that what has been revealed to me will bring a small light of hope to our troubled people in a world that seems to be forever against us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archmage Telra, High Kumarian Scholar of the Order of the Trident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Getae&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the cataclysm that annihilated all life on Solinia thousands of years ago, there existed a civilisation known as the Getae not unlike our own yet with a strange glowing hue about their skin. They believed that through the worship of their god Zalmoxis they were granted everliving immortality so long as they had no interaction with the beings they referred to as the Winged Ones. The Getae were a race that spent much of it’s time underground and naturally opposed all things that came from the sky and they believed their god Zalmoxis to live among them in the caverns and caves that spanned the deep earth above The Under.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to the time of the Cataclysm, and the world was being torn apart, large sections of the network of Getae homeland were ripped open revealing the terrifying landscape far above them that was the beginnings of the Cataclsym – it was here that the winged creature the Getae named Hiran Asura came before them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said that the neon blood that seeped from the Getae down into the earth during this meeting enraged Zalmoxis so much that he personally appeared before this creature and the clash of divine beings ensued far above their lands for days, tearing the land even further apart and resealing the Getae back deep into the earth. It is known that their divine being Zalmoxis did finally fall to this being and and the Getae forever lost their glow but their immortality remained. Centuries past and the land far above them calmed, and it was during this time being known as Gias did appear before them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gias told them Zalnoxis could be brought back but not by their hands. He showed them a vision of the coming together of four great elemental artifacts that could be wielded by one alone, these artifacts had the power to destroy a being known as Kali and The Weaver to others and the first artifact, a golden trident, had already begun it’s journey unknown to those around it. It is believed The Getae have since honoured Gias and departed their homelands to follow him into the Plane of Earth where they still await the hero, the destruction of Kali and the return of the diety, Zalnoxis.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The First War</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-first-war/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-first-war/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The First War&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the period of the God of Balances seclusion the elemental pantheon took to the task of restoring balance to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amurru the Deep One would rule the earthern realms and construct a mighty race of stone golems called Gialon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Savira the Enflamed would claim dominance over the flaming remains of the far most corners of the world. By taking from the dragons willingly she would create an unstoppable weapon know as Xephrit Syfyr a Purefire dragon who would lead an army of flaming elementals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kylia the Tempest would settle the endless oceans with enormous elemental titans and seafolk that would cleanse the lands with tsunamis and endless tempests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Far above the skies Aerin the Valorous would create vast floating cities from the floating remains of the dead sun that had rought the world and in it build majestic cities populated with angels known as the Valerin who would descend to the earth and bring law and peace upon those deemed fit to remain following the great cleansing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each God also created a second seal to a new realm within the planes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sindiril - The Palace of Flames&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valisi - The Realm of Valor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raelion - The Field of Storms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delgar - The Endless Depths&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the millennias that followed the Gods armies fought an endless battle with the creatures of The Outsiders. These behemoths were driven either deep into the sea or far underground where they would drift into mythological writings of the Dal and Kalderan and as The Ancients. Far below the ground and deep within the seas Raelion and Delgar entombed the Ancients so they might never break the balance again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the war the gods retreated to the north of the world and Aerins mighty cities fell to the land to form The Garden of the Gods, the pantheon bore many new Gods of Influence during this time, Methabeht being the child of Kylia and Aerin. The Valerin would find great beauty in the Dal and their children would come to be the Tinai. The Mighty Purefire Dragon Syfyrs success on the burning side of solinia saw the lands turn once again to lush green terrain where he would would settle with the fire elementals on the lands that would one day be known as Nasudana&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dal and Kalderan remained in the largest continent that had not suffered the blow caused by The Outsiders and named it Qylia after the Tempest Goddess Kylia. Here they built large majestic cities in the great forests and deep underground caverns and, one occasion communed with tinai over the will of the gods in the far lands to the north&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some years later as the violence the world had suffered began to settle areas of Qylia began to break away forming new lands. Often the Dal and Kelderan would make pilgrimage to the Garden of the Gods to seek audience with the Gods. During this period the inhabitants found the elemental pantheon silent, perhaps resting from the years of struggle that had proceeded or maybe to leave the people of this world to their own fate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was during this time that the dragons, nestled away on the content of Kumari would take the place of the gods and grant guidance to the Dal and Kelderan seeing it their duty to ensure balance in the world&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The New Leaf</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-new-leaf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-new-leaf/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Leaf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it was that the lands once again became full with the bustling of creative folks of many races. Tides rose and fell whilst winds backed and veered. Stars shone ever bright (as stars want to do) and the moons and sun of Solinia flew their majestic paths from east to west in what all were sure would be an eternal chase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fortunes of many were made and lost on the continents of Alatyr and Nuchalnuth and the Gods came for a time to watch. But even they became bored with the lands that the Jin had unwittingly seeded with the misplaced &amp;ldquo;Children of Time&amp;rdquo; as they would be know in these days of far future. Bored with the way things had coasted along so smoothly for the residents of the now temporally adjusted Solinia and seeing they were not truly in charge of the fate of things as they has wished they were the Gods left once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were the times of &amp;ldquo;The Great Convergence&amp;rdquo; and some say such a golden era was never known again. A time when all races Ancient and new would come to gather and share ideas, advance knowledge, build empires and see them fall. But no greater fall could have ever been imagined then what was about to occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow sensing an imbalance in this area the Necro-mechanical Taktevolken hoards emerged. From the bowels of the earth they had crawled into the lands that destiny had left for them only to find them already inhabited by the races from the future. The Jin did their best to fend off the scourge of undead machines but the unique anti-magic of the Taketevolkiens and their horrendously evil Queen known only as &amp;ldquo;The Darkness&amp;rdquo; was the perfect match for the here-to-fore unsurpassed Meta-magic of the Jin. The Jin and the unholyness that was the Taketevolkiens became embroiled in an inter-dimentional, cross time battle for the life of Solinia itself. Swirling itself into a massive Spellstorm it connected the time waves throughout all past and future ripples allowing the travel of bodies, minds, souls and species. Intermixing them and creating a fusion of conformity and complacency that was to be the undoing of all in the great aura of apathy it engendered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the Storm the Jin fought bravely and the Darkness held it&amp;rsquo;s ground firm. Days passed in seconds and seconds enveloped eons. Still the battle raged. Onslaught was met with entrenchment and massive bombardments fell clattering against ramparts of immovability. Slowly though the Darkness gained ground. Even though their powers were evenly matched their wills were not. For the will of Darkness was fueled by slavery to the ideal of hatred and the Jin, being the freedom loving souls they were..so akin to gods, knew this eternal entrapment was their only real means of saving Solinia. In the real world only a handful of years had passed while the Spellstorm contained the Jin in their plight but within the ravages of time saw countless eons of the slow degradation of the Jins willful mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convinced the fight was bound to be lost the great Jin general Yarket called for the re-seeding of the population of Solinia. A message was sent to the Ni-jin Bless (the Ni_Jin were Jin who had forsakes most of their godlike power in order to escape the Taketevolkien war)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ni-Jin were to bring all the means necessary for the escape of all the races of Solinia&amp;hellip; all but those who were deemed corrupted by the Darkness and the cross contamination of time and space through the Spellstorm. But even the Ni-Jin Bless could not be so cruel and so left an escape route for those who were of quick enough within the form of the Re-summonsing of the Halls of Teleran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Yarket stood on the last precipice of the battlegrounds within the Spellstorm He called upon all the powers of life and nature to aid him in resisting the final descending, enormous &amp;ldquo;Dragon of Darkness&amp;rsquo; A huge dome of unearthly goodness emerged from his chest and grew high above him and his last remaining companions shielding them from the blast of ungodly fire that threatened to engulf them all. So great was this force that all of Solinia shook in its need for her power. Silence fell upon the world and for a moment time stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equilibrium had been reached for the first time in a long long battle the balance showed even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was in this moment that the Highguard was born. In the last effort the general through all his remaining strength into the manifestation of something so pure that it could defeat the Darkness but in so doing broke all things asunder&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cracks in his shield began to form and all the Jin knew that they had lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few moments the inequities in time reversed. Now an instant inside the spellstorm was measured by several passing&amp;rsquo;s of the sun and moon out in the real world. So very few moments remained now and Yarket wept for those about to pay the final price for the jins fear&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside the Highguard waited patiently whilst the chaos unraveled within the Spellstorm and as Yarket did his best to keep his shield aloft long enough for his companions to escape the Dragon of Darkness used up much of its power too.
Explosion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The beggining of the end&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When at last the two forces touched the resulting explosion thrust Solinia out of time and space and destroyed all sentient life on and around the Islands of Alatyr and Nuchalnuth and the lands of Taon. The Jin had lost but not before depleteing the darkness to only a shadow of its former power. Not before leaving in place that which would forever guard Solinia against evil incursions again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep in a Jungle far away from the wrenching of souls from their bodies a leaf falls from a tree, wafting its way to the ground it flutters in its last pantomime of life. Poignantly displaying both sides of itself as it descends only to land upturned on the ground. Gently to rest and shelter a seed that had fallen before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All things must end&amp;rdquo; it spoke in its silent way. &amp;ldquo;But each end beckons something new to begin.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Promised Lands</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-promised-lands/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-promised-lands/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Promised Lands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The news spread quickly, but everybody already knew. Few missed the blue streak that had carved an arched path overhead from the southern horizon to the north, lighting up the night&amp;rsquo;s sky with an eerie glow that lasted almost all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;A star has fallen.&amp;rsquo; Said the messenger. &amp;lsquo;Surely it is a sign from the gods!&amp;rsquo; The High Lord of the Vishim looked down upon the human messenger with thinly veiled contempt. &amp;lsquo;The gods are rarely as cryptic. It is but a fallen star, though an unusual one at that.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the doubt of the Vishim, the word spread throughout the southern continents of Solinia. Half-truths and old myths brought back from the memories of the elders soon became common knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;That light, ya know. Th&amp;rsquo; blue arc of th&amp;rsquo; Gods.&amp;rsquo; Said the drunken Lidkim, leaning on the bar and speaking conspiratorially with the few other reptilians gathered around him. &amp;lsquo;They say it weren&amp;rsquo;t jus&amp;rsquo; a sign, it be&amp;hellip; Directions. I got some friends&amp;hellip; Well, they &amp;lsquo;eard th&amp;rsquo; news from the council of th&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;umans&amp;hellip; Some clever sod plotted out th&amp;rsquo; course th&amp;rsquo; fallin&amp;rsquo; star took. Said it leads right to th&amp;rsquo; promised lands!&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;The promised lands?&amp;rsquo; Asked a sceptical barmaid, laughing at the drunken rambling. &amp;lsquo;Aye! With streets paved with gold, an&amp;rsquo; all can live fer eternity!&amp;rsquo; He continued, not picking up on her disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following weeks, every race of the known world had an explanation for the phenomena observed that one night. By general consensus it was decided that the light that arced across the sky must&amp;rsquo;ve been a sign of some sort; it&amp;rsquo;s trajectory just too perfectly aligned with the fabled lost continent of Alatyr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where most maps were marked &amp;lsquo;here be dragons&amp;rsquo;, the Morannon general drew a rough circle. &amp;lsquo;There be dragons here already!&amp;rsquo; He laughed through his beard to the rest of his chiefs gathered around the broad stone table. His laugh echoed throughout the stone halls of their mountain home. &amp;lsquo;A continent rich in gold and ores, and it&amp;rsquo;s ours for the taking!&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;But where will be gather the resources? We&amp;rsquo;re miners, not ship-builders!&amp;rsquo; One of the stout bearded men slammed his flagon on the table, spilling ale on the map. &amp;lsquo;This is why we&amp;rsquo;re not doing it by ourselves. We&amp;rsquo;ve got our Automata, and I hear the Humans and the Lidkim have joined forces to build a ship&amp;hellip; But they need iron!&amp;rsquo; The general laughed, and the others joined in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it was that similar alliances were forged across the land in the race to build a ship that could survive the journey to the edge of the world. Resources were suddenly funnelled into the construction of the ship that would first reach the new land and claim it as their own: four ships for four alliances, each of four races. Such a time of peace has been unheard of before or since the great ship building; all wars and squabbles halted with the promise of Alatyr. The only thing that mattered was getting there first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first to finish their vessel was the races of darkness. The Mysmaal, with their Corrupt Vishim slaves, the unrelenting Gobel and fearsome Tailless dragons forged a fierce Alliance. Their workforce outranking the others by sheer numbers and dedication, they constructed a huge arc with the figurehead of a beast. No sails did this ship have, rather it was powered by the force of hundreds of individuals moving giant oars and paddles to the sounds of a beating drum. When the weather grew too rough for oars, Tailless were lashed to the ship and drove the boat forwards with the power of their wings, carting the races of darkness towards their destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to be out done, the light races were not far behind. An elegant ship with the styling of the Vishim and Tinai, with the homeliness brought about by having the Eusebians on board. With white sails unfurled, they were still never going to reach Alatyr first&amp;hellip; So they enlisted the help of the Sept. With the buzz of insect wings, the giant wasp like creatures pulled the vessel through the waves at quite a speed. Inside the great hull was their Queen, and the promise of a new home was all too tempting when the Tinai made them the offer. Working through day and night alongside the Tinai, the Sept were a huge asset to the light races hot on the heels of the dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;The power of the living is no match for our machines!&amp;rsquo; Scoffed the Human to her Morannon and Lidkim co-leaders. &amp;lsquo;Our ship is powered by coal, with Automata to tend to it! We have no need for slaves here&amp;hellip; Or giant insects.&amp;rsquo; And so, the industrial races set off in their iron clad wooden steamer, belching steam behind them they set sail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Pulled along? Powered by coal?&amp;rsquo; Laughed the goat-legged Capriped leader of the forest dwellers. &amp;lsquo;Surely, the wind is enough to power a boat. You just need bigger sails!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ship they built was long and slim, with planks of wood that fitted perfectly into the main body of the ship. Their masts were trees with huge sails of leather, cloth and twine draped out in a patchwork of colours. The whole ship felt home-grown as if the forces of nature had willed it to be&amp;hellip; Which in some cases it had. The Wispen had grown the wood themselves, offering parts of them self to aid the journey. The Taxicost&amp;hellip; Though not particularly helpful had done their best to donate what leather and resources they could. The fire Elementals promised they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t burn the ship but lend it light, and those of Air and Water were to make their journey plain sailing. The Earth Elementals were in charge of food. Last but not least, the more organised Capriped had overseen the entire thing. It really was a feat to get the carefree races of the wilderness to work together in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it was, four ships each holding representatives of four races set off for the Northern horizon; equally matched, but each with different values driving them. None of them knowing what they would find there.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Search for Qylia</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-search-for-qylia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/stories/the-search-for-qylia/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Search for Qylia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The candles of the Library of V&amp;rsquo;Lorn dance as a wind hollows it&amp;rsquo;s way through the caverns of Undergate. Raan N&amp;rsquo;Var peers in the dim light through a mysmaal relic titled &amp;lsquo;Of The Days of Defiance&amp;rsquo;. He fingers his way down a long list of lesser known historical figures tapping twice over his target. Suddenly a loud knock strikes three times on the aged wooden door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Enter&amp;rsquo;, he says, slamming the dusty book closed. &amp;lsquo;I assure you S&amp;rsquo;Kor, I have heard nothing of your missing &amp;hellip; Oh&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three masked thieves of the Indigo Daggers stand at the entry way with a bound and covered guest in tow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Very good M&amp;rsquo;Larn! I did not think you would return after my last request. Rather a shame she was taken so easily, I expected more difficulty with this one&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He walks towards the hostage, her clothes torn and blooded, her hands slowly unworking her bindings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;There is no need for that my dear. Release her, this one is chosen by the gods&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An indigo dagger removes the hood revealing a young woman. &amp;lsquo;Natalie, yes? We finally have the pleasure of having you as a guest at the Library of V&amp;rsquo;Lorn. Not a enjoyment we can often extend or have the time for these days. The world being in such the state it is&amp;hellip;.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stares at her, clearly she is infuriated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Quiet, aren&amp;rsquo;t you? Plotting your escape no doubt? I hear you are quite a difficult mouse to catch even for death itself&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan smiles and turns back towards his desk, opening up the tome once again. &amp;lsquo;I have a proposal, perhaps of mutual interest. I believe you have had, can we say, a vision?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looks upwards, thinking &amp;lsquo;No, no those are hardly the words&amp;hellip; Ah yes, You have been chosen to fulfill a holy mandate of the Gods. The Gods which feel you, Natalie, are to restore Zephyr to her rightful place in the pantheon.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Quite a task no?&amp;rsquo; he turns to look in her eyes, she returning his gaze with furiosity &amp;lsquo;One might imagine this is impossible. Particularly following your death&amp;hellip; I might also add I was rather dissapointed to hear /that/ news. But here you are, standing before me, apparently alive&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Aside from your death and resurrection we are not too unsimilar. I have been assigned a holy quest of sorts myself.&amp;rsquo; He sighs &amp;lsquo;My benefactors at the Temple of Deuzulus believe they have found the birthplace of Deuzulus. Normally I don&amp;rsquo;t usually get involved in the duties of the church but when I saw this place for myself Natalie. Well, let&amp;rsquo;s just say history and lore is my business&amp;rsquo;, he smiles and slides the book into the view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Few people have seen this book. I myself have studied it for over a decade. When it first fell in my hands I was overwhelmed by it. Fantastical tales of lands and civilisations long lost to time. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until various names appeared in the, what I can only describe as proto-mysmaalian, writing that I suddenly understood this was no work of mythology.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;And now comes my offer. Far below our feet in the miles sprawling underground kingdom my kin call the Underdark lays this birthplace my people speak of. Ruins, yes, but there lays a portal I am certain I can reactivate. Through that portal lays a time, far in the past where the Gods found their power. Together we shall return Natalie, you shall locate Zephyr and I, well, I have other objectives that I will make clear on our arrival.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;So, what do you say?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>