<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Quests</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/</link><description>Recent content in Quests on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: A Hero is Born</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/a-hero-is-born/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/a-hero-is-born/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quest is from a previous map and is no longer accessible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magrid Stoneheart says ‘Welcome’ te’the Morheim Embassy&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Magrid Stoneheart ‘Citizenship Papers’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magrid Stoneheart says &amp;lsquo;Mhm, s’all seems to check out. I&amp;rsquo;ll av’ ye filed as’a represent’d member o’the populace immediately. Welcome te’Morheim!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives a quest flag &amp;lsquo;CitizenOfMorheim&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says &amp;lsquo;This situation is a disast’r Meliar, we must address the problem with’trade routes immediately! If t’Trading Guilds [supplies] get any lower…. Oh, ay, it&amp;rsquo;s ye again! Did ye see to your citizenship, hmm?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;what supplies problem?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says &amp;lsquo;As Meliar we’just explaining, there appears to’be some commotion down in t’underground trade network. Perhaps ye could go on behalf to scout the situation, maybe see if ye could lend a [hand] on behalf of t’Civil Service?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;I will lend a hand&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says ‘The situation is being overse’n by t’Storm Guard, report to Captain Icewind and tell’im the [service] sent ye.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain Icewind says ‘Sorry, ‘am currently engaged in matters o’grave importance. I am unable to receive ye to Stormwatcher Citadel for a’tour’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘The service sent me’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain Icewind says ‘Kaza’Thul be absent on this day, th’trade networks are broken an’the city is being besieged from beneath our feet. We’must make a stand an’ push back th’intruders before the inner city is breached an’havoc spreads through Morheim. Will t’civil service make a [stand] with t’Stormguard in our hour o’need?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘The service will stand with the Stormguard!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain Icewind says ‘We’re blessed t’have ye stand beside our shields, brother! T’defeat this threat we must push back th’attacks on th’gates and find this source of incursion. Have yer’party report te Sergeant Blackhammer at the Trade Network Gates. Tell him [Icewind] sent ye.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sergeant Blackhammer says ‘Thi’is no a place for a citizen! Please move yerself back into te’city as t’Storm Guard canne guarantee yer safety’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Icewind sent me’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sergeant Blackhammer says ‘Praise to te the’Earthern Ones! We’re in dire need o’more able bodies! Our men have held th’gate but while these green skins are [organised] we shall be a’risk o’ losing all we have held so’far’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘How are they organized?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sergeant Blackhammer says ‘The’tacticians o’the Storm Citadel av’ recognised patterns o’behavior on t’strikes which are more furious an’ well timed each hour! It appears as if the’ are moving as units an’ are being led by a’leader. We’need someone brave enough te’make it into the tunnels an’ assassinate the’leaders. Bring me their scalps so we’can celebrate a minor victory in t’campaign to reclaim back our land!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives flag ‘DefenseOfTheRealm’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Sergeant Blackhammer ‘Redtooth Leader Scalp’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sergeant Blackhammer ‘Ahah! Aye these markings are unlike t’others, undoubtly a higher ranking greenskin! This should send em in disarray! Bring us’more so we can thin te’numbers even more!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives flag ‘RedtoothScalp1’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Sergeant Blackhammer ‘Redtooth Leader Scalp’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives flag ‘RedtoothScalp2’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sergeant Blackhammer ‘Ye doin Kaza’Thuls work citizen! We’can already see lesser attacks! Wi’one more it may give us te’reprieve we need te launch a counter attack!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Sergeant Blackhammer ‘Redtooth Leader Scalp’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives flag ‘RedtoothScalp3’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sergeant Blackhammer ‘Th’men already talk of ye’victory, citizen! Such bravery earns ye the respect of t’Storm Guard! Report back to th’Captain with this note, n’doubt he will also wish te reward ye for yer efforts’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives item ‘Note to Icewind’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Note to Icewind’ to ‘Captain Icewind’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain Icewind says ‘Ye are proof that t’Civil Service are more te Morheim than just a’body o’citizens. Yer ranks are those o’heroes, ready t’stand when the Keladun cry for aid. I hear t’Knights speak of ye already, perhaps one day ye will find yer place in our [order] as a’Storm Guard. Ye work is now complete and we can begin t’counter attack to seize back t’trade network. We are in t’Services debt and will increase our donation te them this season. Please return this t’Grumpa and thank him for his aid. Oh and here is a little something worthy of a hero such as ye’self’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Storm Token of Appreciation’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Storm Guard Crested Sabatons’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Storm Token of Appreciation’ to ‘Grumpa Greyforge’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says ‘I knew I could count on ye, citizen. T’Service once again is in ye debt. The Redtooth Goblins have devastated t’vital trade that powers the Keladun Kingdom. Though t’battle may not be over, yer’part will be forever written as th’day we pushed back t’green skinned menace once and fer all. I have more work for ye, hero, if ye have the time. Come seek me out, eh?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives quest flag ‘AHeroIsBorn’&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: A Life of Fortune</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/a-life-of-fortune/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/a-life-of-fortune/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quest is from a previous map and is no longer accessible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jelran Ironbeard says &amp;lsquo;Another mountain kin here to claim their fortune? Well I guess we better get to business. I am Embassador Ironbeard, it is my duty to see to all applicants for the Great City of Morheim are given suitable work in exchange for [citizenship] in the Keladun Kingdom&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;citizenship&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jelran Ironbeard says &amp;lsquo;Citizenship papers must be formally completed and handed to the Foreign Embassy at Morheim. We currently have vacancies in the Civil Services Office which is headed by Grumpa Greyforge. I suggest you take this notice of assignment to him at [Morheim]. Should he find you suitable for work he will hand you your citizenship papers which you can deliver to the Foreign Embassy to complete your application&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jelran Ironbeard says &amp;lsquo;Morheim is the grand capital of the Keladun that spans not only the highest mountain in the region but deep underground. It is a central hub of trade for Qylia, many foreigners far and wide come to visit us. The road here will lead you to Morheim but beware there have been reports of Wild Worgs roaming the roads&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives &amp;lsquo;Notice of Assignment&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says &amp;lsquo;The Civil Services office provides the necessary labour force to bolster the many guilds of Morheim in times of need. Whether that be civil defense, structural upkeep or tending to the many fields that keep our city population fed. We are a dynamic organisation maintained by the taxes of it&amp;rsquo;s citizens and a vital service to the kingdom&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Grump Greyforge &amp;lsquo;Notice of Assignment&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says &amp;lsquo;Another notice from Jelran, is there some reason you mountain kin are migrating here in such vast numbers? Well, lets not bother with the details and instead focus on how you can be of service to Morheim.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;service&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says &amp;lsquo;I have received a report from Trambl Deeppockets that some wild beasts have found their way into the farming district. Report to him and see to his aid. Should you complete the work return to me with a Token of Appreciation and I will see that your citizenship papers are completed&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives a quest flag &amp;lsquo;Beasts of Burden&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trambl Deeppockets says &amp;lsquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t talk to you right now! I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for the [Civil] Service to send aid&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m from the civil service&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trambl Deeppockets says &amp;lsquo;About damn time! We lost half our crops to those little green terrors! They came in the middle of the night and started digging up the fields! I think they are looking for something! Do something about it and bring me a head so I can stick it on a spike! That should make them think twice!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso loots &amp;lsquo;Book: The Eyes of the Tranquil&amp;rsquo; - MAJOR STORY ARC SIDE QUEST ITEM
Soandso loots &amp;lsquo;Goblin Head&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives &amp;lsquo;Goblin Head&amp;rsquo; to Trambl Deeppockets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trambl Deeppockets says &amp;lsquo;Fine work! You can tell Grumpa we&amp;rsquo;ll support the Civil Service with a higher donation this year! Here&amp;rsquo;s a Token of Appreciation for your efforts!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives &amp;lsquo;Token of Appreciation&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives &amp;lsquo;Token of Appreciation&amp;rsquo; to Grumpa Greyforge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says &amp;lsquo;Hmm, back so fast? Quite efficient for mountain kin. Lucky for you I finished up your papers, go take them over to the embassy and return when you&amp;rsquo;re ready for your next assignment. Welcome to Morheim!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Citizenship Papers
You receive Experience
You receive Shield of the Civil Service&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Faith Lost</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/faith-lost/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/faith-lost/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quest is from a previous map and is no longer accessible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sosandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says ‘Morheims Hero returns, ready to take up the mantle and do their duty. Though this time, it is neither arms nor gobel that the city needs aid but a matter of faith. I have received word from non-other than my brother Chaplain Greyforge at the Church of Kaza’Thul, tell him I sent you’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaplain Greyforge says ‘Praise, Kaza’Thul’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘grumpa sent me’
Chaplain Greyforge says ‘A blessing sent from my own dear kin, I am glad to have you hero. I have heard of your many victories on behalf of the Civil Service. It is the path that Kaza’Thul has laid out for you and now he seeks your [aid].’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What aid?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaplain Greyforge says ‘The Church of Kaza’Thul has many churches scattered around Qylia, it is our duty to spread the word of the underking. Alas, our chapel at the village near Silverlight Caverns has not been heard from in weeks and we worry that Brother Kael has suffered some unfortunate incident. He was regular with his donations and often visited for guidance in [converting] the local population to the true path’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Converting?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaplain Greyforge says ‘Yes, Brother Kael was sent to establish a Chapel to save the population from further blasphemy. They had been worshipping a false god and such heresy was tainting nearby citizens like a plague. Since his posting he has had much success and many have turned over to the true path, but recently there has been no word from him. We need someone to [investigate] the matter and return with your findings’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sosandso says ‘I will investigate the matter’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaplain Greyforge says ‘Blessings to the Earth God, please give this note to Brother Kael and may he be in good health’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Summons from the Church of Kaza’Thul’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives quest flag ‘SilverlightInvestigation’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brother Kael says ‘Flee from here! This land is tainted by black eyed gods! Kaza’Thul has forsaken these people and this wretched land!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Brother Kael ‘Summons from the Church of Kaza’Thul’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brother Kael says ‘Have the church not listened to my plees for the past fortnight! I have been requesting the Knights come to our aid since this [nightmare] began!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soando says ‘What nightmare?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brother Kael says ‘A man came through the town and carried with him a strange artefact, a cube covered with strange symbols and runes I have never seen before. He was silent and always hooded. He was around for a day or two and then dissapeared without a trace. That&amp;rsquo;s when the [terrors] came&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;What terrors?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brother Kael says &amp;lsquo;The villagers were gathered in the church for our midweek service. A storm had gathered over Silverlight and the doors were bolstered shut. It was nothing unusual for this time of year and the church had taken worst than the weather could give. It was when mass began there was a strange howling that was neither the wind nor wild wolf. Then things took a turn for the [worse]&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;How did it get worse?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brother Kael says &amp;lsquo;As lightning ripped through the skies it was then that the congregation leapt in shock as strange shadows of outlandish horrors appeared at the windows of the church as if clamouring to get inside. I beckoned the flock to trust in Kaza&amp;rsquo;Thul for he would allow no beast nor demon to enter. I spoke to them with passion the strengthening words of our Earth Lord for what seems like a whole [night] until the congregation one by one fell asleep from exhaustion. The shadows, always there, clawing at the windows.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;What happened after the night?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brother Kael says &amp;lsquo;It was daybreak when I awoke, I must have drifted asleep at the podium. The sunlight shone through the windows of the church and the shadows had passed. I looked down and the villagers looked out of the windows with relief. We had made it through the night. It was not until later that day we had realised one of our flock was [missing], taken from us in the night.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;Did any others go missing?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brother Kael says &amp;lsquo;Each night we gathered here in this church, and each night one more was taken from us. I sent for aid but received no word from Morheim. You are the first to find me here, alone with only I remaining. Perhaps I am fortunate had you come one night longer I would be gone like the rest. You must find the villagers of [silverlight] and put an end to this curse.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso recieves quest flag &amp;lsquo;TheLostFlock&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;Are you from silverlight?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calar Haraal says &amp;lsquo;A …horr….or … the blackened ones…. leaavveeee…. Nonnee can saaave usss…’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Calar Haraal the Fetid Shackle Key&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calar Haraal says ‘A trick of the eyes? Am I free or just more of its insidious nightmares? Oh how we enraged her with our [wicked] ways.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives flag ‘TheBlackenedOnes’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What wicked ways?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calar Haraal says ‘Dezaal was our goddess, our lady of Silverlight. She protected us when none other would. Now, for our sins of worship of Kaza’Thul, she turns against us. A living nightmare brought on in the night. Dragging us down [here] into the earth to forever suffer her unbearable dreams’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Why did she bring you here?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calar Haraal says ‘A punishment perhaps, we worshipped the Earth God, she drags us down here with the [myconids] to live their life for an eternity until we can redeem ourselves in her eyes’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Who are the myconids?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calar Haraal says ‘The Myconids are her living fungal priests. They roam the underground in her service, preparing the sacred [offering] so we might be closer to her. Since we began worshipping Kaza’Thul we saw them less, but I still hear them down here, creeping through the shadows’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What is the sacred offering?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calar Haraal says ‘The offering was a holy drink the priests would give us that had been prepared by the Myconids. It would give us blissful dreams and visions of our lady. Her many visions helped guide Silverlight over the centuries.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cylum says ‘The sacred grove is for none other the lady’s sporelings!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sosndso says ‘I need a sacred offering’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Requires any faction level with the myconids]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cylum says ‘Only the chosen of the Lady can receive her sacred blessing. We tend to her sanctuary endlessly in her honour. Of late this has become [difficult].’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Why has this become difficult?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cylum says ‘The undying ones desecrate the sacred grove and murder the helpless sporelings. Each day more of her temple is taken from us.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Requires friendly level faction with the myconids]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sosndso says ‘I need a sacred offering’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cylum says ‘Your continued service to the myconids recognise you as a friend to us and our lady. You may take with you an offering, may it guide you’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Offering of Dezaal’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Calar Haraal ‘Offering of Dezaal’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calar Haraal says ‘Gaahh what is this you force down my throat! More poison from her…… agghhh the visions are return…… my lady…… …. Yes…. … I [understand] now ….. I will do your bidding…….. ‘&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives flag ‘FungalDeception’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What do you understand?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calar Haraal says ‘The nightmares are not of our lady. Her sacred waters have been tainted by another and used for neferarios ends that are not clear to me right now. Seek out the well and clear the infestation. See what you can discover about it so we can end this horror.’
Soandso receives ‘Fungal Corruption’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says &amp;lsquo;Can&amp;rsquo;ye see I&amp;rsquo;m busy! Buzz off would ye!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Lirbarian Gharn ‘Fungal Corruption’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says ‘Wha is this lad? Some kind o [fungus], fetid and black – wait!! ye bring necromancy into the great halls!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What necromancy?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says ‘Not since the time of The Unspeakable has the city of Mor’Heim been tainted with death magic this powerful! Had the clergy seen you with this you would be latched to an iron maiden confessing your sins! Where did you [find] this ungodly object?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘I found it in silverlight’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says ‘Such corruption so close to the city? You must take this to the Guild Master immediately. It is vital we locate the source of such powerful magic and put an end to it. Keep this item in this protective seal at all times, should the darkness spread elsewhere we would be unable to stop it’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘A Magically Sealed Case’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tephys Starhammer says ‘You stand before the Grand Arcanist of the Halls of Algar. It is my duty to see the Legacy of Algar continues far into the future and that knowledge is shared among the population of Mor’Heim and it’s allies’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘A Magically Sealed Case’ to ‘Tephys Starhammer’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tephys Starhammer says ‘Kaza’Thul protect us. Could it be that the day Algar feared has finally arrived. The return of the [Shadow Walker]’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘what shadow walker?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tephys Starhammer says ‘His name was Shai&amp;rsquo;Din, an Aerin’Dal that brought Morheim to its knees in centuries past. His power was absolute, far greater even than Algar and he brought with him the full fury of that power on our people. Had it not been for [luck] the Keladun would be no more.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What luck?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tephys Starhammer says ‘Shai’Din was slain by a Auran Stormbreaker in an epic battle between the Storm Guard Elite and the unliving armies of Shai’Din. Necromancy has forever since been forbidden in the realms of the Aerindal and Keladun but there is one [who] may assist us in ascertaining if this corruption is a shadowy remnant of our dark past or a sinister darkness back to plague us all once more’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘who can aid us?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tephys Starhammer says ‘His name is Elzor Val’Elsir and he is a Sun Elf currently occupying the Plains of Aran. He is dangerous and calculated but the subject matter may be of interest to him. I will destroy the remnents of this object, this sample should be enough for him to diagnose’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Sample of Corruption’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elzor Val’Esir says ‘Such Arrogance to approach one of Qylia’s greatest spellcasters with no invitation! Be gone before I have you walk my halls in endless servitude as another unliving minion’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Elzor Val’Esir ‘Sample of Curruption’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elzor Val’Esir says ‘What is this? An interesting death weave, yes…. Magnificent… the crossing of the myconidian spores with plague magic. This looks like…. No, it cannot be. It is so fresh! [Where] did you find this?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘I found it in silverlight’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elzor Val’Esir says ‘Hah those fools at Tol&amp;rsquo;Rael! I knew it! You may go now, I have no further use for you. Run back to that blithering fool Tephys, his impractical handiwork is all over this amateur sample. You may tell him his fears are confirmed, Shai’Dan walks among us once more!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives flag ‘ReturnOfTheLich’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘It is confirmed, Shai’Dan walks among us’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tephys Starhammer says ‘Kaza’Thul save us all. Speak to Chaplain Greyforge at the Church of Kaza’Thul and give him this note. He will know what to do.’
Soandso receives ‘A matter of urgency’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaplain Greyforge says ‘It seems your small investigation has brought to us the gravest of news, perhaps even the darkest hour on Morheim for centuries. Your devotion to the protection of the Keladun and its peoples is a blessing of Kaza’Thul himself. I must now gather the council to discuss this cloud of doom that is gathering over us. Please take this note to our leader, Baelan Stormbreaker urgently. You have done well, my brother will be proud!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Calling Of The Priesthood’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Calling of the Priesthood’ to Exarch Baelan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exarch Baelan says ‘Hmm, what is this? Kaza’Thul be my guide! What a task you have undertaken, you are a true instrument to the Earth Lord! Take this token to the service, it will show our thanks for all you have done, brave devotee. I have little time to reward you, here, take this it is well worthy your efforts. Now may the Gods protect us for what is to come. Should the time come you wish to offer your services to the Priesthood, come see me. We would welcome you to [join] us.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Kaza’Thul Marked Token of Appreciation’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Chestplate of Baelan the Exarch’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Kaza’Thul Marked Token of Appreciation’ to Grumpa Greyforge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says ‘News travels fast among the high ranking of Mor’Heim. The news of the return of Shai’Dan has brought about a commotion among the Paladins, Priests and even now the Royalty speak your name. With the gobel at our feet and news of The Lich it seems the city is in need of our aid. Perhaps, when you are ready, you may once again come to our aid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives flag ‘Instrument of Kaza’Thul’&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Forgotten History</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/forgotten-history/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/forgotten-history/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quest is from a previous map and is no longer accessible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sosandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says ‘Forgive me for not presenting you with a welcome worthy of your presence, as you know the Civil Service is stretched thin aiding with the Gobel and Shai’Dan threats that are simultaneously plaguing Morheim. Though I am sure, in time I will find a way to honour your past deeds when all this blows over, Kaza’Thul let us hope it does. In the mean time we have a situation in the Halls of Algar that needs some urgent attention. Please speak to Feliar Harash, tell him I sent you’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arcanist Harash says ‘Quiet ye! Thi&amp;rsquo;spell takes many a&amp;rsquo;keladuns concentration!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Grumpa sent me’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arcanist Harash says ‘So, Morheim’s new hero comes once again to aid the servants of Algar? You are causing quite the stir among the guilds of our city. Are you sure my minor matter is not [below] you?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘The matter is not below me’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arcanist Harash says ‘Good… good… though you are wrong. Now, tell me, what do you know of the [Ancients]?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Who are the ancients?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arcanist Harash says ‘A shame, I thought perhaps your talents might extend to the scholarly and not just lay behind a blade but others have told me perhaps I can expect too much of people. Well, let us extend this [task] to a little lesson.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What task?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arcanist Harash says &amp;lsquo;You have no doubt seen first-hand the ever encroaching presence of the Gobel from the trade network and many tunnels that run like veins under our city. Since the Stormguard have restricted our access, despite my objections, we have been unable to continue our research in the [ruins] far below our city.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What ruins?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arcanist Harash says ‘Morheim has an ancient past that has, over the centuries, become layered upon itself and its history. Each new generation has constructed a new city more suitable of the modern Keladun. The peak of this being the area we stand in now. As the Gobel ravage through our delicately preserved history we stand to lose [artifacts] and knowledge that by right we should be held here in our libraries.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What artifacts?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arcanist Harash says ‘The list is endless, but of note is an item I have spent years searching the caves to find known as The Sceptre of Tul’Eron. Before the Gobel invasion one of our brightest, Researcher [Ealir], was sent in search of it. However, we have not heard from her in a while’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Where is Ealir’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arcanist Harash says ‘Following a discovery of hers in the archives she took a party of researchers deep into the crumbled underground of Morheim. In the interest of her safety, and recovery of the Sceptre we sent word to the Civil Service for assistance. This is where you come in, bring me the sceptre and word of her safety and the Civil Service can guarantee our donation this season’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives quest flag ‘TheLostResearcher’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso loots ‘Earlirs Notebook’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=== EALIRS NOTEBOOK TEXT ===&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=== TO BE COMPLETED ===&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haltiv Ghurbik says ‘Ugly creature! You make tasty food for the clan!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Haltiv Ghurbik to ‘Ealirs Notebook’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haltiv Ghurbik says ‘You fool! You will give away my disguise and rip me away from my single greatest discovery yet! Oh how the library would speak my name as if as worthy as Algar! I am yet to discover where they are hiding [Ghfemlyn]’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What is Ghfemlyn’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haltiv Ghurbik says ‘No you are pronouncing it wrong! It is Ghfemlyn! Have they honestly sent a neophyte to aid me? Ghfemlyn is the true name of the royal Sceptre of Tul’Eron! It is possibly the most sacred Keladun artifact in existence! These Gobel have [hidden] it somewhere and I must find it’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Where is it hidden?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haltiv Ghurbik says ‘We located the vault where Ghfemlyn was last said to have lain. Someone had broken in and we saw the whole place had been looted. Fortunately a scrap of Gobel clothing was found attached to an empty storage box which looked to be the case that once stored the Sceptre. I could be wrong but I am certain the Gobel have taken this item. Here take it, perhaps you can prove me wrong’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Scrap of Gobel Clothing’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says ‘Darlan Cavediver, Legendary explorer and Private Investigator at your service! What ancient wonders and lost treasures are you and I to find? What songs will the bards sing of our extraordinary adventures? For a small fee you can hire my outstanding abilities and your troubles, no matter how great, shall be no more!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Scrap of Gobel Clothing’ to Darlan Cavediver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says ‘A simple scrap of cloth? NO! A clue! The start of a trail that shall lead you and the Legendary Darlan Cavediver into the annuls of history! It’s taste &lt;em&gt;mmnum mmnum mmnum&lt;/em&gt;, not the usual! The smell &lt;em&gt;sniffffff&lt;/em&gt;, quite exotic! We are looking here at used cloth! But used by who or [what]?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘By a gobel’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says ‘Quite right! Quite right! You are as sharp as you are generous in your payments! But this is no ordinary scrap of clothing my dear friend. It is a Gobel cloth which was until this very day once part of clothing! Clothing which found its way to become [torn] and separated by…’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘A box’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says ‘Yes a box! I was about to say that but I thank you sir for your kind interjection! But do not fear, for this box was no ordinary box! I can deduce with but this scrap of woven cloth that it was a very extraordinary box. A box which [contained]…’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘A sceptre’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says ‘Very good! You are astute! Yes, the sceptre of course which is of great importance to you. A sceptre, if I am to understand correctly, is quite expensive and will make [finding] it nearly impossible to anyone without the skillset and tenacity of non-other than Darlan Cavediver.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘I must find it’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says ‘And so you will! And with the monthly payments for my aid being so marginal you shall hardly never notice them leaving your salary. A price that, in accordance with the worth of the Sceptre, we did but speak about before, shall seem incomparable. Yes, I shall take your dull plain gaze as a sign that you agree with all I say and shall [begin] with our wild and wondrous adventure’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘How do we begin’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says ‘Ah the heroes journey! A call to adventure! The aid of someone extraordinary (that would be me) and therefore phase number three! - The Threshold of [Transformation]! Behold before your very eyes, this moment in time shall mark the end of your old life and the start of something new! All part of my modest, packaged service to you.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Errrr, what transformation?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says ‘The great threshold is always safely guarded but it is the destiny of the adventurer to overcome it! With the [aid] of your wise and masterly companion (that would be me) you shall break through the threshold and peak into a world of Revelation! It is the sacred path of the adventurer, a story that has unfolded and shall unfold until the end of time.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘So far I have seen no aid’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says ‘It is here that my role is now to impart you with a talisman! This, billable, packaged item has been sealed by the Great Darlan Cavediver and with it, it shall guide you on your journey! Now go! The path to the threshold awaits you mighty adventurer!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Cavediver Stamped Parcel’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump Clothspinner says ‘Gah that bafoon has ruined me! He dares send me a bill! If I ever see his face again I swear I will lose my mind!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Cavediver Stamped Parcel’ to Trump Clothspinner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump Clothspinner says ‘What is this? A parcel for me? Hmm…. Let me see…. Dear Mr Clothspinner, I am sure you have received my recent bill for services…. That damn idiot! How dare he send debtors after me after the debacle he calls ‘services’!’….. please find your payment no longer necessary on diagnosis of this attached specimen…… Hmm, what is this? Some material [sample]?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Please can you look at the sample’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump Clothspinner says ‘Well it is not your usual style of weaving. The stitch direction is the reverse of most Keladun craftsmen. The style of dye itself is somewhat similar to Goblin but far less crude. Also, the material itself is brittle and dry suggesting great age. Though exceptionally rare, it is not impossible that this could be Proto [Gobel]. Hmm, yes, that could be it. Is that all you need?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What is gobel?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump Clothspinner says ‘Gobel is the designation most historians give the overarching species of creatures we call Goblins. It is believed most Goblins are descended from them. Why don’t you take this sample to Yiris Starheart, a rather skilled archaeologist that lives in a small cottage near Morheim. She spent many years studying Gobel culture before she began her retirement’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Proto Gobel Weave’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘Oh to be young and full and energy again’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Proto Gobel Weave’ to Yiris Starheart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘My my, would you look at that. Ptarmian Gobel Weaving, a regal dress no doubt. Quite a find and something I have not set my eyes on in [decades]’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Why decades?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘You may find it hard to believe but when I was much younger than I am today I spent many years dedicating my life to uncovering the lost [history] of the Keladun. Oh how I yearned to return to sifting through dirt and lost ruins but sadly my body no longer permits me’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What lost history?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘Few scholars have dedicated their lives to the Ptarmian Era. A time when Gobel and Keladun lived together in harmony. This robe piece is typical of a high ranking Keladun, possibly regal. Sadly that period ended in a [calamity] that we are unlikely to ever return to’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What calamity?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘Long before Morheim was constructed the region known as Ptarmia was shared between the Gobel and Keladun and it was customary for the power of rule to be shared between the Keladun and Gobel settlements. Each year, dignatories from both the Keladun and Gobel would meet in a ceremony of peace and hand over Tul’Eron’s [Gift] to the other, signifying the new leader of Ptarmia.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What gift?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘It is not clear exactly who Tul’Eron was, but it is believed by the few who have studied Gobel history so deeply that he was a [Kelderan] possibly one of the last.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Who were the Kelderan?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘That is a question that nearly every historian would like to discover. We know that the Keladun take their name from the Kelderan and that they existed many centuries before any of our people in Qylia. It is believed we are related through blood, perhaps we are a long lost branch of the great Kelderan Family Tree that preferred the underground and mountain lands of Qylia. Over time no doubt we evolved differently, shorter and more suited to our environments long after the Kelderan were [gone]’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Where did the Kelderan go?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘It is not known where the Kelderan went, perhaps they simply died out as more races walked the lands of Qylia. Perhaps they are still alive to this day in some far away continent that we may once again discover. What we do know is that Tul’Eron lived for a very long time and was highly respected by the Gobel and Keladun. Through the centuries his great sagely advice saw peace in Ptarmia. Perhaps, when he saw we no longer needed him he left Qylia in the hands of its people. The [Sceptre] of Tul’Eron becoming a symbol of a reason for lasting peace’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Where is the Sceptre?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘This is where the darkest times of the Keladun begin to unfold. After the departure of Tul’Eron, there was peace between the Gobel and Keladun for many generations. Each year the Sceptre would pass between the two and the ceremony would be followed by a great feast and dance in celebration of the two races. But as these tales generally seem to go, it was not to last forever and [greed] would form in the hearts of the Keladun’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What greed?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘As with any society that enjoys a lasting peace, the population grows exponentially. It came to a point during the reign of King Enlir that the largest Keladun settlement had grown to such a size it could no longer sustain it’s population. To address this problem King Enlir made a grand proposal of constructing a great city in the mountains of Qylia that could sustain a huge number of Keladun. The only obstacle was getting the Gobel to [agree].’
Soandso says ‘Did they agree?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘Though the proposed mountain had only the smallest of Gobel settlements, the mountain itself was sacred to the Gobel and they put all their efforts into convincing the Keladun to choose another location. But King Enlir was young and stubborn and being the current holder of the Sceptre of Tul’Eron demanded obedience from the Gobel. The Gobel attempted to delay the construction of the city long enough for the day the Sceptre would pass [back] to them and for a while their efforts were fruitful.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What happened when the sceptre was passed back?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘The Sceptre never did pass back. That night the Gobel met at the sacred Rings to perform the ceremony of return a band of Keladun Knights rode in and butchered the Gobel delegation thus sparking a [war] that has been raging ever since. The Sceptre forever since being in the hands of the Keladun and passed between each ruler. ’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What war?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘On news of the assassination of the delegation the Gobel launched attacks all over Ptarmia on the Keladun. But the Keladun were strong and it is thought that the Sceptre of Tul’Eron guaranteed the Keladun’s victory, which it did. The Gobel cities were raised, the mountains cleared and a new city to house the Keladun’s royalty and people was constructed. It’s remains now lay far beneath Morheim and that cursed sceptre is believed to lay down there somewhere in those crumbling halls long since forgotten. Maybe one day someone will [find] it’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘I will find the Sceptre of Tul’Eron’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘Many have died traversing the lost cities that lay below Morheim. It is believed that the first of House Stormhammer to be crowned King had the Staff sealed away in an ancient vault and died trying his best to make peace with the Gobel, to which he had no success. Some believe King Stormhammer still roams the Valley of the Kings moaning in regret over his [failures].’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What failures?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘He made many attempts to make contact with the Gobel but they had become a viscious and bitter people with few resources and constant fear of attack from Keladun. Due to this they naturally became a people of the underground, led only by the strong and brutal. Their settlements devoid of culture and eventually practicing the study of shamanism and some even the darker gods. I believe the Gobel will never find a way to make peace with the Keladun and we will carry this [burden] as a people until the end times’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What debt?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart says ‘It is no wonder the Keladun keep few records of those days that we fell from grace. Perhaps it is a burden too great for a collective people to bear. So most historians speak little of those times and some even try to erase that part of our history in favour of one that is more compatible to what we believe we are as a people. Alas, history is set in stone to those that will search for it and prove the textbooks wrong. Well dear child, thank you for this. You have rekindled an old ladies memories of the past, but I am not the young woman I once was and must now rest.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yiris Starheart gives Soandso ‘The Ptarmian Era – Truth or Fiction?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghostly Apparation says ‘OooOoOooOooo OoOo oOooOooooo’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Ghostly Apparition ‘The Ptarmian Era – Truth or Fiction’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghostly Apparition says &amp;lsquo;Marred is the past of a people who would judge themselves born of equal strength and compassion. My rule over a Kingdom is one of regret that I did not do what was [right]&amp;lsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘What would be right?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghostly Apparition says ‘The return of the Sceptre to it’s rightful owners, the Gobel. Had I forseen such a simple gesture when I was alive oh how I would have handed over The Crown for a chance to redeem my people. Now the Sceptre is held by those who would use it to sink us deeper into [chaos] than see us reclaim our sordid past and move forward with honour’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Who would sink us into chaos?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghostly Apparition says ‘The [Caerthian] Empire slithers across Qylia, its actions positioning us into assured doom. They have taken the Staff in secret and attempt to use its power to unleash havoc on Morheim and my descendants’
Soandso says ‘Which Caerthian?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghostly Apparition says ‘Servants of the wretched Tol’Rael [hide] deep within Morheim with the Sceptre of Tul’Eron, they hope to draw the Gobel deep into Morheim and overwhelm its forces. An effort that will surely fail and result in even more death for the forgotten allies of the Keladun. You must put an end to this diabolic plot and [reclaim] the Sceptre of Tol’Rael so peace can reign over Old Ptarmia once more’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Where are they hiding’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghostly Apparition says ‘Deep within the sewers there lays the hidden Caerthian corruptors. You must take this item and banish them from the Kingdom and end this terrible war’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Ethereal Amulet of Seeing’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saondso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grimi Ironheart says ‘Ghosts and apparations! I can hear them moving in the shadows!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Grimi Ironheart ‘Ethereal Amulet of Seeing’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Caerthian Corruptor Spawns]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso loots ‘The Sceptre of Tul’Eron’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘The Sceptre of Tul’Eron’ to Arcanist Harash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Fear not my icy touch, a spell which has had… unfortunate side effects… plagues me. So, you return The Fabled Gift of Tul’Eron back into the hands of the Keladun once more? Yes, you have done far greater than I have imagined, and learned more than you probably have wished, yes? The Halls of Algar are in your debt, you can assure the Civil Service shall receive more than our usual donation this season. Perhaps one day, should you find yourself willing – you may wish to [join] our order as a permanent member. Now, let me see….. yes….the crown of the sceptre is detachable. Astounding! The legend of the Jewel of Ra’Ael was true! Here, a reward for your efforts, now I have a matter to deal with which is of great importance.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Lorekeepers Appreciation Token’
Soandso receives ‘Ghfemlyn’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Lorekeepers Appreciation Token’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says ‘The Civil Service’s great champion returns once again with a victory for the people of Morheim! I have been requested by the Royalty of Morheim to arrange a meeting between yourself and the Prince. But we have another matter which may need dealing with before then. Return to me when you are ready’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives questflag ‘Bearer of the Staff’&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Kaluden Knights</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/kaluden-knights/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/kaluden-knights/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quest is from a previous map and is no longer accessible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso says &amp;ldquo;Hello&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyndra Oakenhaf (Female Dwaven Knights Guild Master)t says &amp;ldquo;Welcome ye who would heft the [weight] of the oath! I wonder if yer girth be enough to support it though!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso says &amp;ldquo;What weight?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyndra Oakenhaft says &amp;ldquo;To Swear an [oath] beneath the Axe of Grombdyr is no light thing young sapling. Many have tried to stay close to its precepts but few have the will to honour them fully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso says &amp;ldquo;What is this oath?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyndra Oakenhaft says &amp;ldquo; The Oath of a Keludan Knight is sword beneath this great Axe of Grombdyr by all those who are dedicated to following the path of the valour laid out in its [exact wording]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso says &amp;ldquo;What is its exact wording?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyndra Oakenhaft says &amp;ldquo;Listen close young sapling for the words have a power to bind thee to our house in a way that is not easily undone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[I choose the code of Grombdyr as my own. I hearby swear this oath to Valour:
I shall speak only truth
I shall use my weapons to defend the helpless
I shall use my might to uphold the weak
My heart knows only virtue
My wrath will undo the wicked]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso says [above oath]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso receives Questflag : Squire [RECIEVES CLASS KNIGHT]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyndra Oakenhaft says “Now go young squire, fetch me the Heart of a Gobel Preist”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso gives Gobel Preist Heart to Gwyndra Oakenhaft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyndra Oakenhaft says “Truly thy heart knows only virtue! Go forth once more noble squire and fetch me the blade of a Gobel warrior”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso receives Questflag :warrior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Gwyndra Oakenhaft a Gobel Blade&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyndra Oakenhaft says “Truly thy wrath undoes the wicked! Go forth once more noble squire and fetch me the loadstone from the depth of the Gobel Eard!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso receives Questflag : KNIGHT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Gwyndra Oakenhaft a loadstone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyndra Oakenhaft says “Truly thow hast the strength to uphold the code! |Go ye now and free the Lord Heun Ironstrike from the Gobel dungeons and learn the truth that our oath conveys to all”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso receives Questflag : Knight Errant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso says &amp;ldquo;Hello&amp;rdquo; to Heun Heun says &amp;ldquo;One word to all who question our creed. [Honour]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso says “Honour” to Gwyndra Oakenhaft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyndra Oakenhaft says “Truly you have what it takes! Seek Lord Heon ronstrike once again”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soanso receives Questflag : Knight of the Code&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Tangled Web</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/the-tangled-web/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/the-tangled-web/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quest is from a previous map and is no longer accessible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grumpa Greyforge says ‘A meeting with the royalty is a delicate matter with many procedures that we must follow. Due to this, I am not yet ready to send you to the Prince at this time. However, while I deal with all the tasks necessary for such a meeting, I’d like to you to visit the Trading Guild in the outer district as they have requested assistance of the Service. Tell them, as always, I sent you’’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trademaster Ilona says ‘Welcome to the Trading Guild HeadQuarters, I am Lady Ilona, Trademaster of Morheim. We run a tight schedule and have many topics to discuss today so if you forgive my impatience, is there anything specific you need?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Grumpa sent me’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trademaster Ilona says ‘Oh good, you must be from the service. We have a matter that has been troubling of late, it seems we have seen an increasing rise of contraband flowing into the city as well as shopkeepers reporting goods disappearing from their shops during the shadow of night. We’d like you to investigate the matter and report back your findings. I would recommend you start at Kelgors Arms’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Permit of Investigation – Trading Guild’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘Hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kelgor Deephammer says ‘Welcome to Kelgors Arms, the finest steel weaponry and armour in all of Qylia’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Kelgor Deephammer’ ‘Permit of Invesitgation’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kelgor Deephammer says ‘Oh so you’re here to look into the matter of missing arms eh? Well I’m not sure what you want to know. All I can say is everytime I take inventory, I’m down a blade here, a shield there. The shops locked up [secure] on an evening and I may be old but i’ve always had well kept inventory records. Lord knows I’d like my license to sell if I didn’t’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘How secure is your shop?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kelgor Deephammer says ‘My shops as secure as the Vaults o’ Morheim. Have a look around if you like, I’m sure you’ll find it’s all in order’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[If the player returns in the night time, an aggro npc will spawn near a grate in the basement he drops an instruction]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;== HOODS NOTE ==
Get what we asked for and drop them off in the JC, don’t screw this up you know what will happen
== END HOODS NOTE ==&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Hoods Note’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frei Rockbreaker says ‘Welcome’t The Jewled Crown, finest bar you’lfind this side o’Qylia. What’s your poison?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Hoods Note’ to Frei Rockbreaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frei Rockbreaker says ‘Errr this doesn’t look like it’s for me, perhaps you better as our boss about it, he’s upstairs’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Hoods Note’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hello’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiero Oakhaft says ‘Welcome t’the Jeweled Crown! What cannae get ya?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives ‘Hoods Note’ to Tiero Oakhaft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiero Oakhaft says ‘Look kid, I dunno where you got this but you just got yourself involved in the kind of business that you can’t walk away from….’&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Tranquil Road</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/the-tranquil-road/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/the-tranquil-road/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quest is from a previous map and is no longer accessible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says &amp;lsquo;Can&amp;rsquo;ye see I&amp;rsquo;m busy! Buzz off would ye!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives &amp;lsquo;Book: The Eyes of the Tranquil&amp;rsquo; to Librarian Gharn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says &amp;lsquo;Ohhh! What have we &amp;lsquo;ere? A book on the Tranquil an&amp;rsquo;in pristine condition! Sealed wi&amp;rsquo; ethereal magic too! Quite an artifact! Where did ye find this? Ne matter, we must unlock its [secrets]!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives quest flag &amp;lsquo;TheTranquilRoad&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says &amp;lsquo;Ages long passed as&amp;rsquo;it been since any&amp;rsquo;av walked The Tranquil Road. A pilgrimage taken by our ancestors, t&amp;rsquo;Kelderan. Many have sought the knowledge an&amp;rsquo; few are the pages that fill this library. This book is a treasure. If only we were able t&amp;rsquo;[open] it.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;How can i open it?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says &amp;lsquo;Well, &amp;lsquo;only one I know who may aid ye but his&amp;rsquo; is out on a delicate matter for t&amp;rsquo;Lorekeepers, Id recommend ye&amp;rsquo; seek him out but Elder Yrmir&amp;rsquo;s [mission] wa&amp;rsquo; dangerous&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;What was his mission&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says &amp;lsquo;Those a&amp;rsquo;details for t&amp;rsquo;Lorekeepers alone. I canne share much more with ye on that other than he had some dealins with t&amp;rsquo;goblins. Maybe ye might have luck down in Grimrock pass&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives &amp;lsquo;A Sealed Note to the Elder&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elder Yrmir says &amp;lsquo;Elp me! The green beasts have me&amp;rsquo; shackled!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives shackle key to Elder Yrmir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elder Yrmir says &amp;lsquo;Thank ye kindly and not too soon either! Them goblins were ready to boil me up fe&amp;rsquo; tonights supper&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives &amp;lsquo;A Sealed Note to the Elder&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elder Yrmir says &amp;lsquo;Kaza&amp;rsquo;Thul&amp;rsquo;s pick! A tome o&amp;rsquo;the Kelderan! Ye&amp;rsquo;ll need a [Felgeran] Chant te&amp;rsquo; unclasp bound magic like that. Gharn should be able to help ye&amp;rsquo;. Now ye should go before these green skinned beasts return!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says to Librarian Gharn &amp;lsquo;I need a recipe for Felgeran Chant&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says &amp;lsquo;Ye better be jokin&amp;rsquo; me lad. That damn book &amp;lsquo;been missin fe&amp;rsquo; weeks. Tha&amp;rsquo; thief [Gril] Deepforge, calls &amp;lsquo;imself a Lord but steals from t&amp;rsquo;library to save a few gold coin! Ye&amp;rsquo;ll have to get Enchanted Infusions IV back from &amp;lsquo;im before we can get ye t&amp;rsquo;ingredients&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives &amp;lsquo;Note: Overdue Property&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant Ghmir says &amp;lsquo;Welcome, what business do you have with the Deepforge Estate?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;I seek Gril Deepforge&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant Ghmir says &amp;lsquo;Master Deepforge is currently occupied and not seeing guests. May I be able to assist you in any matters that do not [insist] in his person?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;I insist&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant Ghmir says &amp;lsquo;Unfortunately Master Deepforge is overseeing an excavation in the Valley of Kings otherwise he would take audience with you. His [work] takes him many places and he is not always available. Perhaps you should wait for his return&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant Ghmir says &amp;lsquo;I am not at liberty to discuss Master Deepforge&amp;rsquo;s interests, I am merely a humble assistant. Is there anything else you need?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gril Deepforge says &amp;lsquo;Go away! This ground is very delicate and you may distrupt it!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives &amp;lsquo;Note: Overdue Property&amp;rsquo; to Gril Deepforge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gril Deepforge says &amp;lsquo;That blasted scribe never leaves me be for a moment! Can&amp;rsquo;t they see i&amp;rsquo;m on the verge of a breakthrough! I have not done with book and nor do I intend to return it any time soon!&amp;rsquo;
Soandso receives quest flag &amp;lsquo;SacredGround&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan Stormbreaker says ‘By now Gril, you’re just holding onto it to spite the Lorekeepers. Hand it over, we have no further use for it’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso says ‘hand it over’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gril Deepforge says ‘Blah, fine take it’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Enchanted Infusions IV’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says ‘I dunne believe it! Ye finally managed to prize the’tome out of his hands. That has bin’ a hole standing too long on t’shelves of the Library. Now, let us see what we need. Ahh.. yes.. here we are.
Alright, shouldn’t be too difficult. First we’ll need t’bones o’ an earthly creature. A worg should de it’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Librarian Gharn ‘Worg Bones’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says ‘Good! Just what we need, now then lets see.. Liquid touched by the Dead. Mmm, there’be a swamp ne so far from here that was the site of an ancient battle, tis swarmin’wi undead. Perhaps ye should try there, eh?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Librarian Gharn ‘A Fetid Waterbottle’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn says ‘Ah I could smell ye from a mile away, what’eh slimy relic. Ne’er mind, should de for what we need. Right lets see, ahh… hmm.. this should be a difficult one. T’Eyes of a Beholder. Such a creature is but a myth, perhaps this book’be o use to ye’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘Legendary Creatures of Qylia’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso gives Librarian Gharn ‘Eyes of the Beholder’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Librarian Gharn ‘Can it be? Such a legend we’true? Ye really have walked’t’Path of t’Kelderan! Well lets ne’wait any time longer eh? I’ll start t’chant now. Kelra Suvo Axtir! Rato Guergo Fratis! There we are! I must be honest wi’ye, I canne wait to see what lays inside, but perhaps ye should be’tfirst te open it, after all ye did’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soandso receives ‘The Mythical Tome of Xran’Vul’&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Utra - Golden Path</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/utra-golden-path/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/utra-golden-path/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utra - Golden Path&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;through-the-mine&#34;&gt;Through the Mine&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended Level 2-9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say hail AYGAR_LOTHIS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AYGAR_LOTHIS says &amp;lsquo;Heavens te Kaza&amp;rsquo;Thul, another bloody survivor! Are ye ok mate? You should go rest up, get some food and speak te&amp;rsquo; ranthar, he seems te be helping run te&amp;rsquo; camp till we find t&amp;rsquo;other leaders. If te&amp;rsquo;y survived&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say hail Ranthar_Elrin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranthar_Elrin syas &amp;lsquo;I amanged to scout my way up the mountains, looks to be goblin activity so be careful. I saw what looked like an old abandoned mine up there but we have our hands full trying to find survivors. Maybe you could go up there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;what mine?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranthar_Elrin says &amp;lsquo;Head up to the top part of our camp, you will see a trail leading to a broken through hole in the side of the mountain. It looks like there was mining activity there. Be careful, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell what&amp;rsquo;s inside&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You kill Ice Goblin and loot Ice Goblin Head&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Ranthar the Ice Goblin Head&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranthar_Elrin says So you scouted the tunnel and found goblins? Much as I thought, we will attempt to gather some men and clear out a path to the other side of the mountain. When you are rested, i&amp;rsquo;d like you to also scout the land beyond&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what land beyond&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranthar_Elrin says We sent one of our best climbers over the mountain, her name is Ayla. We havent heard back from her and I fear she may have got into some trouble on the other side. Travel back through the mines and find her&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Hail Baroness_Ayla&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baroness_Ayla says Those bastard crows jumped me from above! The forest is teeming with them! You should speak to my friend here, he may be of some help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say hail Jadeclaw Aski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jadeclaw Aski says Those bastard crows jumped me from above! The forest is teeming with them! You should speak to my friend here, he may be of some help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what is ezro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jadeclaw Aski says I saw Ayla descending the mountain and went to investigate. She told me many things about your people. Ezro is a village of my kind deep in the forest, If you head there and speak to our Elders they may be able to help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say how can i head there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jadeclaw Aski says There is a path, not far from here that leads to the city, it lays in the center of the forest along freshwater lakes. Stick to the paths, you will not miss it. Find the leaders and tell them I sent you..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say hail Elite Guard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elite Guard says The Elders are currently in session. None may enter unless the matter is absolutely dire. Please see Overseer Juco in their stead, you can find him in the building on the mound to the south of here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say hail Assistant Pslow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant Pslow says Welcome to Ezro, if you wish to speak to the Overseer then you can find him upstairs, but please be careful he has a bit of a temper at present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say hail Overseer Juco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseer Juco says Those bafoons dont understand what it takes to run a modern anushi settlement in a territory like this! They growl on about tradition, the spirits and how we must be one with the land as I have to deal with the day-to-day business of keeping a populous fed, infrastructure and security - Then they have the gaul to exclude me from the weekly sessions! How dare they! I mean really!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what issue with security&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseer Juco says We are surrounded by Kenku, Myconids and Undead - our only allies are the bullywugs, if you can call them that! They seem more interested in trading than helping us defend ourselves. My best scout, Aski has been missing for over two days and I have no idea what has been rousing in the forgotten ruins to the north. Something is spooking the Kenku and their attacks are increasing, unless we find out why more undead have been heading south of late we may be overwhelmed in the middle of the night&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;something-stirs&#34;&gt;Something Stirs&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended Level 7-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Aski sent me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseer Juco says So that is some good news at least. So there are more of you in the south east? Perhaps this can be a blessing to us at such a time. Reinforcements from Tanqara will take weeks to arrive and if the Kenku attacks do keep hitting us as strong as they have been we will need good allies besides the bullywug. Help me out, will you? Investigate those ruins to the North and see if you can find out what is causing the undead to stir. I will see what I can do to get you a meeting with the Elders, perhaps we can help your survivors and you can help us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive quest Something Stirs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Overseer Juco The_Head_of_Lord_Hezic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodness! Goblins this far north of the dragonspine? But for what purpose and why now? With Necromancer now dead we will send up a small unit to clean up the risen and put them back in the ground where they belong. Now while you were gone I had a chance to speak to Aski and your friend Ayla who both confirmed what you said. Due to this, I spoke with the council and they all agreed to despatch supplies to your fellow survivors. Now, they wish to speak to you so please speak to one of the guards outside and tell them you have been sent for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say I have been sent for to Elite Guard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elite Guard says The elders have been expecting you, please go in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Hail to Ezro Elder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezro Elder says We have heared a great many things about yourself and your friends who washed ashore south of us. We are hoping we can ask just one more thing of you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had we not been in session we would have greeted you personally when you first arrived at Ezro. Sadly we have had a particular situation occur that must be kept between ourselves. As you may know Ezro is a small outpost of Tanqara which is ruled by the great Crusader King. His son arrived here not a fortnight ago before riding off into the Jungle with his personal guards. We fear he has been kidnapped by the Kenku of Zerzura. We implore you to aid us once more and bring back the Prince before the royal family get wind of what has happened here. You may find this a challenge, please take this, hopefully it can be something of help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Blazing Shield of the Elder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zerzura is at -2794 71 -475&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You kill Archlich Karak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loot Perfectionism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loot Arch_Karaks_Head&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give the book Perfectionism to the Elder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh no this cannot be! This is terrible news! Agghh, the prince&amp;hellip;. He was so young&amp;hellip;. one day may have even been King! The royal family will tear Ezro apart for this! I cannot explain how bad this will be for us - please at least find the Head of the monster that did this, deliver it and this terrible news to the Tanqara Guard Captain. The elders must now meet and discuss how we will proceed, we must mourn, we must find a way to repay the family for our failure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Hail Guard_Captain [-2164, 52, -2166]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guard_Captain says &amp;lsquo;As captain of the guard it is my responsibility to ensure all of the city is safe. This includes ensuring each officer is trained by the warriors guild known as the Jadeclaws&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Arch_Karaks_Head to Guard_Captain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guard_Captain says &amp;lsquo;So it is true then, the Prince is dead. I am not looking forward to relaying this message to the Queen but I cant say I hadn&amp;rsquo;t warned her that her son was wreckless heading into those forests. Not that it will be any comfort to her now. No, I guess then we must take the time to mourn and be thankful there is still more to the Kings litter. Thank you for bringing the head of this monstrocity, we could use more people like you in the field. If you are ever looking for work, seek out Scout Ashenrar in the east of here, he will need your help&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say HAIL Scout_Ashenrar [-1959 29 -1956]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scout_Ashenrar says &amp;lsquo;Sssh, quiet I think I can hear something&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what something?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scout_Ashenrar says &amp;lsquo;Orcs I think, yep looks like they have pushed north. We need more soldiers damnit!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what soldiers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scout_Ashenrar says &amp;lsquo;They are busy clearing the roads of undead, but the Orcs could potentially be a bigger threat if they were to cut us off in this ravine, Tanqara relies on supplies from other cities. I dont suppose you can help can you?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what help?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scout_Ashenrar says &amp;lsquo;That&amp;rsquo;s great! I need you to clear out as many as you can to the east of here till you find some sort of reason why they are poking around so close to Tanqara&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;scouting-the-desert&#34;&gt;Scouting the Desert&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You kill Orc_Leader [-1728,32,-1861]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loot Archaic Markings from Orc_Leader&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-spear&#34;&gt;The Spear&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended Level 10-15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Old Farza [-2165,29,-2001] the Archaic Markings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The merchant trader snorts some unusual looking green spice and smiles a toothy grin in your direction &amp;lsquo;So you come to ol&amp;rsquo; Farza do you? Looking for lost Utran pottery? No! The finest of Lunathian wine! Ohhhh&amp;hellip; no, you have something.. yes &amp;hellip; very very old, pass it over to old Farza.&amp;rsquo; The trader takes the small runic stone and gazes over it, feeling along its surface and fingering the lettering with his weather hands. &amp;lsquo;Yes, Darnan, second century&amp;hellip; unusual&amp;hellip; not words that Farza has seen before. A specialist you will need, for a bag of gold, maybe I can advice you&amp;hellip; yes!&amp;rsquo; he smiles his toothy smile and places out his hand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Ancient Tablet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Old Farza a Bag of Gold&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old Farza says &amp;lsquo;Good! You make an old merchant happy, and glad to help you, naturally! Old Farza never lets you down! Hahaa, So to understand this text, you need a linguist, and yes, there are great linguists in the library in Tanqara, but you need a specialist! An expert in Darnan languages! And where do you people fascinated with the Darnar&amp;hellip;..? In Darnar ruins of course! Old Farza travels many times between Tanqara and Lunathis and there are many ruins in a forest to the west of Tanqara. Travel up the northern path from Tanqara and head West. You will find Guzel the Archeologist, maybe his corpse, perhaps. But if this the case, its not old Farza fault. Either way, tell him Farza send you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hail Guzel [-2721 65 -2046]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaagggh more disturbance! More delays! WHAT DO YOU WANT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Guzel the Ancient Tablet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaagggh snatches the tablet from your hands &amp;lsquo;What is this? Wait&amp;hellip; hmm&amp;hellip; second century&amp;hellip; a trade document?&amp;rsquo; He peers closely at the lettering &amp;lsquo;No&amp;hellip; impossible! New script? NEW SCRIPT! This surely is a forgery? Who did you get this from&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Orcs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guzel snorts &amp;lsquo;Oh please! What use would Orcs have with an ancient tablet, they can barely read Tanqaran let alone second century darnan! Though&amp;hellip; hmmm. yess it does seem strange an orc would be making a forgery&amp;hellip;. Perhaps it is worth further study, but some of these words&amp;hellip; old&amp;hellip; lost, BUT! We are in the best place! This whole forest is full of ancient darnan ruins! If we could find more pieces with these unknown words perhaps we could put together what they means? So what do you think? Want to do some work for Guzel?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say I will work for you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guzel beams a smile &amp;lsquo;Excellent yes! You look far more rugged than an old man like Guzel, go in there, where those skeletons are&amp;hellip; see what old items they hold onto that Guzel can decipher. Might take a few pieces&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Guzel Common Rune Tablet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guzel looks over the Tablet and nods, &amp;lsquo;yes yes, very familiar to me, but sadly not much use to us for this case, keep looking!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Guzel Faded Rare Tablet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guzel carefully snatches the tablet from your hands &amp;lsquo;Careful! The writings in this tablet could be one of a kind! Do you wish for us to lose this knowledge forever?! So hmmm&amp;hellip; Just another trade tablet! I&amp;rsquo;m afraid you are going to have to dig deeper and try to find something more interesting&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Guzel Disk of the Sunless&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guzel beams as you uncover the perfectly preserved circular tablet &amp;lsquo;My my, what do we have here? What an unusual shape and such a high quality! It looks to have been preserved perfectly and is filled with&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; He rubs his finger along the symbols in a clockwise motion&amp;hellip; &amp;lsquo;a prayer&amp;hellip; Yes a prayer to a God! I must get this back to my library and cross reference against the archive. It may take me some time so please see my assistant Szsen in Lunathis, he will let you know when the translation is complete and how it may relate to what you seek. I can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee a 100% translation but I will do my best. You have done an old man well, please take this as a reward. Till we meet again!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Ancient Darnar Belt
You receive the title Archeologist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Hail Szsen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szsen says &amp;lsquo;Very busssssy is Sssszsssseennnn, no timesssss for youssss. That inbecccccile Guzel hassss me working on usssselesssss ressssssearch&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Guzel sent me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szsen says &amp;lsquo;The sssstudy of the tabletsssss isss in progressss but the complete transssslation will take sssome time. Szsen wondersss why the ccccircular tablet is sssso fassccinating for you? Sssssurely Szsen hassss much more interessssting things for you&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szsen says &amp;lsquo;Guzel had aquired a fassssincating partial sssspear that ssssseemed to predate even firssssst century Darnan. It wassss in our possesssion but one of the blue-ones tried to sssssteal it from usssss. In the sssstruggle the spear was broken into two piecesssss. I musssssst reaquire thissss artifact. Will you help Szsen return thissss to the collection?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say I will help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szsen says &amp;lsquo;Good, this pleasssses me very much. As i ssssaid earlier the ssspear wassss broken into sssssseveral peacesssss, the partssss we had were the ssssshaft and the innately decorated ssssssocket. We have never been able to locate the blade itsssself. Seek the blue onesssss of the foressssst nearby. One of them musssssst still have the sssssocket.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loot Innately Decorated Spear Socket&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give the Innately Decorated Spear Socket to Szsen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szsen says &amp;lsquo;Yesssss! Quite beautiful indeed! It isssss good to ssssseee this return! We are ssssssure it wasss the sssspiraling monkey decoratation around the sssssocket that the blue onesssss were ssssso fasssscinated with. It provessss the tree dwellerssss are more than just ssssimple animals! Now we mussssst find the sssshaft, a travelling Monk visssssited Lunarissssss recently and ssssswore to us that the ssssshaft was a relic of the Sha Sun monkssssss. He paid usssss as handssssome price to take the ssshaft to hisss people and promised to return with more information. We have yet to hear from him sssssince that day, hissss name was Qin Chi and we believe he was from the eassssst of Utra. He mentioned sssssomething about the ssssstaff being to do with the violent lizzzzardfolk of the ssssands. I am ssssure if you were to seek the lizzzards you could find the ssssstafff&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You kill the Lizardman Priest near Lunathis [-2553 127 -2222] and loot Torn and Blooded Robe of Qin Chi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Torn and Blooded Robe to Szsen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szsen says Ohh nooo is thissss the robe of the monk? Thissss is not good! There is another of Qin Chis kind in Tanqara, perhapsssss you sssshould show this to him&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Torn and Blooded Robe of Qin Chi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find Xon Shu in the garden inside Tanqara&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Torn and Blooded Robe of Qin Chi to Xon Shu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xon Shu says &amp;lsquo;Bantushi barashan. It is a blessing that we should meet here in this place of desolation where life refuses to succumb to the many challenges that face it.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Torn and Blooded Robe of Qin Chi to Xon Shu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xon Shu says &amp;lsquo;Qin Chi&amp;rsquo;s robe! Fear not, though his robe is blooded and torn he is certainly not dead - his destiny reaches far into the future.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say to Xon Shu &amp;lsquo;What is the destiny of Qin Chi&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xon Shu &amp;lsquo;That is for the Jade Emperor and Methabeht alone to know. Qin Chi is formidable but his path is not one that is walked alone. It is now for you to join him on his great journey. Seek the card lady, she will take you where you need to go&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say hail Augur Didyma&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Augur Didyma holds her finger to her lips and beckons you to sit. She stands, slowly, and lights two incense that give of a sweet smell. Gathering herself she sits down and places three cards on the table. &amp;lsquo;It is time, what do you seek?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;Qin Chi&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Augur Didyma turns the first card revealing a tower. &amp;lsquo;To the east lays a tower, long forgotten now and inhabited by the scaled ones. It is a place of blasphemy in the eyes of the gods, doomed to summon the unwanted, cursed for all who walk its halls. The tower requires a sacrifice to bring the ones its new keepers seek. If you hurry, you may save Qin Chi and prevent another calamity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scaled ones tower is Ezarils Gate to the east of Tanqara&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Hail to Qin Chi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qin Chi says &amp;lsquo;Bantui, barashan. I thank you for killing my captives but I am here by my own will, it is the destiny that has been placed before me by the Gods&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what destiny?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qin Chi says, &amp;lsquo;I am here to make a sacrifice, my last sacrifice. You have a path opening up before you, one that has been written in the Kojiki since time immorial. To begin you will require an item very holy, one that had been a shadow of its former self. It was my destiny to bring it back here so it could travel back to the Planes and be whole once more. Now it is time for you to bring it back&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say how will I bring it back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qin Chi says, &amp;lsquo;This tower is a cursed contraption, built by snake like beings who no longer slither the deserts of Utra. The Darnans tried to exploit the magic here but all they ever did was summon suffering into the world. The cost of bringing back the item we seek will require my death, one I am happy to give to allow you to complete the great burden you have ahead of you. With my soul in your hand, you must use it to the floating contraption in the room before us. This will summon the artifact you need. Now barashan, it is time for me to return to Methabeht, do what must be done&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You kill Qin Chi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loot Qin Chis Soul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You summon Oshira Plague Lord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You kill Oshira Plague Lord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Zurvans Staff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Zurvans staff to Szsen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szsen says &amp;lsquo;Ssssso Qin Chi was alive? I thought sssssurely the ssssshaft was losssst forever!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say he was not alive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szsen says &amp;lsquo;That isssss most unfortunate, he ssssseemed like a good man for one of their kind. In honour of him then ssssurely it behoovesss us to finisssh our quest and complete the ancccient sssspear? What do you think? Issss thissss something you would be interessssted in&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say I shall complete the quest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szsen says &amp;lsquo;Then we must now find the missssssing blade head of the sssspear. We know the sssstaff predatesss the Darnar sssssooo it may be wisssse for usss to conssssult ssssome of the oldesssst peoplesss of Utra. The Kenku are hosssstile to usss even to this day but the Bullywugsssss may be more accommodating. Ssssseek their village in the blackfeather plainssssss and sssssee if you can find anything about the ssssspear head. Even if the current population of Bulwugssss are not aware of the sssspear, it may be pressssent in their ancient mythssss and ssssstories&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;SHOP&amp;rsquo; to Lorekeeper_Hurbl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You buy Book: The Great Crossing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE GREAT CROSSING&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THOUGH I WAS JUST
A SMALL TADPOLE
I REMEMBER THE DAY
OF THE GREAT
CROSSING AS IF IT
WAS YESTERDAY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 WEEKS OF BITTER
WIND BY ANCIENT
RAFT ACROSS
AN UNFORGIVING
SEA DID WE TRAVEL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FILLED WITH
CREATURES LARGER
THAN MOUNTAINS
EACH SEEKING TO
TEAR US LIMB FROM
LIMB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEAD WOULD WE HAVE
BEEN HAD IT NOT
BEEN FOR OUR
GREATEST HERO
LORD SIGIG&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WITH HIS SPEAR
BLESSED BY SUR&amp;rsquo;EL
EACH BEAST FELL
BACK INTO THE
DEPTHS AND WE
TRAVELED ONWARDS
FURTHER INTO
THE STORM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AS THE DANGER
PASSED THERE DID
WE FIND LAND ON
THE BARREN COAST
LONG FROM QYLIA
LONG FROM THE
UNDER
LONG FROM THOSE
I WOULD CALL MY
ANCESTORS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AS WE LANDED
WE FOUND THE ISLAND
HOME TO THE SCALED,
SNAKE AND DRAGON
ALIKE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOOD WE WERE FOR
MANY MOON CYCLES
BUT ENDURE WE
ALWAYS HAVE, WHERE
WE COULD FIGHT
WE WOULD, LONG
BATTLES WITH THE
BIRD ONES, BITTER
OF OUR NEW HOME
IN THE SWAMPS
THEY MADE HOME&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LORD SIGIG WITH
HIS SHINING SILVER
SPEAR, FORGED
BY THE MOON
GODDESS AND GIFTED
BY THE OCEAN LORD
STOOD AT THE FRONT
OF OUR LINES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SO GREAT WAS THE
LORD, EVEN THE
GODS BLESSED
HIM ON THE EVE
OF THE BATTLE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PROMISING ALL THAT
FOLLOW HIM ETERNAL
ENTRY INTO GARDEN
OF THE GODS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ON SO WE FOUGHT
THE SKY RAINED
THE BEAKED ONES
THOUSANDS UPON
THOUSANDS FELL
AND AS WE BREACHED
THE NEST WE SAW
WHY THE BIRD ONES
FOUGHT WITH SUCH
FERVOR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SLEEPING, ENCIRCLING
THE CENTRE OF THE
NEST LAY A MIGHTY
CHILD OF KUMARI
ITS GREATH BODY
ENCIRCLING A BROOD
OF EGGS AND
LIGHTNING CRACKLING
FROM ITS BLACK
SCALED BODY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE STORM DRAGON
UNWOUND ITSELF FROM
ITS BROOD AND
SHREDDED ITS CLAW
THROUGH THE
STRONGEST OF OUR
RANKS, STEEL AND
SKIN TORN APART IN
A FLASH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STEPPING FORWARD
CAME SIGIG SLAMMING
HIS GREAT SPEAR
DOWN INTO THE GROUND
MARKING A LINE
BEFORE THAT AGED
SERPENT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HE BECKONED US BACK
WITH A SORROWFUL
SMILE, PROMISING US
HE WOULD SEE US ONCE
MORE, WHEN THE MOON
GATE OPENS AND THE
GODS WELCOME US
INTO THE GARDEN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE GREAT DRAGON
SPREAD ITS MASSIVE
WINGS OUTWARDS,
COVERING THE NIGHT
SKY WITH A BLACK
SHADOW, ITS HUGE
LEGS BUCKLED DOWN
INTO THE GROUND AND
ITS EYES FILLED WITH
RAGE AS IT GAZED
DIRECTLY AT SIGIG
AND LET LOOSE
A MIGHTY ROAR
THROWING US ALL TO
OUR FEET&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE LAST WE SAW WAS
LORD SIGID CHARGE
FORTH LAUNCHING HIS
SPEAR INTO THE
SCALES OF THE GREAT
SCALED ONE. THE
DRAGON WAILED AND
LASHED ABOUT, ITS
MIGHTY NECK KNOCKING
OVER THE BEAKED ONES
IT SNAPPED ITS MIGHTY
HEAD AT THE THE
IMMOVABLE SIGIG, ITS
RAZER SHARP TEETH
SLICING INTO THE
CHEST OF OUR CHOSEN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IT WRITHED LEFT AND
RIGHT SMASHING SIGIG
INTO THE ROOF AND
WALLS OF THE BROOD
CHAMBER AND WITH A
RUNNING CHARGE BURST
THROUGH THE BUILDING
AND INTO THE SKY
CARRYING AWAY OUR
GREATEST CHAMPION&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IN THE DISTANCE WE
COULD SEE SIGIG
SWIPING DEFIANTLY,
THE SCREAMS OF THE
DRAGON ECHOING
THROUGH THE
BLACKFEATHER - THE
BEAKED ONES LOOKING
ON OUR RANKS, NOW
WITHOUT THEIR
MIGHTY PROTECTOR
BEGAN TO RETREAT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BLOODY AND TORN, WE
TOOK THE OPPORTUNITY
TO RETREAT, THE
BEAKED ONES PARTED
LIKE A RETREATING
SHORE AS WE RETURNED
HOME, ALL THE WHILE
LISTENING TO A
DARK AND SORROWFUL
CRY OF SOMETHING
GREAT WAILING IN
THE MOUNTAINS THAT
LOOMED OVER HEAD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IT HAS BEEN MANY
MANY YEARS SINCE
LORD SIGIG LEFT US
AND WE HAVE NEVER
SINCE HEARED OF
THE GREAT STORM
DRAGON OF THE
BLACKFEATHER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TADLINGS STILL
BELIEVE SIGIG
FIGHTS ON, DEEP
WITHIN THE CHASMS
OF THE DRAGON SPINE
MOUNTAINS SHALL
ONE DAY RETURN TO
LEAD US INTO THE
LAND WHICH WAS
PROMISED SO LONG AGO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szsen says &amp;lsquo;What a fascccccinating sssssstory! Thossssse creaturessss never wissssh to ssssspeak to me, i ssssupose thissss explainssss their disssstrussssst for lizzzzzardfolkssssss. If this Sssssgig sssspear is that which we sssseek then it is likely in the mountainsssss somewhere in the blackfeather plainsssss. It sssso happens there is a contractor in Tanqara that may know more about the minessss up there. Sssspeak to him and sssssee if he has come acrosss anything unusual in the dragonsssspine mountains&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;have you seen anything unusual in the dragonspine mountains&amp;rsquo; to Contractor_Kuram&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contractor_Kuram says &amp;lsquo;We find unusual stuff all the time, we toss most of it up in the mountains. Sometimes if we find something valuable the guys may take it to the pawnbroker. He doesnt pay much but its something. I guess you are better speaking to him about unusual stuff&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say hail pawnbroker_gisf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawnbroker_Gisf says &amp;lsquo;Hello, looking for something in particular?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say i am searching for something unusual&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawnbroker_Gisf says &amp;lsquo;Hmm unusual&amp;hellip; well that could be many of the things i have, perhaps you could be more specific?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say i am looking for a spear&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawnbroker_Gisf says &amp;lsquo;Spear yes&amp;hellip; not the only one&amp;rsquo; he whispers &amp;lsquo;are you with Lord Murag?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say who is murag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pawnbroker_Gisf says &amp;lsquo;Oh nothing, nothing, forget i ever said anything&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find Lord Murag forcing Orc miners to try to find something deep in the mountains at Redscar Mines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You kill Lord Murag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have looted Spear Head&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Spear Head to Szsen &amp;lsquo;Isssss thissss possssssible? The ssssspear head hasss been found!! What a wonderful sssssuprise! You have made Szsen ssssoo very happy! Here take thisssss note from Guzel, he has completed your transsssssssslation, as for your help I hope this will come in ussssse one day&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive THE SWORD OF HEAVEN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Darnan Cloak of Majesty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have gained experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only in our
darkest moment in
last days of the
wars with the
dragons that Cynem
returned. His powers
far greater than he
had ever possessed,
slew countless
dragons with an army
of Dracoliches and
undead. Holding in
his hands the Sword
of Heaven of our God&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cynem completed his
task and returned
once more far below
the belly of Utra.
Some say he
experiments on our
father, extending
his own powers and
still trying to open
that way back home
perhaps one day he
will suceed or more
likely, we will all
be judged for what
we have done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-sword-of-heaven&#34;&gt;The Sword of Heaven&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended Level 19-30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quest starts in the Halls of the Sunless&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loot Darnar Contraption from Lord Darnar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Hail Tinkerer Ssasri&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinkerer Ssasri says &amp;lsquo;The finesssst of utilitiesss and devicesssss! Hand crafted by Ssasri!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Ssasri Darnar Contraption&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinkerer Ssasri says &amp;lsquo;What is thisssss? A toy of ssssuch delicate dessssign? Issss it in need of repair or perhapsssss you wisssssh to sell it to Ssasri? Yesss i would be most interesssssted in this fasssscinating toy! Where did you get it, it looks aged, and does not seem Tanqaran or Lunathian. Issss this perhapss from the ruins?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say it is from the ruins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinkerer Ssasri says &amp;lsquo;How very sssstrange! That the old onessss would create sssssuch marvelous thingssss. I bet perhapssss you might find sssssomeone in Avaris who may know more?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say What is Avaris?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinkerer Ssasri says &amp;lsquo;Avaris yesss, a distant city, it is believed they have been here for sssssome time but they do not like outsssssiderssss like usss. Perhapssss you may find a way to speak to them&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinkerer Ssasri says &amp;lsquo;The way to Avaris is quite far from here, you may find be able to find a guide there in the Orcish kingdom of Arrr, it is far south eassssst from here. If you are travelling there perhapssss you can do me a favour? I have a delivery, a ssssspecial clock for an Orc called Xug. If you take thisssss to him, he will reward you on my behalf&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Clock of Forgotten Souls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Clock of Forgotten Souls to Shadowknight Xug&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shadowknight Xug says &amp;lsquo;Finally Xug get my clock back! I knew stupid lizard be no use. Let me see, ugghhh yess it fixed now! Ok he no so bad. Here you take some gold, Xug no need shiny things&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Xugs Bag of Gold Coins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say hail Darlan Cavediver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says ‘Darlan Cavediver, Legendary explorer and Private Investigator at your service! What ancient wonders and lost treasures are you and I to find? What songs will the bards sing of our extraordinary adventures? For a small bag of gold you can hire my outstanding abilities and your troubles, no matter how great, shall be no more!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give &amp;lsquo;Darlan Cavediver&amp;rsquo; Xugs Bag of Gold Coins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says &amp;lsquo;What luck! Such a day in such a place we two were to cross paths! Maybe we have met before? No matter! What matters is we are here together now. Me, a legendary explorer and you, a person, together to begin a grand adventure across the vast oceans of this world, riches and treasures await, great stories to be written and all for an affordable, renewable payment plan&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say I seek a treasure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says &amp;lsquo;Of course you seek a treasure! Who would not? And what a better person to find that treasure than the legendary Darlan Cavediver? I&amp;rsquo;ve found quite a few treasures you know, over my many years! Young you may think I am from my humble, well kept appearance but Darlan Cavediver is over 6000 years old by my reckoning! I don&amp;rsquo;t know how or why but lets just say I have always been here and the gods willing will be here for many more moons to come. Now is this treasure a vast hoard, an ancient weapon or a lost powerful tome of ages gone?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say it is a weapon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says &amp;lsquo;Yes it is indeed a weapon! A great weapon that will turn you into the worlds greatest killing machine! I know this because I have met people just like you before. You can trust in Darlan Cavediver to find this magical bow&amp;hellip;. no? axe mmm?&amp;hellip; sword ?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say it is a sword&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says &amp;lsquo;Ahaha see! I knew we had a connection! Some say Darlan has a type of psychic power to read the minds of those he is sent by the Gods to help. Now we shall find this sword oh yes! Almost very very soon, as soon as Darlan is allowed to leave that is&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say allowed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says &amp;lsquo;Oh yes well, I am a great explorer as you have no doubt heard in the taverns all over Solinia. Sometimes great journeys require an adventurer like myself to make certain agreements and deals with people to facilitate the many important duties I have to complete on my way. Like for example, the Orcs here say I owe them my eternal servitude for the theft of weapons from the amourer in the middle of the night. I say how can you brandish such words as theft to a man such as Darlan Cavediver? Objects are merely instruments allowing me to complete the many great feats that change the very fate of life on Solinia.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say you are bound in servitude&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says &amp;lsquo;For now I am apparently enslaved to the Orc Chieften of ARRR, am I saying ARRRR right? You have to scream its name, yes? Well until ARRRR sees me fit for release, the great adventurers of Darlan Cavediver must come to a halt! You could however, speak to the Chieften yourself and perhaps get him to agree to release me? Of course I would then be able to continue the necessary dangerous and exceptionally complex work needed to help you to recover this great and mighty sword you seek&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say hail Chief Gurok&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Gurok says &amp;lsquo;You walk before Gurok, what makes you worthy to stand before the mightiest of Orcs?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say how can i make myself worthy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Gurok says &amp;lsquo;Gurok know of your invasion of Redfang, this pleased Gurok. Gurok let you walk into ARRR because of this. But how Gurok know you wont steal from ARRR like you steal from stupid Redfangs? Why Gurok trust you?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say how can i make you trust me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Gurok says &amp;lsquo;Gurok have brother, he stupid, he good fighter but he stupid. He get lost, far south in forest. He captive and need to be free, no brother of Gurok should be held by smelly goblin creature. You find brother Lok save Gurok brother and we trust you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Hail Lok&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lok says &amp;lsquo;Stupid blue people wrap Lok in metal! Me no move! You help Lok! Brother important, he be pleased!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Lok Goblin Jailer Key&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lok says &amp;lsquo;Haha! Lok free! Stupid blue people! I kill them all! You find my brother Gurok, give him Loks beads, he know i alive&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Orcish Prayer Beads of Lok&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Orcish Prayer Beads of Lok to Chief Gurok&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gurok says &amp;lsquo;You save Lok! Gurok happy, I no think you come back, is suprise to Gurok. You must be strong fighter so now you please Gurok and fight our best fighter in Arena. If you win, Gurok maybe find you worthy&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You recieve Arena Champions Token&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Arena Champions Token to Gurok&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gurok says &amp;lsquo;Hahaha! Gurok saw fight! You not so weedy as you look! Gurok now think you worthy. Gurok smart to let you in city. Now gurok wonder what you want&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say I want to free Darlan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gurok says &amp;lsquo;Darlan is Gurok slave now, he try to steal from ARRR. We consider bash his head in and feast on him in stew, but he look kind of stinky and not in good way. If you want Darlan you have to buy him as he property of Gurok. Why you want such stupid slave I never know.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say I want to buy him&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gurok says &amp;lsquo;Ok ok, I consider to sell but not for shiny gold piece. Gurok want someone dead, you good at fighting. The flappy people to east cause Gurok so many problem. We want to spread ARRR, but they no like Guroks people. They have princess, she very stroppy lady. You kill her and give Gurok her wings. Ahahahaha, yes this be good! I give you Darlan for this.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You kill Princess Celina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loot Wings of Princess Celina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Wings of Princess Celina to Gurok&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gurok says &amp;lsquo;AHhhhhhhhhhhhhhh!!!! She dead! You best fighter! Darlan yours now, you take his key and use him as you will&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gurok gives you Darlans Key&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Darlans Key to Darlan Cavediver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says &amp;lsquo;Finally my freedom! Yes unlock me from these frightful shackles so a great explorer can be free once more to roam a world in need of his aid! Wait, what, you are not going to free me? ARE YOU KIDDING ME. I will not be a slave! No wait&amp;hellip; no dont leave&amp;hellip;. ok fine&amp;hellip; fine.. look if I help you find your sword, you will free me right?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say I will free you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says &amp;lsquo;Alright! Good, we are communicating! You receive the aid of the great explorer Darlan Cavediver and I receive my freedom! This is a fair price, and believe me when I say how sorry I am that I have already spent the gold you gave me. You see anyone will tell you I am quite industrious and despite my shackles I was able to bribe me way to freedom twice in your absense. Now back to the Sword, Do you have any idea where it may be?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Avaris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says &amp;lsquo;Avaris, a second home to Darlan Cavediver! Even the mention of my name will have you rolling into the main halls. We could go right away but they wont let you in without an Avaran Seal! I did have one, but I lost it during a long loving relationship with a Mysmaal of the south. I could go with you but since you insist on keeping me shackled like a djinn you will have to find it yourself. Bring me my entry seal from the mysmaal in Castleblack Veil and I will arrange us a wagon that will take us to the city. Dont be too long, the orcs get bored and poor dashing Darlan Cavediver starts to get funny looks from the orc women when the moon comes up. I cant go through that thrice, i simply cant&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loot Darlans Magical Seal from Lady Ashri&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You giveDarlans Magical Seal to Darlan Cavediver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darlan Cavediver says &amp;lsquo;Aha! You have unwittlingly fallen into one of Darlan Cavedivers many unavoidable ruses! This is not an Avaran Entry Seal but a teleportation device that will take me back to my Sirens dear city where you shall never find me again! This will teach you for keeping me shackled! We could have been such friends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Darlan Cavediver dissapears&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Enemies All Around</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/enemies-all-around/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/enemies-all-around/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enemies All Around&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Enemies All Around&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quest starts in: Morheim Lighthouse (113,101,479)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended Level: 13-20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must have completed: Freedom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;Hail, Assistant Tanri&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant_Tanri says to soandso &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, i&amp;rsquo;m waiting for someone important to arrive&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;I have arrived to help&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant_Tanri says to soandso &amp;lsquo;Ah good you have made it. Rail is sorry she was unable to meet you here in person and has sent me in her stead as she travels south on a delicate matter. Your efforts in Haven has uncovere d a plot to simultaneously attack haven and morheim from the abandoned mines and caves that lay under both our respective towns. With the death of Argb Tooflus the orcs under Haven are now in disarray however the Goblins under Morheim are still at large and a danger to our allies in Morheim. Please meet with Sir Jirn in the Paladin Guild at Morheim. He will task you with your next assignment. Tell him Tanri sent you&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive a quest flag!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit Sir Jirn in the Stormwatcher Citiadel in Morheim. The Paladin guild is located down the stairs from the Temple of Kaza&amp;rsquo;Thul in the inner areas of Morheim. [264, 28, 293]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;Hail, Sir Jirn&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sir Jirn says to soandso &amp;lsquo;go out there and spread kaza&amp;rsquo;thuls word&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;Tanri sent me&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sir Jirn says &amp;lsquo;So ye elfn lady finally sent sum help eh? Well, we be acceptin it friend. It&amp;rsquo;s been some time since we took a batterin&amp;rsquo; to the Gobels and words spreadin&amp;rsquo; they&amp;rsquo;re build up their numbers again down&amp;rsquo;n the abandoned halls below Morheim. We be needin ye to dispatch a certain one the hoods say is named Kazril, a tricky one mind so watch yeself. Ye can find the entrance near the rear exit te&amp;rsquo; morheim, no doubt t&amp;rsquo;one ye came in. Bring me his head n&amp;rsquo;the&amp;rsquo; stormwatchers el reward ye&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazril is a Goblin located in the miners guild below Morheim, you can find him by finding your way to the ruined area of Morheim at 235, 59, 376. Once inside fight your way to the very back of Morheim. He is located near two towers with a rather difficult raid mob (you can avoid) and other rogues and necromancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give the Head_of_Kazril_Gzirix to Sir Jirn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sir Jirn says to soandso &amp;lsquo;Ah ye sure have Kazic on ye side! Ye dun t&amp;rsquo;Citadel a great favour t&amp;rsquo;day friend an we StormGuard always remember our allies. Take this eh? Something te&amp;rsquo; remember us by. Ye best get back te&amp;rsquo; ye contact, let him know it&amp;rsquo;s done&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive a quest flag!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Stormguard Sword of Honour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Return to Assistant Tanri in the lighthouse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say to Assistant Tanri &amp;lsquo;it is done&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant Tanri says to soandso &amp;lsquo;Good, rail was wise to put her trust in you. Now we must irradicate the Orcs that have been amassing to the south of our borders. Iradicate Chief Rugel in the Nagul Rock infestation and return with his head&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive a quest flag!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel to Nagul Rock to the south of Morheim and retrieve the head of Chief Rugel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give the Head of Chief Rugel to Assisant Tanri&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant Tanri says to soandso &amp;lsquo;You are an living instrument of the gods, we are proud to have you working to put the world right again. I have just one more task to give you, Rail went south to meet with the Kingdom of Balrud but we are yet to hear word from her. I need you to head to Balrud and track her whereabouts, though it is unlikely she has been kidnapped twice in one month, we cannot be sure. I fear this may be the last we speak friend, know that it was an honour to work with you, Hero&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive a quest flag!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Heroes Augmentation!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Freedom</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/freedom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/freedom/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Freedom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quest starts in: Haven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended Level: 1-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Hail, Overseer Teris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseer_Teris says to soandso &amp;lsquo;don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid young one. we anushi may be unfamiliar with the races of your [land] but we come in peace&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;what land&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseer_Teris says to soandso &amp;lsquo;good question, we have searched for some time to answer this. we are, as of right now, unable to determine the exact location we have made our settlement. all we know is that the [caerthian] citadel and it&amp;rsquo;s surroundings were ripped from the [land] it once stood and was transported here, to this place&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;who are the caerthians?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseer_Teris says to soandso &amp;lsquo;the [caerthian] empire is a blight on Qylia, dominating and enslaving all it comes across. It is how my people came to fall from grace and become nothing but a source of labour for the [caerthian]s. However, lucky for us, there were some [sympathisers].&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;what sympathisers?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseer_Teris says to soandso &amp;lsquo;though the empire itself is corrupt and evil, some of the population saw pitty for my people. These caerthians are the ones that you see here today, in haven. During the destruction and our arrival to this place, these caerthians freed us from our bonds and we made our escape across the ocean. It is here we plan to find [help] and build up our forces and attack the caerthians once more and free the rest of my kind&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;how can i help?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseer_Teris says to soandso &amp;lsquo;This plan is currently in motion but we are, as yet unable to begin. We first need the aid of the Aerindel, the true rivals of the [Caerthian] empire. With theri strength and our knowledge of the citadel it should give us the ability to break the chains of my kin and leave the empire in ruins. [Rail] N&amp;rsquo;Ris is currently working on this but is currently missing, until we hear word of her we shall not be able to proceed&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;where is rail&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseer_Teris says to soandso &amp;lsquo;[rail] was investigating rumours that a nearby mine had been inhabited by invading orcs. If you could find the time to find her it would be of great [help] to me&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive a quest flag!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rail is a prisoner in the abandoned mines directly east of Haven. You can find it below the wooden orc warrior outpost along the path as you exit Haven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Hail, Rail N&amp;rsquo;Ris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rail_N&amp;rsquo;Ris says to soandso &amp;lsquo;the cage is broken but my shackles are tied! free me so I can get out of this place!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retrieve Simple Iron Key from Argb Toofluss who is also located in the mines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say Hail, Rail N&amp;rsquo;Ris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give the Simple_Iron_Key to Rail&amp;rsquo;Nris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rail&amp;rsquo;Nris says to soandso &amp;lsquo;I wondered how long it would take for that kitty to send me someone to help, give him this - he&amp;rsquo;ll tell you where to meet me&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have recieved a Quest Flag!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Note for the Overseer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give &amp;lsquo;Note for the Overseer&amp;rsquo; to Overseer_Teris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseer_Teris says to soandso &amp;lsquo;a note written in the Farsan Cypher, so you found her then? Give me a moment to read over this&amp;hellip; ah&amp;hellip; oh, oh no! It seems things have taken a turn for the worse. [Rail] needs your [help] urgently at the lighthouse near Morheim. Follow the road east of here, you can&amp;rsquo;t miss that dwarven architecture. Oh and take this for your efforts!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive a quest flag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Honour Blade of Teris&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Vipers</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/the-vipers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/the-vipers/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vipers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Vipers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quest is no longer active&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;old-quest-script&#34;&gt;Old Quest Script&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;player receives medal for defeating Warrior Solan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;player gives Warrior Solan the Medal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warrior Solan says &amp;lsquo;For 43 years I have held the Champion title of Highguard and only one other has ever gotten so close to bring me to my knees. You should be proud of your achievement friend, may you hold the title so long as I. Maybe now I can retire to a life of beer and being a thorn in the side of my beautiful wife&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;player receives quest flag FIND_WARRIOR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;player says &amp;lsquo;Who is this one?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warrior Solan says &amp;lsquo;She was as strong as a bear and as vicious as a viper. Oh how her beauty stunned me, this was long before my wife mind. She carried with her a blade marked with symbols and no shield I have seen could keep it at bay. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I wrestled it out of her hands that I was able to pin the lass, oh how angry she was! Hah!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Player says ‘Hail’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murshir_Vah says ‘A fools errand to attempt delivery with the Vipers stranglehold on the route to the elven capital’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murshir_Vah says ‘The Vipers have been raiding our caravans night and day. It’s got so bad even the Jadeclaws have had to personally escort some of our most important shipments. But this leaves us with a weaker defence at home. Sometimes I wonder if this is all part of Cinthias plan. What are a few wagons full of food worth to her compared to a defensible port city?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Player says ‘Who are the Vipers’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murshir_Vah says ‘Cinthia is the leader of The Vipers; they say she is undefeatable in combat. While ever she has her eye set on our home our trade and safety will be compromised. Maybe it you could clear up the road it might send a message to her that we will not be pushed around so easily’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Player gives ‘Viper Head’ to Murshir_Vah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murshir_Vah says ‘So you despatched the raiders! Good, here is a reward for your efforts friend! Should you wish to aid us again maybe we could strike back at Cinthia and her ragtag raiders at the very heart of her operations’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Player says ‘who is Cinthia’ to Murshir_Vah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murshir_Vah says ‘It is said Cinthia has an underground outpost to the north of here in a Hidden cove, find your way to her Stronghold, slay her troops and bring back the supplies she dare steal from us’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Player gives ‘Stolen ShaSun Supplies’ to Murshir_Vah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murshir_Vah says ‘You got the supplies! Oh thank you here take this, my days of adventure are but a dream!’&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Windstriker</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/windstriker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/quests/windstriker/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windstriker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windstriker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recomended level: Ranger, 50&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say &amp;lsquo;Hail&amp;rsquo; Kessel the Wolf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessel the Wolf says So many people strip the forests and ravage the lands to forge their tools and weapons. More and more are forgetting the ancient arts of nature and how to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what ancient arts of nature?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessel the Wolf says Through natural means, you can attain a true woodsman&amp;rsquo;s weapon; unmatched by anything a mortal craftsman could forge through such destructive measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say how can I attain this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessel the Wolf says I would not offer this service to just anyone, but I can sense the blessings of the forests upon you. However, I will require a few special items in order to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say what items?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessel the Wolf says I will need the branching arm of the Woodwalker just west of here, the tears of the Siren Queen, the boiling blood of the fiery magistrate, and the hairs of a powerful goblin lord. Bring these things to me, and I will craft a bow that truly reflects nature&amp;rsquo;s glory!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loot the &amp;lsquo;Arm of the Woodwalker&amp;rsquo; from The Woodwalker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Kessel the Arm of the woodwalker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessel the Wolf says &amp;lsquo;Good, now return to me with the tears of the Siren Queen&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Kessel the Tears of Isla Anata&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessel the Wolf says &amp;lsquo;Good, now return to me with the boiling blood of the fiery magistrate&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Kessel the Blood of Kten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessel the Wolf says &amp;lsquo;Good, now return to me with the hairs of the powerful goblin lord&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You give Kessel the Hairs of Uuago Kiz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessel the Wolf says Yes, this is perfect. We now call upon the spirits of this sacred ring to bind these items into a weapon that may be used to defend our sacred groves and untainted forests from those that would mindlessly strip them barren. May Windstriker ever aid you in the defense of our natural realm from those that would see it destroyed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive XP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You receive Windstriker&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>