<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Utra</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/</link><description>Recent content in Utra on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Blackfeather Plains</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/blackfeather-plains/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/blackfeather-plains/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackfeather Plains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Blackfeather Plains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nestled at the foot of the Dragonspione Mountains the Blackfeather Plains is an endless swampy forest making home to the Kenku of Zerzura and Bullywugs of Pollywog Hollow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the Anushi of Tanqara have begun to cut a trade route through the forest and have settled in the central lake a city they have named Ezro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through diplomacy the Ezronite traders have become friendly with the Bullywugs but are under constant threat from the Kenku who loom ever watching in the everdark canopies over head&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some speak of shambling dead that roam through the forests at night, pouring out of long lost ruins in the north, whatever is causing their unrest, is becoming more and more frequent&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Dragonspine Mountains</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/dragonspine-mountains/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/dragonspine-mountains/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dragonspine Mountains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dragonspine Mountains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mountains mark an uncrossable barrier between the Blackfeather and Vale of Zhuvirae on the western lands of Utra. Populated mainly in its winding cavernous depths are the Goblins of Sraal and the Myconids which find warmth in the heat of the lava that sloshes like a river through the iron filled unbelly of Utra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is believed the mountains take their name from some ancient storm dragon, the last of many that once inhabited this continent in ages past. At night, some still believe they can stlil hear the wailing of the ancient scaled one as it weeps for its long lost kin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently the Orcs of Redfang have begun to dig deep into the northern parts of the mountain range, led by a fanatic oracle named Lord Murag they are seeking something ancient but the mountain keeps its secrets away from the hands of mortals&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Kalderstrond Woods</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/kalderstrond-woods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/kalderstrond-woods/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalderstrond Woods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalderstrond Woods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evil diesel clockworks have dug their way up from the under and into the Kalderstrond! They are burning every tree and mining every ore in their newly created subterreean clockwrok city&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;steam vents can be seen all the way through the forest, but thereal adventure is below the surface in the metal corridors of the city&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Mt Kalderstrond</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/mt-kalderstrond/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/mt-kalderstrond/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mt Kalderstrond&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Mt Kalderstrond&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Southern Wastes</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/southern-wastes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/southern-wastes/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Southern Wastes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Southern Wastes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All along the wind battered Barren Coast that stretches from West to East lays the frigid Southern Wastes. An unforgiving tundra of ice and snow that is home to Sirens and Goblins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the cold doesnt kill the travellers making their way through this land, then they will surely end up as play things of the Sirens in the Palace of Frozen songs. Weary travellers caught sailing past this land will hear the gentle song calling them towards the gleaming lights that sparkle in the distance, unknowning the dangers that wait them if they manage to safely land on its shores&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the west side of the Wastes is the Goblin Kingdom of Sraal, an ever expanding race of blue Gobel who have emerged from the Dragonspine Mountains intent on claiming territory on the surface. They feast on the animals and creatures that wander, lost, from the Vale of Zhuvirae to the north and have recently set their sights on lands claimed by the Orcs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the far East you will find the most recent arrivals to the Wastes. The Asurans have constructed an impenetrable fortress known as the Summit of the Fallen, some believe it is a temple to gods long lost, others an outpost for something much bigger to come&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Steppes of the Stormking</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/steppes-of-the-stormking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/steppes-of-the-stormking/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steppes of the Stormking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steppes of the Stormking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wide open wilderness of the eastern lands of Avaris sits at the foot of the mountains of the holy sanctuary of Elysia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This land is home to Storm Giants, and the bones of many dead dragons that fell in the war with the avarians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the craggy open steppes are the wildlife that make up the staple of the Storm Giants diet, and on occasion a exploring band of orcs or newly arrived meroei hoping to find riches in the hills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Storm King sits on his throne in Storm Keep at the hills of the nearby mountains, he is an unforgiving war loving champion that has not seen a good battle since the days the last of the dragons fled the land&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The giants respect the holy nature of the elysian caldera that lays beyond the mountains, they understand what happens should they disrepect the gods. They are more than happy to protect the entrance to the valley and act as bouncers killing anyone who dare approach&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Fading Wilds</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/the-fading-wilds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/the-fading-wilds/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fading Wilds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fading Wilds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fading forest to the south of the steppes is home to those that have been banished from the Valley of Elysia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This browning dying woodland is home to all manner of natures strangest creations from mutated satyr, decaying myconids, rotting undead and viscious acid filled plant life that is unforgiving to any&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do make it deep into to the forest then you are likely to end up wrapped in the cacoons of the fading spiders smother the forest in cobwebs, slowly digesting the remnents of satyrs and giants that got tangled in there months ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems some civilsation must have existed here at some point, as if you were to slash your way through the cobwebs and fettid vines you would find long forgotten golden temples, to who are what we will never know&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Sleeping Sands</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/the-sleeping-sands/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/the-sleeping-sands/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sleeping Sands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Sleeping Sands&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Valley of Elysia</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/the-valley-of-elysia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/the-valley-of-elysia/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Valley of Elysia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-valley-of-elysia&#34;&gt;The Valley of Elysia&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said in the beginning there was nothing but a vast endless sea of unbroken darkness in which a god as ageless as time swam, lighting its way with vast jewel like suns. On its journey the god did stumble upon the barren landscape of a now dead star lying upon its center it did see a bright blue lake of incredible beauty glistening with astral magic of the wisps that flickered above it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is here in the Valley of Elysia where life first emerged on Solinia. The Valley is revered even by the Gods and guarded by faithful Satyrs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;places-of-interest&#34;&gt;Places of Interest&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;xhier-thal&#34;&gt;Xhier&amp;rsquo;Thal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city of Xhier&amp;rsquo;Thal is home to the Satyrs of Elysia, here you will find churches to first prime elemental pantheon and many gods of nature. It is the embodiment of nature and is part of the main entrance into the Valley of Elysia which the Satyrs guard fearcly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the city is surrounded by forest, the wispen lights that hang from the trees light up the whole city with all manner of illuminous colours which accentuate the lush greens and earthy browns of the worlds most ancient forest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Xhier&amp;rsquo;Thal people are humble in their way of life, with tents and huts as their homes, they strive to stay as close to nature as possible but show worship through their many dances, rituals and statues of legendary satyrs, fauns, centuars and other creatures of nature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tomb-of-aataltal&#34;&gt;Tomb of Aataltal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here a sacred golden tomb lays in center of a forest, it is believed that Aataltal returned to Solinia and spent the rest of his life here in the Valley. The Satyr finally laid him to rest and placed this tomb temple here in his honour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;halistros-fall&#34;&gt;Halistros Fall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mountainous peak is the only place in the valley where life is completely absent. It is said that it is here that Halistro placed a curse on Solinia and true evil entered into the world - The Satyrs strictly forbid anyone from visiting this place&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lake-elysia&#34;&gt;Lake Elysia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holiest place on Solinia, the lake is said to glisten in the light of the moon and the magical lights of the wisps dance along its surface. Only the satyrs may drink from this lake, or on occasion the gods themselves when they return to pay homage the first&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Vale of Zhuvirae</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/vale-of-zhuvirae/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/vale-of-zhuvirae/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vale of Zhuvirae&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vale of Zhuvirae&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is written that in ages past the Gods did walk upon Solinia like the mortals of today. It is here, in the center of the land of Utra, that Zhuvirae found beauty in the untouched ancient forests and lakes that shimmered in her ever watching moon light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laying in the center of a circular mountain range and at the foot of the Dragonspine mountains, the Vale sits comfortably protected on almost all her sides. It is on the mountain range to the far west that we find Castle Blackveil, settled decades before the arrival of the Orcs and Anushi that now dominate most of Utra. The people of the Vale know to stay clear of its walls as any that have entered their territory have never returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travellers through this land will see the touch of ancient gods of nature as the fairies and nymphs of the Kingdom of Rustcap play happily and mischievously in the deepest and most ancient parts of the forest. Ever guarding the forest from those that would seek to take from her, the Rustcap people are untrusting of outsiders, particularly the Orcs to the east and Avarians and Giants to the west that are constantly encroaching on their home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is believed that deep below the land of Zhuvirae lays a great source of magical energy, which sustains the life of the fairy people that live extremely long lives in the Vale, but sadly, the horrors that lay below the forest are a perfect counter balance to the beauty you will see on its surface.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>