<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vintage Story Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Guides</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/</link><description>Recent content in Guides on Vintage Story Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Code of Conduct</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;Note: You are expected to check this page often as it will change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solinian Code of Conduct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure that all members are able to enjoy their online experience safely and freely, Solinia has established a Code of Conduct which all members (and moderators) are expected to follow. This is above and beyond the Rules. Make sure you read and understand this section well as it is the foundation upon which all our players place their stories of heroism and kinship, murder and betrayal. Above all remember those who weave these tales are real people behind the masks they choose to dawn. Have fun and do your best to help others to have fun too. Yours is not the only hero in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harmful Behavior&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members agree to not engage in behavior which interferes with other players’ enjoyment of the game. This includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staff Respect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not bug staff, if you have an issue please report it either in the support channel on discord (see our site for the discord link) or if it is a gameplay issue related to our plugin create an issue on github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mixxit/solinia3-core/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mixxit/solinia3-core/issues&lt;/a&gt; Being a staff member is difficult, draining and mostly unrewarding. Please be respectful, they work hard for this server for free. If you are being rude to them it will be classified as griefing. If a staff member asks you to stop doing something and you don&amp;rsquo;t it will be classified as griefing. If you can, just leave them alone they are most likely very busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PvP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PVP is allowed on the server but you must request consent from the player you wish to engage in combat with. You are not permitted to attack players in the spawn areas. Just use your brain, nobody wants to come to a server and be instantly attacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Griefing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disturbing other player’s property or items without their permission, including: * Breaking or placing blocks on other player’s property * Stealing items from chests owned by other players * Entering other player’s houses uninvited * Purposefully preventing players from being able to complete quests, gathering items etc. Share the game, try not to camp, agree to split the camp if necessary &lt;sup&gt;50&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt;. Note killing vendor NPCs etc are fine, just don&amp;rsquo;t do it if someone else is busy with them. If you need to kill them then ask to share the camp * Stealing or killing player animals horses animals etc. * Stealing all the loot in a group Most of this is self evident. Just think, is it yours? Would you like this done to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not permitted to access our server via a VPN or tor exit node&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Nuisance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating “traps” or placing dangerous blocks (fire, lava, etc.) in public property “Spamming” the chat with repetitive or unwanted messages Building 1x1 towers (even for your elytra) it looks horrid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harassment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Killing a player, even indirectly, outside of designated PvP RP&lt;br /&gt;Following, sending /msg messages, or otherwise harassing another player after they have asked you to stop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server Abuse / Hacking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPCs are limited in their abilities, many people cheese npcs by standing two blocks above the NPC. It is not likely to get you banned but it is frowned upon. Do not get caught doing this. Use root or whatever your equivelent is ability is. Do you really want us to make NPCs teleport to you when cant path? Attempting to gain unauthorized access to the server, otherwise restricted console commands, or using third-party tools to “hack” elevated privileges or unauthorized abilities will result in a citation. This also includes:&lt;br /&gt;Item duplication glitches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This includes causing the server to use more resources than it would normally. Such as extending the map, causing lots of entities to spawn, making use of redstone or using abilities or anything else that would cause out of the ordinary increased cpu, memory, bandwidth or storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modded clients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Other glitches and exploits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redstone, Large Animal farms, Breeding Villagers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redstone should be kept to a minimum, if you are wondering if you need permission to do something its probably too big and not permitted You may not breed villagers, use armour stands if you want an npc like creature You must keep your animal farm at an acceptable level that will not affect player frame rate or be done just for your convenience. We need the entity space for other mobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enforcement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All violations of this code of conduct will result in an instant ban with very little chance of appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are lucky you may be given a warning, at which point accept the warning and move on with your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disagreements with Staff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staff decisions are final. If you kick up a fuss about the decision a staff member has made and they have told you to drop it (and you don&amp;rsquo;t) expect a ban. If you believe a staff member is acting out of malice then please inform the owner. If the owner desides the decision was correct then deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suggested Conduct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are suggestions for interacting with other players. It would be great for everyone, regardless of rank, to take heed of these suggestions. However, for higher ranks, we recommend this even more strongly, and we might even go so far as to call this a “code of conduct” for the higher ranks, who have a responsibility to act fairly justly and above all honourably when representing the server. Be welcoming to new players, including guests. Attempt to get involved and help them in meaningful ways. Drop off some food or starter mats for people who have just gotten a pelot. Recognize positive behavior, especially good builds. Drop by and offer your compliments if they are due. Offer constructive suggestions if asked. When you see someone breaking some behavioral or other rules, please politely correct them in private via /msg. Nobody likes to be called out in public. For people who have a tendency to ask lots of questions, politely redirect them to the website rather than simply saying “website.” If applicable, give them a general idea of where to look, such as the name of the page. Make sure they feel listened too and that people are encouraged to ask any questions they may have. There is no such thing as a dumb question. If you feel you must answer (or ask!) a question that you are unsure of or is not covered on the website or the Solinia wiki, provide your best answer via /msg, or ask someone you know via /msg, rather than in global chat. We do not wish to encourage guessing at or asking these questions in global, as this can send inconsistent messages to new players&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For clear or persistent rules violations, use your judgment. Highguard Masters and Elders, provide a clear warning via private /msg if it is warranted. When necessary, mute or ban appropriately, and without drama. For other ranks, please report rules violations via /pm on our forums to a Highguard rather than any kind of public forum post. Public announcements of rules violations tend to have a negative effect on our community. PM`s are confidential between the submitter and admins.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Mod</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/mod/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/mod/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;Mod packs are now installed automatically on server join since Vintage Story 1.16, you no longer need to download them&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: New Player Guide</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/new-player-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/new-player-guide/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome&#34;&gt;Welcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have reached this page then you have probably just joined our server and are wondering how to play! First, welcome! Second, this guide is always changing so be sure to come back regularly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you arent on our server yet you can join by searching for Fall of an Empire in your in game server list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-you-need-help-this-page-cant-give&#34;&gt;When you need help this page cant give&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just ask our players in ooc with /o [your message here] - even if nobody is online it is connected to Discord so someone will likely get back to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started-wip&#34;&gt;Getting started (WIP)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;if-you-are-new-to-vintage-story&#34;&gt;If you are new to Vintage Story&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the survival guide on the Vintage Story Wiki - &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.vintagestory.at/index.php?title=Survival_Guide_-_Your_first_day&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://wiki.vintagestory.at/index.php?title=Survival_Guide_-_Your_first_day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;help&#34;&gt;HELP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any help, please ask in /ooc &lt;msg&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/v9mx3QdTPF&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;come by our discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Roleplayers Reference</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/roleplayers-reference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/roleplayers-reference/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;Note: You are expected to check this page often as it will change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see this page for additional advice regarding roleplay that is not covered in our New Players Guide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IN CHARACTER DEATH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence forth, In character deaths will be taken seriously.
&lt;strong&gt;Do not&lt;/strong&gt; agree to In character death unless you are prepared for the consequences of Revival. A Real life-time limit will be attached to an in character death. This time limit will be dependent on the Signaculum&amp;rsquo;s Validity verse the revival spell used. After the Signaculum has expired, character resurrections must be approved by an Admin via Roleplay with an action following the /pray function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resurrection Spells&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spells may be used for as long as the signaculum is valid (7 hours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resurrection after Signaculum expired [A God call]:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priests* may use /pray to call upon their chosen god(s) of worship on behalf of the deceased character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A staff member may or may not respond to the prayer of the priest. Character standings with gods will affect the chance of revival as well as the cost of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are brought back with a god call:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cost* will be determined by the God(Staff) responding, and will be required to be paid upon revival. The price will be paid to the priest god, and not that of the character being revived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRIESTS:&lt;/strong&gt; The following classes are considered Priests and are able to pray
Cleric, Paladin, Shaman, Shadow-knight&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COSTS&lt;/strong&gt; The following are examples of costs of revival and are not limited to such examples
Level(s), Item(s)
A character being revived by their own god will pay a smaller price compared to that of a character being revived by a god not of their faith.
Non-Religious characters will pay steeper prices, And Characters of opposing faiths may not receive revival at all.
A character with higher faith/worship of their god will have improved chances and lower costs of revival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Statistics</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/statistics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/statistics/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id=&#34;primary-stats&#34;&gt;Primary Stats&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no one perfect way to set up an individual character class. Much of it depends on your playing style, your preferences and the decision you make as to how you want your character to make his or her way through the world. Below are the basic descriptions of how the stats affect the characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strength-str&#34;&gt;Strength (STR)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Attack Power (see &amp;ldquo;ATK&amp;rdquo;), Bow Damage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strength is a valuable stat for melee and tank characters to increase both their max and average hit of damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stamina-sta&#34;&gt;Stamina (STA)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Hit Points (see &amp;ldquo;HP&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stamina is very valuable for tanks to increase maximum hit points. It&amp;rsquo;s also somewhat valuable to other classes for the same reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;agility-agi&#34;&gt;Agility (AGI)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agility influences the ability of an enemy to hit you. Above 75, the AC provided for each Agility is slight. Below 75 agility causes a large AC hit. For example, on a level 60 ogre SK, going from 76 to 85 AGI provides 3 AC. But going from 66 to 75 AGI provides 45 AC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dexterity-dex&#34;&gt;Dexterity (DEX)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Bard Song missed notes; Procs, Crits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This determines how often you crit with your weapons, how quickly you learn weapon and rogue skills, and how often a magic weapon will process its skill. This is a good skill to have for fighters, especially warriors, rangers, rogues and of only limited use for magic users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wisdom-wis&#34;&gt;Wisdom (WIS)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Caster mana amount (mana pool) for Clerics, Paladins, Druids, Shamans and Rangers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255
*Soft-cap: 200&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intelligence-int&#34;&gt;Intelligence (INT)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Caster mana amount (mana pool) for Necromancers, Magicians, Enchanters, Wizards, Shadowknights &amp;amp; Bards*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255
*Soft-cap: 200&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charisma-cha&#34;&gt;Charisma (CHA)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Charming (ENC/BRD only)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;secondary-stats&#34;&gt;Secondary Stats&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;armor-class-ac&#34;&gt;Armor Class (AC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armor Class as a whole is divided into two parts. The first determining how hard you get hit and the other when you will be hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the AC is &amp;ldquo;mitigation AC&amp;rdquo; which is calculated from the worn AC you gain from your gear, Defense skill, and it is assumed spells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other part of AC is the &amp;ldquo;avoidance AC&amp;rdquo; which is defined by your Defense skill and your AGI stat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max (cap): None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soft-cap (raw ac/worn ac): Level * 6 + 25 This only applies to characters level 50 or below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attack-power-atk&#34;&gt;Attack Power (ATK)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attack, is a statistic used to compare against an opponent&amp;rsquo;s AC. It is based on your Weapon Skills and Offense. While these are two parts of a whole they do differing things independently. Weapon skills will determine if you miss an opponent and Offense increases your to-hit in theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When compared against an opponent&amp;rsquo;s Mitigation AC it is further added to by the Strength stat and +ATK mods on items or from spells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max (cap): None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hit-points-hp&#34;&gt;Hit Points (HP)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes known as &amp;ldquo;health&amp;rdquo;, a player&amp;rsquo;s HP determines how much damage you can sustain before dying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max (cap): None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hit points can be increased directly through +HP gear, or indirectly through +STA gear, or temporarily through HP enhancing spells like the Cleric&amp;rsquo;s symbol line and the Shaman&amp;rsquo;s talisman line of spells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mana-mana&#34;&gt;Mana (MANA)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A player&amp;rsquo;s mana pool determines how many spells you can cast. Mana is increased directly through equipment, through WIS for priests, rangers and paladins, and through INT for casters, shadowknights and bards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max (cap): None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are Buff_Lines#Mana_Regeneration| many spells that enhance the rate of mana regeneration, which are always prized by casters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a single Enchanter line of spells that increases maximum mana directly, and another Enchanter line to increase Intelligence, as well as two spell lines which increase Wisdom, and both will increase mana indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resists&#34;&gt;Resists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A player&amp;rsquo;s resistances determine the chance for negative spells to be resisted by the player and the damage they deal. The resistance type being checked is determined by the specific spell that is being cast. Resistances can be raised or lowered through beneficial or harmful spells and certain gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The five resists types are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poison&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tertiary-statistics&#34;&gt;Tertiary statistics==&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;damage-per-second-dps&#34;&gt;Damage Per Second (DPS)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:&amp;ldquo;See also: Haste Guide&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Melee &amp;amp; Caster Damage dealt over time; Weapon Ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;weapon-ratio&#34;&gt;Weapon Ratio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: DPS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formula: (Weapon Damage / Weapon Delay) = Ratio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: (18 / 27) = 0.666 DPS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to the guys over at p99 wiki&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Voting</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/voting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/voting/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Voting page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;open-all-sites-at-once-firefox&#34;&gt;Open all sites at once [Firefox]&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; onclick=&#34;
window.open(&#39;https://www.vintagestoryservers.net/server-fall-of-an-empire-roleplay-server.15&#39;);
&#34;&gt;Click here to open all the pages below, at once&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;individual-sites&#34;&gt;Individual Sites&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vintagestoryservers.net/server-fall-of-an-empire-roleplay-server.15&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.vintagestoryservers.net/server-fall-of-an-empire-roleplay-server.15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>