<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Guides</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/</link><description>Recent content in Guides on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Code of Conduct</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;Note: You are expected to check this page often as it will change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solinian Code of Conduct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure that all members are able to enjoy their online experience safely and freely, Solinia has established a Code of Conduct which all members (and moderators) are expected to follow. This is above and beyond the Rules. Make sure you read and understand this section well as it is the foundation upon which all our players place their stories of heroism and kinship, murder and betrayal. Above all remember those who weave these tales are real people behind the masks they choose to dawn. Have fun and do your best to help others to have fun too. Yours is not the only hero in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harmful Behavior&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members agree to not engage in behavior which interferes with other players’ enjoyment of the game. This includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staff Respect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not bug staff, if you have an issue please report it either in the support channel on discord (see our site for the discord link) or if it is a gameplay issue related to our plugin create an issue on github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mixxit/solinia3-core/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mixxit/solinia3-core/issues&lt;/a&gt; Being a staff member is difficult, draining and mostly unrewarding. Please be respectful, they work hard for this server for free. If you are being rude to them it will be classified as griefing. If a staff member asks you to stop doing something and you don&amp;rsquo;t it will be classified as griefing. If you can, just leave them alone they are most likely very busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PvP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PVP is allowed on the server but you must request consent from the player you wish to engage in combat with. You are not permitted to attack players in the spawn areas. Just use your brain, nobody wants to come to a server and be instantly attacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Griefing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disturbing other player’s property or items without their permission, including: * Breaking or placing blocks on other player’s property * Stealing items from chests owned by other players * Entering other player’s houses uninvited * Purposefully preventing players from being able to complete quests, gathering items etc. Share the game, try not to camp, agree to split the camp if necessary &lt;sup&gt;50&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt;. Note killing vendor NPCs etc are fine, just don&amp;rsquo;t do it if someone else is busy with them. If you need to kill them then ask to share the camp * Stealing or killing player animals horses animals etc. * Stealing all the loot in a group Most of this is self evident. Just think, is it yours? Would you like this done to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not permitted to access our server via a VPN or tor exit node&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Nuisance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating “traps” or placing dangerous blocks (fire, lava, etc.) in public property “Spamming” the chat with repetitive or unwanted messages Building 1x1 towers (even for your elytra) it looks horrid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harassment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Killing a player, even indirectly, outside of designated PvP RP&lt;br /&gt;Following, sending /msg messages, or otherwise harassing another player after they have asked you to stop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server Abuse / Hacking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPCs are limited in their abilities, many people cheese npcs by standing two blocks above the NPC. It is not likely to get you banned but it is frowned upon. Do not get caught doing this. Use root or whatever your equivelent is ability is. Do you really want us to make NPCs teleport to you when cant path? Attempting to gain unauthorized access to the server, otherwise restricted console commands, or using third-party tools to “hack” elevated privileges or unauthorized abilities will result in a citation. This also includes:&lt;br /&gt;Item duplication glitches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This includes causing the server to use more resources than it would normally. Such as extending the map, causing lots of entities to spawn, making use of redstone or using abilities or anything else that would cause out of the ordinary increased cpu, memory, bandwidth or storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modded clients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Other glitches and exploits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redstone, Large Animal farms, Breeding Villagers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redstone should be kept to a minimum, if you are wondering if you need permission to do something its probably too big and not permitted You may not breed villagers, use armour stands if you want an npc like creature You must keep your animal farm at an acceptable level that will not affect player frame rate or be done just for your convenience. We need the entity space for other mobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enforcement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All violations of this code of conduct will result in an instant ban with very little chance of appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are lucky you may be given a warning, at which point accept the warning and move on with your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disagreements with Staff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staff decisions are final. If you kick up a fuss about the decision a staff member has made and they have told you to drop it (and you don&amp;rsquo;t) expect a ban. If you believe a staff member is acting out of malice then please inform the owner. If the owner desides the decision was correct then deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suggested Conduct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are suggestions for interacting with other players. It would be great for everyone, regardless of rank, to take heed of these suggestions. However, for higher ranks, we recommend this even more strongly, and we might even go so far as to call this a “code of conduct” for the higher ranks, who have a responsibility to act fairly justly and above all honourably when representing the server. Be welcoming to new players, including guests. Attempt to get involved and help them in meaningful ways. Drop off some food or starter mats for people who have just gotten a pelot. Recognize positive behavior, especially good builds. Drop by and offer your compliments if they are due. Offer constructive suggestions if asked. When you see someone breaking some behavioral or other rules, please politely correct them in private via /msg. Nobody likes to be called out in public. For people who have a tendency to ask lots of questions, politely redirect them to the website rather than simply saying “website.” If applicable, give them a general idea of where to look, such as the name of the page. Make sure they feel listened too and that people are encouraged to ask any questions they may have. There is no such thing as a dumb question. If you feel you must answer (or ask!) a question that you are unsure of or is not covered on the website or the Solinia wiki, provide your best answer via /msg, or ask someone you know via /msg, rather than in global chat. We do not wish to encourage guessing at or asking these questions in global, as this can send inconsistent messages to new players&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For clear or persistent rules violations, use your judgment. Highguard Masters and Elders, provide a clear warning via private /msg if it is warranted. When necessary, mute or ban appropriately, and without drama. For other ranks, please report rules violations via /pm on our forums to a Highguard rather than any kind of public forum post. Public announcements of rules violations tend to have a negative effect on our community. PM`s are confidential between the submitter and admins.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Mod</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/mod/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/mod/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;You can now install our modpack via this page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technicpack.net/modpack/fall-of-an-empire-server.1690920&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.technicpack.net/modpack/fall-of-an-empire-server.1690920&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: New Player Guide</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/new-player-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/new-player-guide/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome&#34;&gt;Welcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have reached this page then you have probably just joined our server and are wondering how to play! First, welcome! Second, this guide is always changing so be sure to come back regularly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you arent on our server yet you can join: play.fallofanempire.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-you-need-help-this-page-cant-give&#34;&gt;When you need help this page cant give&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just ask our players in ooc with /o [your message here] - even if nobody is online it is connected to Discord so someone will likely get back to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-map&#34;&gt;Our Map&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Utra! Your new home for your time visiting us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/img/Utra.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;picking-a-class-and-race&#34;&gt;Picking a class and race&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you will be hit with is the race/character selection screen. This is very comprehensive if you have our mod, if not it will fall back on a basic book selection system. Do not worry about what you pick, you can always change your character later by just typing /opencharactercreation again (there is a min time wait of 15 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a bit more background information on Playable races and classes see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/classes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Classes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/races/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Races&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have picked your race and class you will need to decide which type of player you are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-types-of-play&#34;&gt;Two Types of Play&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We currently cater for two types of players, Roleplayers and RPG players!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For roleplayers, which is mainly socialisation and creative building - you will simple be able to get straight to it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For adventurers/rpg players, its a bit more complicated as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/mod&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;you need to install our Mod&lt;/a&gt; for the best type of play (it has target bars, spell systems, pet controls, auto attack that wasnt possible with just a plugin)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-resource-pack&#34;&gt;Our resource pack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a resource pack that is a customised version of Conquest. It lets you see custom appearance items we use for classes. You dont have to have it, but really its very beautiful if you do. You can download it here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the Resource Pack from &lt;a href=&#34;https://solinia.blob.core.windows.net/solinia-public/solinia3-resourcepack.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://solinia.blob.core.windows.net/solinia-public/solinia3-resourcepack.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;paths&#34;&gt;Paths&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-a-choice&#34;&gt;Make a choice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below we will go into more detail of the two types of players. If you are not interested in building or roleplaying, you can skip straight to adventuring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;roleplaying-path&#34;&gt;Roleplaying Path&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro-1&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a roleplayer, you will have dropped straight onto our mob free building zone in a small village with some npcs and a boat. Getting close to any NPC and right clicking will target it. Type HAIL to introduce yourself to the npc. Any words it says in purple you can type back to it. Some npcs have shops you can access by typing SHOP or bankers with BANK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-in-our-world&#34;&gt;Building in our World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area you start out in is made specifically for player building. Just walk a little beyond the npc area and you will find you can break blocks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large portion of our map is reserved for world content and we have several locations earmarked for public builds. You can protect these areas with towny. However, if you would prefer to live somewhere else that is protected, please give our staff a shout on discord and we will open up any area of the world so long as it doesnt affect roleplay, npc content or aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;world-setting&#34;&gt;World Setting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are able to see the specific date you are in by typing /today in chat and the name of the day and date will come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day and night cycles on Solinia are roughly ¼ that of a Real life one (24hrs) This is very useful for Roleplaying effectively and Remembering Births/Deaths too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current content setting is Utra, within the The Severed Isles, you can find more information about this region of the world by clicking here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/locations/the-severed-isles/utra-sacred/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are also able to see map of the Severed Isles and your location on it, by going onto the website and clicking dynmap &lt;a href=&#34;http://play.fallofanempire.com:8123/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://play.fallofanempire.com:8123/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deities&#34;&gt;Deities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of roleplay, please see our gods - You can set the god you worship with /setgod &lt;a href=&#34;../../gods&#34;&gt;Gods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-to-stay-in-character&#34;&gt;Try to stay in character&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When roleplaying try not to break out of character, we know it’s not possible to stop this, so when you need to break out of character just put two brackets before and after your message eg &amp;ldquo;(( Sorry guys, I got to go in 10 minutes ))&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo; I’ve to go in 10 minutes &amp;rdquo; ( in character ). Alternatively use /ooc command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;racial-languages&#34;&gt;Racial languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each race of Solinia speak a unique language that cannot be understood by foreigners. By default your character will speak your racial tongue in /local RP chat As you hear more of another racial tongue you will eventually be able to understand it and even speak it by toggling your racial tongue with the /language command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Languages augment roleplay and allow unique tense scenarios where players of another land may not understand the secret words you are saying to your allies - get out there and travel the lands to learn more of them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;emote&#34;&gt;Emote!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also when physically doing something in roleplay use an emote to perform your action ie: /me picks up the empty vase, and inspects it closely&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;leave-it-up-to-random&#34;&gt;Leave it up to random!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the /dice to add some randomness to your roleplay&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consult-the-gods&#34;&gt;Consult the gods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tarot has guided the kings of Solinia for as long as they have existed. Leave your decisions up to the /tarot command next time you have to decide something difficult&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-players&#34;&gt;Finding Players&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also see all players online with the command /who all&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-money-without-adventuring&#34;&gt;Making money without adventuring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can sell vanilla minecraft items at any vendor of these types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COAL_ORE
GOLD_ORE
GOLD_INGOT
GOLD_BLOCK
IRON_INGOT
IRON_ORE
IRON_BLOCK
DIAMOND_ORE
DIAMOND
DIAMOND_BLOCK
LAPIS_ORE
LAPIS_BLOCK
REDSTONE_ORE
REDSTONE
REDSTONE_BLOCK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With inspiraton points you can also buy things from the /inspiration shop which you can sell for money! See the /inspiration command and its subcommands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;protecting-an-area&#34;&gt;Protecting an area&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot build in the town area of the npcs, but walk enough out and you will find the rest of the island is available for use (that other players havent claimed)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can build and protect an area using towny. Towny requires money which you can either get from other players, take up the Adventuring Path or simple vote for our server in /inspiration sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-and-player-cities&#34;&gt;Building and Player Cities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Fall of an Empire, the world is divided into two types of areas: Player Build Areas and Campaign Areas. You cannot build or destroy in Campaign Areas but players are welcome to build whatever they like in the player areas, so long as it follows the server rules To protect the environment from griefing and managing abandoned areas, players must purchase any land they wish to build or destroy on. For this we use towny (see below) Although anyone can create an area for themselves in a player build area, we recommend all payers join an already established town to facilitate RP. However, if you are a hermit type, you can pay the fee of $500 to purchase a town with the /town create command You can find player build areas on our dynmap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;establishing-a-new-town&#34;&gt;Establishing a new Town&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create your own town you need to be in the Wilderness. That’s anywhere where a town doesn’t exist already. When you walk around it will say ~Wilderness This means you are standing in a chunk that is currently unoccupied. To found your town there you can use this command /town new Townname This will establish a town at your position assuming you have the money to pay for it. The size of the town will start out at 16x16 blocks wide and all the way from bedrock to the sky. To keep your town you need to pay Upkeep this is important to remember and you can see the prices using the towny prices command /towny prices To deposit money into your town bank so your upkeep continues to be paid daily use the /town deposit command &lt;em&gt;Run out of money in your town bank and your town will fall&lt;/em&gt; /town deposit amount You can also see the balance of your town bank with /town or /t&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inviting-new-residents-to-your-town&#34;&gt;Inviting new Residents to your town&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To invite others to your town, you can use the command /town invite [name] Once the player joins they will be a member of your town and will show on the town resident list on /town&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;extending-your-town&#34;&gt;Extending your town&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can extend your town by standing in an adjacent ~WildLand area and typing /town claim Prices are shown on the /towny prices command - you can also extend your town in large chunks with /town claim rect amount Which claims area around your town at a distance of ‘amount’ If you want to claim a plot that is not adjacent to your town will need to be claimed as an outpost, these are more expensive and are shown on /towny prices /town claim outpost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;marking-your-town-plots-for-sale&#34;&gt;Marking your town plots for sale&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to sell plots for your residents in your town you can stand in an area and do forsale command /plot forsale [AMOUNT] Where amount is the price you want to sell the plot for You can unlist it for sale with /plot notforsale Residents can buy plots with /plot claim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;adventuring-path&#34;&gt;Adventuring Path&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro-2&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you need to find an npc called Adventurer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find him outside the tavern in the starting area&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right click him to target him&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now type HAIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He will introduce himself and offer you options in purple text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say those words back to him (Ie say: I am an adventurer) - This will then teleport you to the adventuring tutorial (or tell you that you are missing the mod)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you forgot to install the mod, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/mod&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;you need to install our Mod&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have trouble with installing it, feel free to ask in /o &lt;your message here&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-to-grips-with-the-adventuring-tutorial&#34;&gt;Getting to Grips with the Adventuring Tutorial&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because our server is so different you might need help getting started with the change in the interface. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/tutorialfortutorial/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;See our Tutorial for the Tutorial page&lt;/a&gt; for a complete step by step guide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statistics&#34;&gt;Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;../Statistics&#34;&gt;Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;targetting-yourself-for-spells&#34;&gt;Targetting yourself for Spells&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To target yourself please see your keybinds, by default this is ctrl - 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will see your name in the target area on the right&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clearing-your-target&#34;&gt;Clearing your target&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To clear your target please see your keybinds, by default this is ctrl - ¬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spell-reagents&#34;&gt;Spell Reagents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some spells require reagents which you can get from drops and shops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold the reagent in your hand when in the inventory window and drop it onto the reagent button in the top right corner of the screen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively you can type /reagent add&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various vendors in cities spell reagents for spells. Some powerful or rare spells may require mob drops for the reagents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bind-wound&#34;&gt;Bind Wound*&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players can bind their wounds with an abiliy from a level 1 vendor. This requires bandages in your /reagent pouch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gear&#34;&gt;Gear&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scattered among the various merchants and lost dungeons of solinia lay many forgotten items of power which increase player statistics and grant unique bonuses that players cannot find elsewhere such as spell resistances and mana regeneration Items and weapons often can only be used by specific players so be sure to inspect the item before purchasing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some items slot into special equipment slots that display on the right side of your inventory window&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remove items from your equipment slots you can right click the slot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to earn starter gear is via the medallion quests found outside most taverns in npc cities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skills&#34;&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each class provides a number of Skills for your character to learn using /skills Skills range from language to magic and melee skills and affect how various mechanics work in Fall of an Empire. These are generally damage modifiers, resists and other passive &amp;lsquo;always on&amp;rsquo; effects. Skills have a limited value that generally is determined by your level and for resists can be raised by certain special items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abilities-and-spells&#34;&gt;Abilities and Spells&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abilities and Spells are items that can be found in game that look like enchanted books. There are hundreds of abilities that have all manner of effects from beneficial to destructive or even utility. Abilities can be purchased from most Profession Guilds in large NPC cities, special abilities can also be found on monsters throughout the world and hidden vendors scattered around Solinia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use an ability you will need to drop the spell book into your spell button in the top right of your inventory. Once it is in your spellbook you can open the spellbook with the K keybind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spells can be chosen and placed into memorisation slots at hte top of your screen by left clicking on the spell and left clicking on a memorisation slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can quick cast these spells by default with ALT-1 ALT-2 ALT-3 etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the right of the screen you will notice you have a TARGET:. Targets can be selected by right clicking an npc or palyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note some abilities require a target where as others, such as area of effect will target yourself automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abilities require Mana/Power which can be found at the top of your screen. You can regenerate mana by standing still or wearing mana regen items. You can also buy potions, get special buffs from other players or stand in a regen pool or area. Items with statistics on them such as INT, WIS or AGI depending on your profession&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pet-classes&#34;&gt;Pet Classes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some pets require reagents, such as bone chips to summon your skeleton pet or malachite to summon a magician pet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put these in your reagent pouch with /reagent add or drop the reagents onto the reagent icon in the top right corner of your inventory screen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make your pet attack another mob, first target the mob with right click. Then use the keybind for Pet Attack (default R) to send your pet in. You can also control this with /pet attack and stop attack with /pet back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another useful command is /pet equip to destroy the item you are holding and give it to your pet, this can make your pet very powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See more info on your pet with the /pet command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternative-advancement&#34;&gt;Alternative Advancement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a player reaches level 50 they are able to access the /toggleaa command. This will begin siphoning all experience gained into alternative advancement which will reward points that can be spent on new character powers in the /AA command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAs can massively increase a players power far beyond what tradition levels can and allows players to keep progressing their character despite reaching maximum level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;earning-money-through-adventuring&#34;&gt;Earning money through adventuring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fall of an empire uses its own internal economy plugins to allow players to interact with merchant NPC&amp;rsquo;s to sell and buy items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like with NPC quests, right click NPC&amp;rsquo;s which are buying or selling items and type SHOP and they will list everything they are interested in trading Click on each item you wish to buy or sell to complete a transaction. For example click an item in your inventory at the bottom and click it on the top merchant inventory to sell it. NPCs only buy &amp;lsquo;adventuring items&amp;rsquo; not raw minecraft items (for economic control reasons)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Killing mobs is a great way to make money if you are just starting off or alternatively buy items off the /inspiration shop and sell them for $500 each. You can gain inspiration once a day from voting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check your balance at any time use the command /balance or /bal You can also pay other players using the /pay command with /pay playername amount&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parties&#34;&gt;Parties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also create a group to talk to players in any distance by using the /group command and /g &lt;msg&gt; to send a message Groups also allow you to earn experience with your fellow heroes as well as monitor their hit points You can invite players to your party with /group invite and list all players in your party with /group list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;travel&#34;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting around isn’t easy, so we recommend using &lt;a href=&#34;http://play.fallofanempire.com:8123&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://play.fallofanempire.com:8123&lt;/a&gt; while travelling long distances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At most major cities you can find a Travelling Denko npc which can ride you to another town for a low cost (see their shop)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, travel with friends where possible and be sure to grab a saddle from a Horse Vendor and use a steed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the journey is a long one, stock up on rations so you don&amp;rsquo;t get stuck in the wild with no food or find a friendly druid and wizard who can teleport you to various locations around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;map-of-the-world&#34;&gt;Map of the World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://play.fallofanempire.com:8123&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://play.fallofanempire.com:8123&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;anything-else&#34;&gt;Anything else&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;help&#34;&gt;HELP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any help, please ask in /ooc &lt;msg&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/4FYXka5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;come by our discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Roleplayers Reference</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/roleplayers-reference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/roleplayers-reference/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;Note: You are expected to check this page often as it will change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see this page for additional advice regarding roleplay that is not covered in our New Players Guide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IN CHARACTER DEATH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence forth, In character deaths will be taken seriously.
&lt;strong&gt;Do not&lt;/strong&gt; agree to In character death unless you are prepared for the consequences of Revival. A Real life-time limit will be attached to an in character death. This time limit will be dependent on the Signaculum&amp;rsquo;s Validity verse the revival spell used. After the Signaculum has expired, character resurrections must be approved by an Admin via Roleplay with an action following the /pray function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resurrection Spells&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spells may be used for as long as the signaculum is valid (7 hours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resurrection after Signaculum expired [A God call]:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priests* may use /pray to call upon their chosen god(s) of worship on behalf of the deceased character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A staff member may or may not respond to the prayer of the priest. Character standings with gods will affect the chance of revival as well as the cost of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are brought back with a god call:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cost* will be determined by the God(Staff) responding, and will be required to be paid upon revival. The price will be paid to the priest god, and not that of the character being revived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRIESTS:&lt;/strong&gt; The following classes are considered Priests and are able to pray
Cleric, Paladin, Shaman, Shadow-knight&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COSTS&lt;/strong&gt; The following are examples of costs of revival and are not limited to such examples
Level(s), Item(s)
A character being revived by their own god will pay a smaller price compared to that of a character being revived by a god not of their faith.
Non-Religious characters will pay steeper prices, And Characters of opposing faiths may not receive revival at all.
A character with higher faith/worship of their god will have improved chances and lower costs of revival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Statistics</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/statistics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/statistics/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id=&#34;primary-stats&#34;&gt;Primary Stats&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no one perfect way to set up an individual character class. Much of it depends on your playing style, your preferences and the decision you make as to how you want your character to make his or her way through the world. Below are the basic descriptions of how the stats affect the characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strength-str&#34;&gt;Strength (STR)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Attack Power (see &amp;ldquo;ATK&amp;rdquo;), Bow Damage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strength is a valuable stat for melee and tank characters to increase both their max and average hit of damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stamina-sta&#34;&gt;Stamina (STA)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Hit Points (see &amp;ldquo;HP&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stamina is very valuable for tanks to increase maximum hit points. It&amp;rsquo;s also somewhat valuable to other classes for the same reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;agility-agi&#34;&gt;Agility (AGI)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agility influences the ability of an enemy to hit you. Above 75, the AC provided for each Agility is slight. Below 75 agility causes a large AC hit. For example, on a level 60 ogre SK, going from 76 to 85 AGI provides 3 AC. But going from 66 to 75 AGI provides 45 AC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dexterity-dex&#34;&gt;Dexterity (DEX)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Bard Song missed notes; Procs, Crits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This determines how often you crit with your weapons, how quickly you learn weapon and rogue skills, and how often a magic weapon will process its skill. This is a good skill to have for fighters, especially warriors, rangers, rogues and of only limited use for magic users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wisdom-wis&#34;&gt;Wisdom (WIS)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Caster mana amount (mana pool) for Clerics, Paladins, Druids, Shamans and Rangers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255
*Soft-cap: 200&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intelligence-int&#34;&gt;Intelligence (INT)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Caster mana amount (mana pool) for Necromancers, Magicians, Enchanters, Wizards, Shadowknights &amp;amp; Bards*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255
*Soft-cap: 200&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charisma-cha&#34;&gt;Charisma (CHA)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Charming (ENC/BRD only)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Max (hard-cap): 255&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;secondary-stats&#34;&gt;Secondary Stats&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;armor-class-ac&#34;&gt;Armor Class (AC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armor Class as a whole is divided into two parts. The first determining how hard you get hit and the other when you will be hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the AC is &amp;ldquo;mitigation AC&amp;rdquo; which is calculated from the worn AC you gain from your gear, Defense skill, and it is assumed spells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other part of AC is the &amp;ldquo;avoidance AC&amp;rdquo; which is defined by your Defense skill and your AGI stat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max (cap): None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soft-cap (raw ac/worn ac): Level * 6 + 25 This only applies to characters level 50 or below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attack-power-atk&#34;&gt;Attack Power (ATK)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attack, is a statistic used to compare against an opponent&amp;rsquo;s AC. It is based on your Weapon Skills and Offense. While these are two parts of a whole they do differing things independently. Weapon skills will determine if you miss an opponent and Offense increases your to-hit in theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When compared against an opponent&amp;rsquo;s Mitigation AC it is further added to by the Strength stat and +ATK mods on items or from spells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max (cap): None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hit-points-hp&#34;&gt;Hit Points (HP)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes known as &amp;ldquo;health&amp;rdquo;, a player&amp;rsquo;s HP determines how much damage you can sustain before dying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max (cap): None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hit points can be increased directly through +HP gear, or indirectly through +STA gear, or temporarily through HP enhancing spells like the Cleric&amp;rsquo;s symbol line and the Shaman&amp;rsquo;s talisman line of spells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mana-mana&#34;&gt;Mana (MANA)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A player&amp;rsquo;s mana pool determines how many spells you can cast. Mana is increased directly through equipment, through WIS for priests, rangers and paladins, and through INT for casters, shadowknights and bards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max (cap): None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are Buff_Lines#Mana_Regeneration| many spells that enhance the rate of mana regeneration, which are always prized by casters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a single Enchanter line of spells that increases maximum mana directly, and another Enchanter line to increase Intelligence, as well as two spell lines which increase Wisdom, and both will increase mana indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resists&#34;&gt;Resists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A player&amp;rsquo;s resistances determine the chance for negative spells to be resisted by the player and the damage they deal. The resistance type being checked is determined by the specific spell that is being cast. Resistances can be raised or lowered through beneficial or harmful spells and certain gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The five resists types are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poison&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tertiary-statistics&#34;&gt;Tertiary statistics==&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;damage-per-second-dps&#34;&gt;Damage Per Second (DPS)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:&amp;ldquo;See also: Haste Guide&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: Melee &amp;amp; Caster Damage dealt over time; Weapon Ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;weapon-ratio&#34;&gt;Weapon Ratio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affects: DPS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formula: (Weapon Damage / Weapon Delay) = Ratio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: (18 / 27) = 0.666 DPS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to the guys over at p99 wiki&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Tutorial for Tutorial</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/tutorialfortutorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/tutorialfortutorial/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;Since the tutorial is for Adventurers, this guide will assume you have spoke to the Adventurer NPC and entered the Tutorial&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide is for new players who are struggling with the tutorial&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must have the MOD to complete this guide &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/mod/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/mod/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the signs before reading this guide as they contain more information that may help you understand more about game
This guide is solely for the actions required to complete the tutorial and nothing more
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Walk to the NPC and right click over them, the npc will be highlighted white and show in your target window on the right of your screen
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Press the H button to highlight them or type HAIL
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
The npc will send a message to you, and you can ask them questions about words that are in pink, type back to the npc
what is my purpose
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
The npc will now give you more text based on your question, ask them further questions about the new pink words
What is my own world
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Again ask more about the Pink words
Who is the betrayer
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
 
Ask her more about how to undo what she has done
How do I undo what she has done
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic7.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Tell her
I will go back to my reality
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic8.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
You have now been teleported to the next area of the tutorial
 
Find the NPC Loa and Hail her by targeting her and pressing H or typing hail
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic9.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Ask her about the realm
What realm
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic10.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Loa would like you to look through her SHOP and see if you can find the book that is about the world you come from
The book you are expected to give her is Solinia
 
Target Loa and type SHOP to open the shop interface
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic11.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Left click on the Solina book and then left click it on the bottom area, you will buy the book
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic12.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
You can now close the shop window with escape
Now hail Loa again and you will receive a line that says you can give her the book, click on this line
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic13.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Once you give her the line she will send you to a different NPC which will help you recover your strength
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic14.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Hail Great Gish by targeting him and pressing H (or type Hail)
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic15.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
He is expecting you to bring a tribute, go around the corner and find the NPC and kill it. Bring his head back to Gish
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic16.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
To attack an NPC you will need to right click the NPC so he is in your target window, you can toggle auto attack with the Z button by default (see your keybinds)
 
Auto attack the Bullywug until he dies and give you a head
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic17.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic18.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Hail Great Gish and give him the Bullgwug head by clicking on the yellow line
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic19.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Tell great gish
I will continue on my path
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic21.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
He will now send you to an NPC who will help you learn magic to return home
Head to the NPC named Cailleach in the center of the room
Target her and hail her
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic22.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Ask her about simple thing to begin with
Say
What simple thing
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic23.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
She now tells you to buy a spell from her shop
Target her and say shop to open the shop window
Left click the throw stone spell and left click it into your inventory at the bottom
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic24.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic25.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Now you have the spell you will need to store it in your spellbook
Open your inventory and Pick up the spell
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic26.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Drop the spell into the spell book in the top right
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic27.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic28.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
 
Now close your inventory and open your spellbook with the K button
You will see one spell in your spell book
You will need to memorise your spell to use it. You can memorise up to 8 spells at once
Left click the spell you want to memorise
Now left click on one of the 1-8 slots
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic29.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
It will now appear in your top left for you to quick cast with ALT-1 to ALT-8
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic30.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
 
Now target one of the Elemental Minions and press ALT-1 or the appropriate number for the slot you chose to memorise the spell in
You will see the casting bar on the right go up and the npc will be hit by a spell
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic31.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
The spell is a low damage spell so you may find auto attacking easier to kill the NPC
Once the NPC is dead he will drop an elemental head
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic32.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Go back to Cailleach and give her the head by targeting her, hailing her then clicking the give button
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic33.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
 
Cailleach will now give you a spell
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic34.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Add the spell to your spellbook
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic35.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic36.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Memorise it as before
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic37.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
 
Target yourself with CTRL-1
Cast the spell with ALT-8 or whatever spell slot number you placed it in to leave the tutorial and start the main game
Note you will see the casting bar on the right slowly casting the spell
&lt;img src=&#34;https://fallofanempire.com/img/pic38.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Voting</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/voting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/guides/voting/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Voting page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;open-all-sites-at-once-firefox&#34;&gt;Open all sites at once [Firefox]&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; onclick=&#34;
window.open(&#39;https://www.planetminecraft.com/server/fall-of-an-empire-heavyrp/vote/&#39;);
window.open(&#39;https://minecraft-mp.com/server/118059/vote/&#39;);
window.open(&#39;https://minecraftlist.org/vote/5962&#39;);
window.open(&#39;http://minecraftservers.org/vote/464284&#39;);
window.open(&#39;https://minecraft-server.net/vote/fallofanempire&#39;);
window.open(&#39;http://minecraft-server-list.com/server/345651/vote/&#39;);
window.open(&#39;http://www.minecraft-servers-list.org/index.php?a=in&#39;);
window.open(&#39;https://minebrowse.com/server/364&#39;);
window.open(&#39;https://topminecraftservers.org/vote/11735&#39;);
&#34;&gt;Click here to open all the pages below, at once&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;individual-sites&#34;&gt;Individual Sites&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.planetminecraft.com/server/fall-of-an-empire-heavyrp/vote/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.planetminecraft.com/server/fall-of-an-empire-heavyrp/vote/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://topminecraftservers.org/vote/11735&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://topminecraftservers.org/vote/11735&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://minecraft-mp.com/server/118059/vote/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://minecraft-mp.com/server/118059/vote/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://minecraftlist.org/vote/5962&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://minecraftlist.org/vote/5962&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://minecraftservers.org/vote/464284&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://minecraftservers.org/vote/464284&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://minecraft-server.net/vote/fallofanempire&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://minecraft-server.net/vote/fallofanempire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://minecraft-server-list.com/server/345651/vote/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://minecraft-server-list.com/server/345651/vote/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.minecraft-servers-list.org/index.php?a=in&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.minecraft-servers-list.org/index.php?a=in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://minebrowse.com/server/364&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://minebrowse.com/server/364&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>