<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Items</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/</link><description>Recent content in Items on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Aegis</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/aegis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/aegis/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aegis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Aegis is a legandary shield gifted to Sigurd by Gias, the Goddess of Earth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said that this powerful shield was made from the material of the Plane of Earth itself&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Blade of Ashiri</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/blade-of-ashiri/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/blade-of-ashiri/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blade of Ashiri&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Ashri Blade is a legendary artifact which was split into many shards, in ages past. From the start of the modern era, it is believed to have been wielded by the Euesebian mythological character Ashri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For centuries, the most knowledgeable scholars have studied the texts that speak of this blade but few have located and studied any of it&amp;rsquo;s components. Although its whereabouts are currently unknown, throughout history it has appeared in stories and tales of many different races&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of it&amp;rsquo;s mythological status some believe it to be a fantasy but those in possession of these shards know the truth. It is far from a legend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vishim travelled to Taon centuries ago seeking the blade after studying Meroei texts though no one is sure if they were successful in their endevour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment of the blade is still in the possession of the Chunel who pass this item from leader to leader as a symbol of power and respect to their ancestor Eshu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appearances&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eusebian Tales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ashri Blades first appearance is in the early writing of eusebian scholars which tell of the theft of the Ashri Blade.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Blooddawn, the Iconoclasm</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/blooddawn-the-iconoclasm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/blooddawn-the-iconoclasm/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blooddawn, the Iconoclasm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Blooddawn, the Iconoclasm, is a legendary blade used in the last days of the City of Esoron, wielded by General Drixdr of the armies of Hiran Asura.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is now held by Carith Faroth, who attempts to assist in the destruction of the High Patheon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Crown of Andvari</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/the-crown-of-advari/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/the-crown-of-advari/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dusted Tome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Crown of Andvari has been the subject of many Eusebian legends and is said to have granted it’s wearer vast riches beyond their imagination and tonight the Scholars of the libraries of Landing have brought this topic to the table once more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Gentlemen, I wish to bring to you information regarding the Crown of Andvari based on the following…’ the old scholar clears his throat and slams open an ancient and creaky tome as he begins to read out loud ‘And here did I look over my now burning kingdoms, had I known I would have left that cursed crown in the pyramid where I found it, for vast riches has it brought me but only chaos has it sown amongst my people. Only now do I realise how paranoid I had become in those days – each night scared even my closest friends would take it from me. My people of …’ the scholar speaks loudly, as if making a point of the next words ‘Tawis Karon’ will return to their humble roots and be rid of this lust for wealth and power’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scholar closes the book, and coughs heavily, years of Kumari Perique taking it’s toll on him ‘And so we see mention of the island we now stand – I conclude that, solely for the purposes of research and confirmation of this myth, that we begin our search for this crown at once’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aged oracle and scholars look amongst each other and nod, the search would begin tonight&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Dusted Tome</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/dusted-tome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/dusted-tome/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dusted Tome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
This dusted tomb contains the religious teaching of Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul and the origins of the Caerthian empire - you notice a particular piece of text of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XI.II
THE FORGOTTEN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saint X&amp;rsquo;Lron rose before the crowd baking below the glorious eye of our protector Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Let it be known to all of our Kin! We, the blessed of he, once spanned the forgotten lands of the east in the time of the sixteenth dynasty of Ra&amp;rsquo;Ern - children of the sun we once were but the green lands of the lower men we had conquered, bringing the light of him to all people of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the frontier our people rose great cities with cathedrals that stretched into the skies. So wonderous were our icons brought the attention of the lesser god of shadow who spoke of our unstoppable devotion to all that is right in the eyes of Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He spoke at length of a challenge that lay before our people that was so great the very fabric of the planes could crumble should we not intervene on behalf of our lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There at the gates of Cal&amp;rsquo;Drin did the shadow being grant life etern&amp;hellip;. &amp;lsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The rest of the rest of the page appears to be missing]&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: The Ashri Blade</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/the-ashri-blade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/the-ashri-blade/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ashri Blade&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The Ashri Blade is a legendary artifact from the start of the modern era believed to have been wielded by the Euesebian mythological character Ashri&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ashri Blades first appearance is in the early writing of eusebian scholars which tell of the theft of the Ashri Blade from the proto humans&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ashri Blade is a legendary artifact which was split into many shards, in ages past. From the start of the modern era, it is believed to have been wielded by the Euesebian mythological character Ashri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For centuries, the most knowledgeable scholars have studied the texts that speak of this blade but few have located and studied any of it&amp;rsquo;s components. Although its whereabouts are currently unknown, throughout history it has appeared in stories and tales of many different races&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of it&amp;rsquo;s mythological status some believe it to be a fantasy but those in possession of these shards know the truth. It is far from a legend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vishim travelled to Taon centuries ago seeking the blade after studying Meroei texts though no one is sure if they were successful in their endevour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment of the blade is still in the possession of the Chunel who pass this item from leader to leader as a symbol of power and respect to their ancestor Eshu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appearances Eusebian Tales The Ashri Blades first appearance is in the early writing of eusebian scholars which tell of the theft of the Ashri Blade.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Throne of Val`Elsir</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/throne-of-valelsir/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/items/throne-of-valelsir/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throne of Val`Elsir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A legendary seat of power for the Sanguine Kingdom of Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The throne is believed to have originally sat in the throne hall of Cal&amp;rsquo;Drin&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>