<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire – Notable NPCs</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/</link><description>Recent content in Notable NPCs on Minecraft Roleplay Server - Fall of an Empire</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Adelita</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/adelita/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/adelita/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adelita&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A famous ruler mentioned in the Poem of Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Akakios</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/akakios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/akakios/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akakios&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A mythological villain mentioned in the Poem of Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Alpha</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/alpha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/alpha/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A famous Hero mentioned in the Poem of Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Asag</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/asag/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/asag/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Asag is spoken of frequently in Gialon texts as the &amp;lsquo;serpent betrayer&amp;rsquo; that would join them in battle and made home for centuries at the sumit of Nasudana&amp;rsquo;s steep mountains far above the Temple of Syfyr. Interestingly, Asag is also mentioned in Half Dragon texts as being the destroyer of Python. From rudimentary art found of the dragon it appears this dragon was either diseased or cursed or possibly a poison elemental dragon. Betrayer Connecting the dots, some scholars believe that Asag was once banished from the western continents by the dragons and made his new home in the land of Nasudana. Whether or not he returned to save his homeland during the attacks by Python is unknown as it is difficult to place these events chronologically. He was either banished before Python or after&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Ashri Loviatar</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/ashri-loviatar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/ashri-loviatar/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashri Loviatar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Ashri is a legendary female early eusebian Hero believed to have existed during the Modern Era. She is said to have been a member of the House of Loviatar during the time of Proto Human dominance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashri was due to be wedded to Sabe Alexander before his assassination&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She led an uprising against the Proto Humans and stole a powerful weapon which took her name as The Ashri Blade&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is known of Ashri is that her campaign was extremely successful and had a long lasting effect on the Proto Human Empire&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Celudar</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/celudar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/celudar/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celudar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The great ice dragon Celudar was a legendary artisan of the city of Tarakan it was said she had a gift of visions of the future and would often craft items for lesser kin so that great dangerous could be averted&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Enoch</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/enoch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/enoch/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enoch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A famous Hero from Alcor mentioned in the Poem of Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Eshu</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/eshu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/eshu/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eshu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Eshu was a Chunel Slave that led a rebellion against the Oshira slavemasters freeing the Gialon and Chunel Eshu is known to have carried a shard of the Blade of Ashri during this campaign which is carried by the chief of the leading tribe to this day. The Blade was recovered from the heart of the entombed Mysmaal King which gave her the strength to lead the rebellion Eshu is a legendary Heroic Figure to the Chunel and some Gialon&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Ghufran</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/ghufran/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/ghufran/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghufran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A famous hero of ages past mentioned in the Poem of Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Hiran Asura</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/hiran-asura/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/hiran-asura/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiran Asura&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Hiran Asura was once a form of Angel known as Tinai that populated the planet in it’s earliest days when the Gods still roamed the lands. It is known that Hiran was granted high office as overseer of one of the many Tinai cities that surrounded the earth in those early days and was unique in that he and his brother were one of the few male Tinai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under Hiran Asura’s rule his people flourished and were known as some of the greatest followers of the God Methabeht until an event which would change life on Solinia forever. A being, known now to be named Kali or ‘The Weaver’ was drawn to the magic and ever growing life of Solinia and began to sow seeds of chaos and destruction among its people. One of these was the possession of another Tinai ruler who was convinced to turn away from the teachings of Methabeht and follow another, it was this ruler who we know murdered Hiran Asura’s brother and claimed his land for his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tinai had never experienced any such ruthlessness and evil and were unsure how to proceed but Hiran Asura demanded vengeance. It is known that this began the fall of Hiran Asura and the initiation as the events that we know to be the Cataclysm and the ending of the Mythological Age. Hiran Asura challenged this fallen king and a battle ensued for weeks. Failing to possess the boons that his nemesis had aquired through the worshipping of gods other than Methabeht Hiran Asura’s rage only increased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was then here at his weakest moment did The Weaver appear to him, promising him the powers to defeat his rival. She promised him that through the destruction of the lesser gods he could absorb their power and gain access to planar abilities far greater than his rival could ever imagine and when his task was complete and his enemy defeated he would hold such dominion over the very forces of the universe he could bring back his lost brother and restore the life he had once known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corrupted by his hatred and dispair at defeat Hiran Asura handed his life over to the Weaver and his destruction of the Gods that once walked on the lands of Solinia began. The World was devastated during his battles with the gods and the innocent younger races were permanently erased at the hands of Hiran. Some races fled to The Under and others, such as the Tinai, who fought valiantly but eventually were forced to flee the planet completely. An entire pantheon of Gods were slain by Hiran Asura and the power he began to contain erased nearly all of the man he had once been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to the time that the last of the Gods stood before him the Weaver finally presented herself and explained her treachery and her possession of the Tinai she had used to butcher Hiran’s sibling. The Lesser Gods no longer stood in her way and the unique properties of Solinia would now be at her disposal and none could stand before her except the elements. She cursed Hiran Asura to forever be sealed within a tomb that no living creature could enter, to be tormented by his lust for power and foolish destruction of all life on Solinia. Till his misery was so great she would use his power against the four elemental gods and finally claim the domain over the unique world of Solinia&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: King Zuriel</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/king-zuriel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/king-zuriel/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King Zuriel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Dead ruler of the now Ruins of Zuriel&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Leonidas</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/leonidas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/leonidas/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leonidas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A famous Hero from Alcor mentioned in the Poem of Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Morgana Vex</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/morgana-vex/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/morgana-vex/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morgana Vex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Queen Morgan Vex has supplanted the Throne of Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir and is engaged in a civil war with her husban King Tullan Vex She is an original member of the dynasty of House Vex&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Oboron</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/oboron/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/oboron/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oboron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A famous Hero mentioned in the Poem of Taliesin from Azura&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Python</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/python/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Python was an ancient Storm Dragon who turned against his kind and attempted to destroy all dragons and their capital, Valum Vaton . He is credited with the creation and enslavement of the Half Dragon race according to recovered texts and was believed to have been slain in combat by the mythological figure Sigurd and ancient dragon Asag. It is known that Python was eventually given the curse of darkness by an Unknown Mysmaal. Python finally fell at the far below the the city of New Highguard on Kumari after being mortally wounded by the Kumari civilians at which point he sacrificied himself to release the ancient seal on the Vault of the Fallen which resulted in the total destruction of the Kumari continent&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Raan N&#39;Var</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/raan-nvar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/raan-nvar/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan N&amp;rsquo;Var&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;head-archivist-of-v-lorn&#34;&gt;Head Archivist of V&amp;rsquo;Lorn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;physical-description&#34;&gt;Physical Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;facial-features&#34;&gt;Facial Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His eyes bear the mark of a man who has spent many years thumbing ancient texts by candle light&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;apparel-accessories&#34;&gt;Apparel &amp;amp; Accessories&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High Archivist N&amp;rsquo;Var is draped, much like his counterparts, in the studious garbs of the Library of V&amp;rsquo;Lorn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mental-characteristics&#34;&gt;Mental characteristics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;personal-history&#34;&gt;Personal history&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan&amp;rsquo;s deep understanding of Dark Elven racial heritage has provided each of the Houses of Undergate with important advice on matters of war, politics and arcanum. The Library of V&amp;rsquo;Lorn towers high into the subterranean city of Undergate and is filled with all manners of tomes, artifacts and lost treasures. It is thanks to Raan&amp;rsquo;s careful management that the Library continues on as an important location of Dark Elven wisdom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the vast amount of knowledge that flows through a single man it is not entirely clear how much Raan could be manipulated knowledge to his own ends. On the surface Raan always seems impartial, but giving that the Library of V&amp;rsquo;Lorn has absolute control over all relics and information flowing in and out of Undergate, some may wonder what one could achieve with such power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan is a master multischooled arcanist and has studied many forbidden and lost spells very few scholars have seen. His Keepers meticulously collect, study and catalogue an ever increasing volume of artifacts for the Library which he distributes as he sees fits to the various guilds that operate in Undergate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan is to the point, motivated and deeply connected to all members of society, high and low. He will rarely be involved in public functions, instead prefering to use any of his spare time spent in study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan will never offend or share his personal feelings towards others, instead trying to keep himself in favour with anyone who may potentially aid in the aquisition of new curiosities and tomes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;employment&#34;&gt;Employment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan began as Keeper in the Library of V&amp;rsquo;Lorn and worked his way to Head Archivist following the natural death of his predecessor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accomplishments-achievements&#34;&gt;Accomplishments &amp;amp; Achievements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-Disciplined Arcanist Head of the Library of V&amp;rsquo;lorn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personality-characteristics&#34;&gt;Personality Characteristics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;likes-dislikes&#34;&gt;Likes &amp;amp; Dislikes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raan fears the collapse of the political hierarchy that currently operate in Undergate. It has been a constant dance of power between the Church and Military that he feels one day one may result in total chaos and subsequently the fall of the Library of V&amp;rsquo;Lorn&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Rail N&#39;Ris</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/rail-nris/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/rail-nris/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rail N&amp;rsquo;Ris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rail N&amp;rsquo;Ris is a Sun Elf renegade and former citizen of the Caerthian Empire. She is one of the main leaders of the Cearthian Sympathisers who were known to have sided with the Anushi during the Anushi-Caerthian slave uprising of 196981 UT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rail used Count N&amp;rsquo;Ris&amp;rsquo;s personal funds to smuggle Anushi by boat from Caerthia into the lands of the Morheim Kingdom of Amaria. With the aid and leadership of teh anushi named Teris, a new stronghold was established knownn as Haven which became a refuge to all and any subjugated races on the lands of Amaria&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using her diplomatic skill Rail was able to form an alliance between many of the major cities of Amaria which became crucial during the Caerthian Invasion, the last stand being at the Aerindal city of Eindel&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Rhukadlor</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/rhukadlor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/rhukadlor/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rhukadlor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Rhukadlor envisions himself as a noble warrior, and over time has started to modify his appearance to follow suit. Standing at around eight feet tall, he&amp;rsquo;s quite broad and not with fat. He&amp;rsquo;s encased in heavy plate armor, which is covered in dents and nicks from past battles. Somewhere beneath the damage one can see that there were once detailed engravings, most are too chipped to make sense of now. His primary weapon is the large claymore slung across his back. Though not particularly broad, it&amp;rsquo;s quite long and gives him a good amount of range with his sweeping attacks. Rhukadlor was a general of the ancient Human empire, and was responsible for many of their military victories. Now that the empire has fallen, he&amp;rsquo;s taken it upon himself to start reclaiming the lands that were once a part of it. He&amp;rsquo;s already taken most of southeastern Nuchalnuth, and has recently repaired Verlore Rhukadlor is a fearsome warrior. Swinging his claymore in great arcs, he can hit large numbers of enemies at the same time with ease. In his long life he&amp;rsquo;s also picked up some magic, and is capable of periodically shelling enemies at a range with bolts of superheated energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Romnus Silverdawn</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/romnus-silverdawn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/romnus-silverdawn/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romnus Silverdawn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Romnus Silverdawn was a slave prisoner in the proto human kingdom who formed the Silverdawn Republic in 2385 MA after the slaves were freed. His daughter was Eryinth Silverdawn, wife of Athos Valeron&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Sabe Alexander</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/sabe-alexander/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/sabe-alexander/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sabe Alexander&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Sabe Alexander was a royal prince of the House of Alexander during the Proto Human era He was assassinated in 37569 ME during his wedding with Ashri Loviatar&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Saint X&#39;Lron</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/saint-xlron/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/saint-xlron/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saint X&amp;rsquo;Lron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mythical figure of the Caerthian Sol&amp;rsquo;Azul religion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;../../items/dusted-tome&#34;&gt;Dusted Tome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Shai&#39;Din</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/shaidin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/shaidin/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shai&amp;rsquo;Din&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An extremely dangerous Demi Lich spoken of in Keladun and Caerthian texts&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Shana</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/shana/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/shana/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shana&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A famous Hero mentioned in the Poem of Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Sigurd</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/sigurd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/sigurd/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sigurd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Sigurd is a mythological warrior spoken of in many texts of the western hemisphere and is spoken of in his odyssey as travelling the four corners of the world completing several tasks for the ancient dieties. One of these tasks is known to have rewarded sigurd with the Aegis, a powerful shield that allowed him to defeat incredible creatures. What baffles the scholars most about Sigurd is his race as he appears to be almost similar to the modern human race but they could not have existed during that time. It is perhaps some other similar race from ancient times that has been lost to the ages. The search for sigurd has been the life long work of many geneologists attempting to uncover more history of their own race in the time before the cataclysm. It is known that recently Sigurd returned with the arrival of Python on the island of Kumari - how this was achieved is unknown&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Taliesin</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/taliesin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/taliesin/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Taliesin is mentioned in tales of several eastern hemisphere cultures and is believed to predate the Cataclysm It is known that Taliesin returned during the events of the Fall of Python and led attacks on Ashengate before the destruction of Kumari He is widely known by bards for the Poem of Taliesin&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Tullan Vex</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/tullan-vex/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/tullan-vex/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tullan Vex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King Tullan Vex, true King to the Throne of Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir and Mysma leads the Army of Crimson Shadow against his wife Queen Morgana Thex who has claimed the Sanguine Kingdom of Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir for himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His armies are positioned in the The Savage Plains with his throne temporarily located in The Eternal Sanctum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King Tullan Vex had ruled the Sanguine Kingdom of Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir since they were granted the gift of Vampirism by Somnus the Shaderider in 1596 LA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His eternal kingdom prospered under his rule for over 2000 years but it was not until his love for a consort drove his wife Queen Morgana Vex to madness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Year 0 MA, Tullan was impaled by an Oshira Thrall at the behest of the Queen Morgana Vex leaving him cripled. He was buried, semi alive in a crypt far below The Flaming Abyss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would not be until 1121 MA that King Tullan would be freed from his prison by Eshu a Chunel slave of the Oshira&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then King Tullan has risen a force he has named the Army of the Crimson Shadow which he rules from his new palace in the tombs of his ancestors at The Eternal Sanctum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King Tullan almost met his end in battle during the events that led to the Spellstorm but he escaped with his life and continues his war to this day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Army of the Crimson Shadow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enemies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Queen Morgana Vex&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Emperor Val&#39;Elsir</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/emperor-valelsir/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/emperor-valelsir/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Esir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emperor Elaril Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruler of the Caerthian Empire during the Mythological Age and the Time of Crisis, Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir is a pure blood Sun Elf of the lands of Qylia. He oversaw a bitter rivalry with the Aerindal Kindgdoms of the North, invading them twice during his leadership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;noteable-campaigns&#34;&gt;Noteable Campaigns&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-war-of-the-four-kingdoms&#34;&gt;The War of the Four Kingdoms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is believed Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir oversaw a propagander campaign forcing the Ophidians to invade Caerthain territory as a justification for Caerthian evacuation and expansion north into Aerindal territory. Paying the Ogres a large sum to invade the Keladun and Aerindal whilst simultaneously blaming brutalities on caerthian refugees the Caerthians began a war into the lands of Aerindal and conquered the city of Eindel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was during this period that the Aerindal drifted into the pages of history, had it not been for the return of future travellers into the past, the Aerindal would never have been seen again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-caerthians-invasion-of-amaria&#34;&gt;The Caerthians Invasion of Amaria&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/events/the-caerthian-invasion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Caerthian Invasion of Amaria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;death&#34;&gt;Death&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emperor Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir was murdered by the lich Shai&amp;rsquo;Din in the final moments of the Eindel siege during The Caerthian Invasion of Amaria in 1234 P-OE (196982 UT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;family-name&#34;&gt;Family Name&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir is believed to be a word that represents the city of Cal&amp;rsquo;Drin and was discovered by the Caerthians in the subterranean areas of the appropriated city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name (and in particular the throne) was adopted by the earliest dynasties of the Mysmaal many years after the fall of the Caerthian Empire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;deuzulus&#34;&gt;Deuzulus&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is believed that Deuzulus was once a prince of the Caethian Empire and also carries the Val&amp;rsquo;Elsir name, though he has long since discarded any of his former self since his elevation to God of Hate&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Eryinth Valeron</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/eryinth-valeron/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/eryinth-valeron/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;Eryinth Valeron was the wife of Athos Valeron and at one time the leader of the Silverdawn Republic before her poisoning in 2450 MA by House Stormbreaker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eryinth Valeron, born Eryinth Silverdawn was daughter of Romnus Silverdawn, leader of the Silverdawn Republic. She was crowned Queen on her fathers death and married Athos Valeron in 2433 MA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the Stormbreaker Civil War she was poisoned by the House Stormbreaker leaving her husband in charge of the republic following her death in 2450 MA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Region known as Eryinth is named in her sake&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docs: Ra&#39;Ern</title><link>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/raern/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.fallofanempire.com/docs/notable-npcs/raern/</guid><description>
&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ra&amp;rsquo;Ern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ra&amp;rsquo;Ern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ra&amp;rsquo;Ern family was a long line of Caerthian rulers&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>